[
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An aqueous solution in which the concentration of OH\u0152 ions is greater than that of H+ ions is:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "basic",
            "X": "acidic",
            "Y": "neutral",
            "Z": "in equilibrium"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What general type of bonding is found in molecules in which electrons are shared by nuclei?",
        "Answer": "COVALENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 4 processes where latent heat is absorbed:  evaporation;  condensation;  water melts;  water freezes",
        "Answer": "EVAPORATION;  WATER MELTS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a metallic element, composes about 5% of the Earth\u2122s crust, oxidizes very easily, and when pure is a dark, silver-grey metal:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "cobalt",
            "X": "nickel",
            "Y": "iron",
            "Z": "titanium"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In general, metals are relatively hard except for what group of metals in the Periodic Table?",
        "Answer": "ONE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to standard chemical nomenclature and indicating the proper charge, what is the formula for hydrogen sulfide?",
        "Answer": "H2S"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Of the following group of 4 cations, which are the LARGEST and SMALLEST ions, respectively:  K+;  Na+;  Rb+;  Li+",
        "Answer": "LARGEST = Rb+;  SMALLEST =  Li+"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a diprotic acid:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "H2C2O4",
            "X": "H3PO4",
            "Y": "HCl",
            "Z": "HNO2"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "an ideal gas cannot undergo condensation",
            "X": "the less mass a particle has, the faster it will effuse",
            "Y": "when a gas is compressed, its temperature always increases",
            "Z": "a gas is easier to compress than a liquid"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following would be LEAST applicable for determining the end point in a titration experiment:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "pH meter",
            "X": "phenolphthalein (read as: fee-knoll-THAY-lean) solution",
            "Y": "potentiometer",
            "Z": "mass spectrometry"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following gases will have the LOWEST freezing point:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "hydrogen",
            "X": "water",
            "Y": "helium",
            "Z": "carbon dioxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a substance that is very reactive with the oxygen in air and must be stored under water or some other substance to keep it from becoming incendiary:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "fullerene",
            "X": "white phosphorous",
            "Y": "calcium fluoride",
            "Z": "calcium oxide"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best describes the catalyst in the destruction of ozone by chlorofluorocarbons:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "homogeneous",
            "X": "heterogeneous",
            "Y": "enzymatic",
            "Z": "autocatalytic"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most common term for the direct addition of water to an alkene (read as: al-KEEN) to make an alcohol?",
        "Answer": "HYDRATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Under constant temperatures, a sample of gas at a pressure of 120 kilopascals is allowed to expand from 2 liters to 8 liters.  Calculate the new pressure, in kilopascals:",
        "Answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "any foreign substance added to water will cause a freezing point drop",
            "X": "a nonvolatile solute raises the boiling point of a solvent",
            "Y": "methane has a higher boiling point than ethane",
            "Z": "freezing point depression is a colligative property"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to standard chemical nomenclature, what is the formula for aluminum bicarbonate?",
        "Answer": "Al(HCO3)3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Carbon monoxide, or CO, will be adsorbed (read as: ADD-sorbed) onto the surface of which of the following metals the MOST strongly:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "iron",
            "X": "nickel",
            "Y": "cobalt",
            "Z": "gold"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 3 choices in order of increasing bond energies:  O2;  N2;  F2",
        "Answer": "F2;  O2;  N2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The molal (read as: moe-lahl) is a concentration unit that is most appropriately used in experimental designs that determine:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "freezing point depression",
            "X": "osmotic pressure",
            "Y": "density",
            "Z": "vapor pressure lowering"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electron capacity in each of the 4 sublevels s, p, d, and f, respectively?",
        "Answer": "s = 2;  p = 6;  d = 10;  f = 14"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A sample of oxygen gas is collected over water at 14\u00baC.  Knowing that the vapor pressure of water at 14\u00baC is 1.6 kilopascals, and that the pressure of the resultant mixture is 120 kilopascals, find the pressure, to the first decimal place, exerted by the dry oxygen alone:",
        "Answer": "118.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT generally true of activation energies in chemical reactions:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "activation energies vary from reaction to reaction",
            "X": "the Arrhenius equation can be used to determine the activation energy of a reaction",
            "Y": "the lower the activation energy is, the faster the reaction",
            "Z": "increasing the temperature of a reaction decreases the activation energy"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true about aqueous solutions:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "diluting a buffer with water can change the pH of the water",
            "X": "metal cations can act as weak acids in water solutions",
            "Y": "an acid whose Ka = 6 \u00d7 10\u015210 is weaker than an acid whose Ka = 5.8 \u00d7 10\u01524",
            "Z": "an acid whose pKa is 3.0 is stronger than an acid whose pKa is 7.0"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A lead chromate solution is typically what color:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "blue",
            "X": "red",
            "Y": "yellow",
            "Z": "green"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules exhibits a dipole moment:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "CH4",
            "X": "H2S",
            "Y": "CO2",
            "Z": "SO3"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When dissociated in water, which of the following acids has its dissociation equilibrium shifted farthest to the right:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "HClO",
            "X": "HClO2",
            "Y": "HClO3",
            "Z": "HClO4"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 4 bonds in order of decreasing polarity:   Br\u0152Br;  K\u0152Br;  P\u0152Cl;  Li\u0152F",
        "Answer": "Li\u0152F;  K\u0152Br;  P\u0152Cl;  Br\u0152Br"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name the LARGEST atom or ion in EACH of the following 3 pairs:  1) an iron 3 plus ion or an iron 2 plus ion  2) an oxygen atom or an oxygen 2 minus ion  3) a gallium 3 plus ion or a gallium atom",
        "Answer": "1) IR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Using proper chemical nomenclature, finish balancing the following chemical reaction.  Make sure to indicate the state of each substance, such as solid, liquid, aqueous, or gas:  3NaOH(aqueous) + H3PO4(aqueous)  what?",
        "Answer": "Na3PO4(aqueous) +  3H2O(liquid)"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Giving your answer to the first decimal place and in liters, one mole of gas at 1.00 atmosphere pressure and a temperature of 273.15 kelvin occupies what volume?",
        "Answer": "22.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A sample of gas occupies a volume of 300 cubic centimeters at a pressure of 2 atmospheres.  Calculate what the pressure would have to be, in atmospheres to the first decimal place, in order for the gas to have a volume of 500 cubic centimeters at constant temperature:",
        "Answer": "1.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following has a melting point of 185\u00baC and readily dissolves in water at room temperature, but is NOT an electrolyte:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "NaCl",
            "X": "decane",
            "Y": "methane",
            "Z": "sucrose"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the systematic chemical name for the following ionic compound:  Cr2(SeO4)3",
        "Answer": "CHROMIUM(III) SELENATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a substance whose molecular and empirical formulas are NOT the same:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "benzene",
            "X": "water",
            "Y": "ammonia",
            "Z": "sulfur dioxide"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a molecule with a square pyramidal molecular geometry around its central atom:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "PCl5",
            "X": "ClF5",
            "Y": "XeF4",
            "Z": "SF6"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An organic compound with the formula C6H14 is an:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "alkane",
            "X": "alkene",
            "Y": "alkyne",
            "Z": "arene"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following gases has the highest effusion rate through a pinhole opening from one compartment to another and at room temperature:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "argon",
            "X": "CO2",
            "Y": "SO2",
            "Z": "helium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 3 concentration units that are temperature-dependent:  molal (read as: moe-LAHL);  molarity;  normality",
        "Answer": "MOLARITY;  NORMALITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calculate the enthalpy of vaporization, in kilojoules, of water at 25\u00baC and 1 atmosphere.  Assume the standard enthalpy of formation of liquid water is \u0152286 kilojoules and the standard enthalpy of formation of water gas is \u0152242 kilojoules:",
        "Answer": "44"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name the elements in the following reaction that have been oxidized and reduced, respectively:  Zn(solid) + CuSO4(aqueous)  ZnSO4(aqueous) + Cu(solid)",
        "Answer": "OXIDIZED = Zn"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is closest to the pKa of an acid whose  Ka = 5.0 \u00d7 10\u01524:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2.3",
            "X": "3.3",
            "Y": "4.0",
            "Z": "5.0"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to VSEPR bonding theory, if 2 of the bonded atoms in an octahedral molecule are replaced by 2 electron pairs, the molecule will assume what geometric shape, such as in XeF4:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "linear",
            "X": "trigonal bipyramidal",
            "Y": "square planar",
            "Z": "square pyramidal"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to VSEPR bonding theory, if one of the bonded atoms in a trigonal bipyramidal molecule is replaced by 2 electron pairs, the molecule will assume what geometric shape, such as in ClF3:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "t-shaped",
            "X": "see-saw",
            "Y": "linear",
            "Z": "bent"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many quantum numbers are required to completely describe a specific electron in a multi-electron atom?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following describes the quantum number that indicates the direction in space of the electron cloud surrounding the nucleus of an atom:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "magnetic quantum number",
            "X": "principle quantum number",
            "Y": "angular momentum quantum number",
            "Z": "spin quantum number"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to general solubility rules, name all of the following 5 substances that are NOT soluble in water:  lithium iodide;  sodium chloride;  iron(II) hydroxide;  sodium nitrate;  barium sulfate",
        "Answer": "IRON(II) HYDROXIDE;  BARIUM SULFATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider a hypothetical reaction, A + B  C + D.  At zero time, the concentration of A = 1 molar, after 30 seconds A = 0.5 molar, and after 50 seconds A = 0.3 molar.  Calculate the average rate of disappearance of A over the time interval 30 seconds to 50 seconds, in molarity per second:",
        "Answer": "1 \u00d7 10\u01522"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "a reaction that requires free energy is spontaneous",
            "X": "gases, as a group, have higher entropies than liquids",
            "Y": "standard molar entropies of pure substances are always positive values",
            "Z": "spontaneous processes involve non-equilibrium conditions"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider the reaction, N2(gas) + 3H2(gas)  2NH3(gas).  If the concentration of ammonia increases from 0.3 molar to 0.9 molar in a 10-minute period, find the average rate of reaction over this time interval.  Give your answer to the 2nd decimal place in moles per liter minute:",
        "Answer": "0.03"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT generally true of reaction equilibria:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "if the temperature of an exothermic reaction is raised, the equilibrium shifts to the left",
            "X": "the equilibrium constants for forward and reverse reactions are the reciprocals of each other",
            "Y": "pure liquids appear in the equilibrium expression but pure solids do not",
            "Z": "an equilibrium constant greater than 1 means that the reaction favors products at equilibrium"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calculate : delta G naught), giving your answer in kilojoules, for a reaction in which  300 kelvin and 1 atmosphere pressure:",
        "Answer": "+150"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following substances has the greatest density:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "hexane",
            "X": "methylene chloride",
            "Y": "diethyl ether",
            "Z": "ethyl acetate"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules is most likely to have a zero dipole moment based on its molecular shape:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "PF3",
            "X": "H2O",
            "Y": "PCl3",
            "Z": "BeF2"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What chemical term is given to the formations that occur in water when a hydrophilic head and a hydrophobic tail organize into spheres that orient the tails within the sphere?",
        "Answer": "MICELLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Using proper chemical nomenclature, finish balancing the following combustion reaction for the gaseous products of carbon dioxide and water:   2C4H10(gas) + 13O2(gas)  what?",
        "Answer": "8CO2 + 10H2O"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 3 molecules that are considered saturated hydrocarbons:  ethylene;  ethane;  cyclohexane",
        "Answer": "ETHANE;  CYCLOHEXANE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many milliliters of a 0.250 molar H2SO4 solution will react with 10 milliliters of a 0.250 molar NaOH solution",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name the 2 different bond angles present in a molecule with octahedral geometry, such as in SF6:",
        "Answer": "90;  180"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a titration experiment, it takes 20.0 milliliters of a 0.05 molar barium hydroxide, Ba(OH)2, solution to neutralize 40 milliliters of a nitric acid, or HNO3, solution to the equivalence point.  Calculate the molarity of HNO3, rounded to the second decimal place:",
        "Answer": "0.05"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the bond order for each oxygen-oxygen bond in the ozone or O3 molecule?",
        "Answer": "23"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Hydrogen gas effuses through a pinhole opening from one compartment to another about how many times as fast as nitrogen gas:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2.4-times",
            "X": "3.7-times",
            "Y": "5.3-times",
            "Z": "8.2-times"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "For the following 3 processes, predict whether the change in enthalpy, or ive, respectively:  1) decomposition of ammonium nitrate  2) sublimation of dry ice  3) condensation of gaseous iodine to liquid iodine",
        "Answer": "1) +;  2) +;  3) \u0152"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider the following equilibrium reaction,  PCl5(gas) 3(gas) + Cl2(gas).  If a 1-liter flask contains 0.02 moles of PCl3 and 0.02 moles of Cl2 at equilibrium, how many moles of PCl5 are in the flask.  Assume the equilibrium constant is 5 \u00d7 10\u01522.",
        "Answer": "8 \u00d7 10\u01523"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Of the following 5 alkanes, which one has the LEAST combined strain energy from angle strain and torsional strain:  [read slowly] cyclopropane;  cyclobutane;  cyclopentane;  cyclohexane;  cyclo-octane",
        "Answer": "CYCLOHEXANE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most common name for the conformation that the ring structure of cyclohexane adopts to reach a strain-free value?",
        "Answer": "CHAIR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "L-alanine and D-alanine are BEST classified as what type of isomers:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "cis",
            "X": "trans",
            "Y": "structural",
            "Z": "optical"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many sigma and pi bonds, respectively, are there in a  molecule with the following formula: [read slowly] CH3CHCHCH2CH3",
        "Answer": "SIGMA  14;  PI = 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following are the units of the rate constant for a  2nd order reaction given that concentration is measured in molarity and time in seconds:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "M\u01522s\u01521",
            "X": "M\u01521s\u01521",
            "Y": "Ms\u01521",
            "Z": "M\u01522minutes\u01521"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "1.0 gram of an unknown organic molecule is dissolved in 50.0 grams of benzene.   Determine the molecular mass of the unknown if this solution freezes at 4.5\u00baC.  Assume the freezing point constant of benzene is 5.0\u00baC per molal, and the freezing point of benzene is 5.5\u00baC.  Give your answer to the nearest whole number in grams per mole.",
        "Answer": "100 f = 5.5\u00ba \u0152 4.5\u00ba = 1.0\u00baC;  m f/ Kf = 1.0\u00ba/5.0\u00ba = 0.2m or 0.2mol/kg;"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider the following equilibrium reaction,  FeO(solid) + CO(gas) (solid) + CO2(gas), where \u015210 kilojoules.  Which of the following would have a similar effect on the equilibrium position as lowering the temperature:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "adding iron",
            "X": "increasing pressure",
            "Y": "removing carbon dioxide",
            "Z": "removing carbon monoxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the electrolysis of water, if a very small amount of sodium sulfate is added to the water, give the equation for the half reaction that occurs at the ANODE.  Make sure to indicate proper charges and the state of each substance, such as solid, liquid, aqueous, or gas:",
        "Answer": "2H2O(liquid)  O2(gas) + 4H+(aqueous) + 4e\u0152"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the overall reaction order for the following rate law:   rate = k[NH4+][NO2\u0152]   (read as: k times the concentration of NH4+ times the concentration of NO2\u0152)",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calculate the one-atmosphere boiling point elevation, in degrees Celsius to the 2nd decimal place, for a solution made by dissolving 1 gram of solute in 0.1 kilograms of water.  Assume the formula weight of the solute is 300 and the boiling point depression constant is 2.0\u00baC per molal..",
        "Answer": "0.07"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the scientific term for the ratio between the density of a given substance to that of water when both are at the same temperature?",
        "Answer": "SPECIFIC GRAVITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following pure substances has the highest melting point at 1 atmosphere of pressure:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "magnesium oxide",
            "X": "diamond",
            "Y": "sodium chloride",
            "Z": "cesium chloride"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Group 1 cations and group 7 anions combine to form:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "metal alloys",
            "X": "alkali halides",
            "Y": "alkaloids",
            "Z": "organometallic compounds"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the chemical name for the compound formed when pure iron and pure sulfur are mixed together and heated:",
        "Answer": "IRON SULFIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the pH of a solution with a pOH of 6.8 at 25\u00baC?",
        "Answer": "7.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following substances is water soluble:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "ethanol",
            "X": "dichloro-methane",
            "Y": "chloroform",
            "Z": "benzene"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the atomic number for the ground state element with the following electron configuration:  1s22s22p5 (read as: 1, s, 2; 2, s, 2; 2, p, 5)  A",
        "Answer": "1s22s22p5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many grams of KCl, with a molar mass of 75, are needed to make 1 liter of a 3 molar solution?",
        "Answer": "225"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the electronegativity difference in the bonding atoms is large, what general type of bond is formed?",
        "Answer": "IONIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules has a double covalent bond:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "hydrogen",
            "X": "oxygen",
            "Y": "nitrogen",
            "Z": "methane"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name for the most malleable and ductile metal which can be dissolved in aqua regia but is unaffected by air and most other reagents?",
        "Answer": "GOLD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the molecular formula for the conjugate acid of the following Br\u00f8nsted-Lowry base:  SO42\u0152",
        "Answer": "HSO4\u0152"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A beaker of concentrated aqueous ammonia is placed next to a beaker of concentrated aqueous hydrochloric acid at room temperature.  After a short while, a white cloud forms between the beakers.  This is a demonstration of:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "effusion",
            "X": "diffusion",
            "Y": "efflorescence",
            "Z": "effervescence"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In addition to the \ufb01sniff test\ufb02, which of the following is a standard laboratory test for a sulfide, such as hydrogen sulfide gas:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the gas passed over a filter paper soaked in colorless lead nitrate turns the paper brown",
            "X": "when inserted into a flame, a glowing wooden splint bursts into flames",
            "Y": "a flame test gives off a deep purple color",
            "Z": "paper chromatography"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a gas that is tested for by ignition in air on contact with a lighted splint to produce a high-pitched \ufb01popping\ufb02 sound:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "oxygen",
            "X": "hydrogen",
            "Y": "helium",
            "Z": "nitrogen monoxide"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The Lewis dot structure for the N+2 ion would show how many dots?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an endothermic process:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "sublimation",
            "X": "melting",
            "Y": "vaporization",
            "Z": "condensation"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the molarity of a sodium hydroxide solution made by dissolving 4 grams NaOH in 250 milliliters of water?",
        "Answer": "0.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an element that is very important to human life, is contained in vitamin B-12, belongs to a group of transition metals, and has magnetic properties like iron:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "selenium",
            "X": "cobalt",
            "Y": "zinc",
            "Z": "manganese"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the pH of a 1 molar NaOH solution at 25\u00baC?",
        "Answer": "14"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a weak electrolyte:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "ammonia",
            "X": "dilute sulfuric acid",
            "Y": "1 molar sodium chloride",
            "Z": "dilute perchloric acid"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A molecular solid will most typically have which of the following melting points:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "very high",
            "X": "high to very high",
            "Y": "low",
            "Z": "variable"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the bond order between the 2 carbon atoms in acetylene?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to standard chemical nomenclature and indicating the proper charge, what is the formula for the sulfite ion?",
        "Answer": "SO32\u0152"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the atomic sublevel with the next highest energy after the 4p sublevel:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "4d",
            "X": "4f",
            "Y": "5s",
            "Z": "5p"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the  electronic configuration for sulfur, located in Period 3 and Group 16 of the Periodic Table:",
        "Answer": "1s22s22p63s23p4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The conversion of solid CaSO4 into solid CaO and SO2 gas is an example of what class of chemical reaction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "decomposition",
            "X": "hydrolysis",
            "Y": "combustion",
            "Z": "single replacement"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the oxidation number of chromium in the chromate ion, or CrO42\u0152?",
        "Answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Ca(OH)2, NaOH, and Ba(OH)2, are all:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "weak bases",
            "X": "completely ionized in water",
            "Y": "alkali halides",
            "Z": "standard buffers"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds is most SOLUBLE in water at 10\u00baC:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "KNO3",
            "X": "CaSO4",
            "Y": "BaSO4",
            "Z": "AgBr"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The electronegativity of oxygen is 3.4 and the electronegativity of calcium is 1.0.  Which of the following best describes the formation of the calcium oxide:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2 electrons are transferred from calcium to oxygen",
            "X": "2 electrons are transferred from oxygen to calcium",
            "Y": "2 electrons are shared between calcium and oxygen",
            "Z": "1 electron is shared and another is transferred from calcium to oxygen"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the chemical formula for the conjugate base of HNO2?",
        "Answer": "NO2\u0152"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following ions does NOT have a noble gas electron configuration in ionic compounds:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ca2+",
            "X": "F\u0152",
            "Y": "Al3+",
            "Z": "Na\u0152"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Charles law is particularly useful in explaining which of the following:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "dry air is more dense than humid air",
            "X": "CO2 escapes from a bottle of soda when opened",
            "Y": "the change in enthalpy when nitrogen and oxygen react to form nitrogen dioxide",
            "Z": "a hot-air balloon rises when the air in the balloon is heated"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If pure water is at its boiling point at standard pressure, how many additional calories of heat are needed to convert 1 gram of water from the liquid to the vapor state?",
        "Answer": "540"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name for the straight-chain alkane containing 5 carbons?",
        "Answer": "PENTANE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the electronegativity difference in the bonding atoms is intermediate in strength, what general type of bond is typically formed?",
        "Answer": "POLAR COVALENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a molecule having a nonpolar covalent bond:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "bromine gas",
            "X": "hydrogen fluoride",
            "Y": "water",
            "Z": "hydrogen bromide"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following are elements in the Periodic Table whose outer shell electrons are on two principal energy levels:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "alkali metals",
            "X": "noble gases",
            "Y": "alkaline Earth metals",
            "Z": "transition elements"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to standard chemical nomenclature and indicating the proper charge, what is the formula for potassium perchlorate?",
        "Answer": "KClO4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "hydrogen gas found in nature exists as a monatomic molecule",
            "X": "when 2 oxygen atoms combine to form O2, energy is released",
            "Y": "when chlorine gains 1 electron, it becomes larger",
            "Z": "noble gases tend not to bond because of their stable valence configurations"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Knowing that the chemical name for gypsum is calcium sulfate dihydrate, gypsum is what percent water by weight?  Assume the atomic masses of calcium = 40; sulfur = 32 and oxygen = 16.  A",
        "Answer": "Assume the atomic masses of calcium = 40; sulfur = 32 and oxygen = 16.  AN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the general name for a hypothetical gas that obeys Boyles\u2122s law at all temperatures and pressures?",
        "Answer": "IDEAL GAS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true of ideal gases:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2 or more gases form homogeneous mixtures in all proportions",
            "X": "collisions between gas particles are both elastic and inelastic",
            "Y": "they diffuse rapidly",
            "Z": "they assume the shapes of their containers"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds is used as a fuel additive in what is commonly known as \ufb01dry-gas\ufb02 by solubilizing water to reduce its contamination in gasoline:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "isooctane",
            "X": "glycerol",
            "Y": "MTBE",
            "Z": "isopropyl alcohol"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The molar heat of vaporization for water at its boiling point and in kilojoules per mole is:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "6.01",
            "X": "40.7",
            "Y": "540",
            "Z": "2,260"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An increase in which of the following conditions would NOT lead to an increase in pressure of a gas in a piston:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "increased temperature",
            "X": "increased number of gas molecules",
            "Y": "increased average kinetic energy of gas particles",
            "Z": "increased volume"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To the nearest whole number, how many grams of Na2SO4, whose formula weight is 142, are needed to prepare a 500 milliliter 0.100 molar solution?",
        "Answer": "7"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to VSEPR bonding theory, what type of geometry does a molecule have when the central atom is surrounded by 4 bonded groups, such as in methane?",
        "Answer": "TETRAHEDRAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is considered a weak acid:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "HCO2H",
            "X": "HClO4",
            "Y": "HNO3",
            "Z": "HBr"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When a strip of sodium reacts with dilute HCl, what gas is produced?",
        "Answer": "HYDROGEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The release of hydrogen gas in the above experiment is called:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "combustion",
            "X": "effervescence",
            "Y": "diffusion",
            "Z": "ebullition"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The reaction Fe3O4 + 4H2  3Fe + 4H2O, is an example of what class of chemical reaction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "decomposition",
            "X": "single replacement",
            "Y": "combustion",
            "Z": "combination"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Find the mass percent composition, rounded to the nearest whole number, for each atom in KClO3.  Assume the atomic masses of potassium = 39, chlorine = 35, and oxygen = 16",
        "Answer": "K = 32%;  Cl = 29%;  O = 39%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the theoretical end of a titration:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "end point",
            "X": "indicator point",
            "Y": "equivalence point",
            "Z": "standardization point"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a strong acid-base titration, what is the pH of the solution when the equivalence point is reached?",
        "Answer": "7"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A sample of gas is heated from 300K to 500K.  If the container is sealed and of fixed volume, which of the following will remain constant:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the average kinetic energy of the gas molecules",
            "X": "the average speed of the gas molecules",
            "Y": "the density of the gas",
            "Z": "the pressure of the gas"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following does NOT have the electron configuration of argon:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "O2\u0152",
            "X": "Cl\u0152",
            "Y": "S2\u0152",
            "Z": "K+"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the electrolysis of a copper chloride solution, what forms at the cathode and anode, respectively?",
        "Answer": "CATHODE = COPPER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to standard chemical nomenclature, what is the formula for ammonium sulfate?",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "About how many calories per gram will it take to sublimate water at standard pressure:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "180",
            "X": "360",
            "Y": "540",
            "Z": "720"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A Buchner (read as: BYOU-kh-ner) funnel is a piece of laboratory glassware often used in chemistry labs for which of the following procedures:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "combustion",
            "X": "filtration",
            "Y": "centrifugation",
            "Z": "distillation"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is one of the main reasons why oxygenates are used as gasoline additives:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "allow for more complete combustion",
            "X": "decrease sulfur buildup in engine pistons",
            "Y": "prevent water condensation in stored fuels",
            "Z": "corrosion inhibition"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider the following equilibrium reaction,  PCl5(gas) 3(gas) + Cl2(gas).  If a 2 mole sample of PCl5 dissociates to give 0.2 moles of Cl2  at equilibrium, find the molar amounts, to the 1st decimal place, of PCl5 at equilibrium:",
        "Answer": "1.8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The reaction CuCl2 + Na2S  CuS + 2NaCl2, is an example of what class of chemical reaction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "synthesis",
            "X": "single replacement",
            "Y": "double replacement",
            "Z": "decomposition"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 4 species that contain an odd number of electrons:  O21\u0152;  O22\u0152;  SO2;  CO",
        "Answer": "O21\u0152"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the 2 alkenes (read as: al-KEENS) with the shortest carbon chains and lowest molecular weights?",
        "Answer": "ETHYLENE;  PROPYLENE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 4 metals in order of increasing reactivity in dilute HCl:  zinc;  aluminum;  gold;  calcium",
        "Answer": "GOLD;  ZINC;  ALUMINUM;  CALCIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the general name for a substance that facilitates a chemical reaction by providing an alternative reaction pathway with a lower activation energy while remaining unaltered?",
        "Answer": "CATALYST"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "You need to prepare 500 milliliters of a 0.100 molar NaOH solution from a 0.250 molar solution.  What volume, in milliliters, of the 0.250 molar solution must be diluted to 500 milliliters?",
        "Answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following species would be expected to have the most covalent character?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Beryllium fluoride",
            "X": "Magnesium chloride",
            "Y": "Aluminum oxide",
            "Z": "Silver bromide"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Under which of the following sets of conditions would nitrogen gas deviate the MOST from the ideal gas law?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "500 Kelvin and 50 atmospheres",
            "X": "500 Kelvin and 5 atmospheres",
            "Y": "150 Kelvin and 50 atmospheres",
            "Z": "150 Kelvin and 5 atmospheres"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Infrared spectroscopy typically analyzes which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Electronic excitement",
            "X": "Nuclear spins",
            "Y": "Molecular vibrations",
            "Z": "Atomic rotation"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the oxidation number of the central cobalt atom in [Co(NH3)4Cl2]+ [C-O-N-H-3-4-C-L-2-plus]?",
        "Answer": "+3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following does NOT have to contain an oxygen atom single-bonded to at least one carbon atom?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ether",
            "X": "Ester",
            "Y": "Mercaptan",
            "Z": "Carboxylic acid"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements is most reactive to water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Potassium",
            "X": "Zinc",
            "Y": "Palladium [puh-LAY-dee-uhm]",
            "Z": "Nickel"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A student is titrating an unknown acid with 0.100 molar sodium hydroxide. At the end of the experiment, the student calculates the concentration of the acid to be 1.1% higher than the actual value. Which of the following sources of possible experimental error most likely contributed to this final error?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Not zeroing the balance",
            "X": "Adding 2 drops of indicator instead of the procedure-stated 3 drops",
            "Y": "Not reading from the bottom of the meniscus when reading the burette",
            "Z": "Leaving some water in the receiving Erlenmeyer flask before adding the acid"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Place the following four molecules in order from strongest to weakest ionic bonding: 1) calcium oxide, 2) cesium iodide, 3) potassium chloride, 4) lithium fluoride.",
        "Answer": "1, 4, 3, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Jacques Charles is well-known as the inventor of the hot air balloon, and there is also a law that carries his name. Which of the following is a correct postulation, based on Charles\u2122s Law?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "As the gas in a balloon is heated, its mass increases",
            "X": "As the gas in a balloon is heated, the pressure of the gas outside the balloon decreases",
            "Y": "As the gas in a balloon is heated, the pressure of the gas outside the balloon increases",
            "Z": "As the gas in a balloon is cooled, its density increases"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A 10.0 gram sample of gold with a specific heat capacity of 0.1 joules per gram degree Celsius is heated using 100.0 joules of energy. If the original temperature of the gold is 25.0\u00b0 Celsius, what is its final temperature in degrees Celsius?",
        "Answer": "125"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Acetyl-CoA [CO-A] carboxylase-1 alpha, a fatty acid synthesis regulatory enzyme, functions to carboxylate Acetyl-CoA. What is the name of the newly formed carboxylated product?",
        "Answer": "MALONYL-CoA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following protons will appear farthest downfield in the 1H [Proton]-NMR spectrum?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Alkane",
            "X": "Alkene",
            "Y": "Alkyne",
            "Z": "Aromatic"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An atom of an unknown element has 33 electrons. What is the likely ratio of the numbers of atoms of that element to calcium when in an ionic compound?",
        "Answer": "2:3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Henderson-Hasselbalch equation can provide the percent dissociation of  a weak acid. When the pH is equal to pKa, the weak acid is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "99% dissociated",
            "X": "75% dissociated",
            "Y": "50% dissociated",
            "Z": "25% dissociated"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to the Clausius [KLOU-zee-uhs] inequality, the derivative of entropy is greater than or equal to the derivative of heat, divided by temperature. When is the equal case true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "For an irreversible change",
            "X": "For a reversible change",
            "Y": "For temperatures greater than 273 Kelvin",
            "Z": "For temperatures less than or equal to 273 Kelvin"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer in scientific notation, calculate the rate of decomposition in molar per second, using appropriate significant figures, if the concentration difference is 0.10 molar over a 20.0 second interval.",
        "Answer": "5.0 x 10-3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When mixed at a molar ratio of 3 to 1, which of the following solution mixtures is a buffer system?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrochloric acid and sodium chloride",
            "X": "Acetic acid and sodium hydroxide",
            "Y": "Potassium hydroxide and phosphoric acid",
            "Z": "Perchloric acid and ammonia"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true with respect to reaction mechanisms?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Fast, reversible steps may be present",
            "X": "Fast, nonreversible steps are never present",
            "Y": "The elementary reactions sum to give the overall reaction",
            "Z": "The slow step is sometimes the first step"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A particular molecule of XeF4 displays 3 IR bands and 3 Raman bands at completely different energies. Based on this information, which of the following is its VSEPR structure?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Tetrahedral",
            "X": "Octahedral",
            "Y": "Square planar",
            "Z": "See-saw"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Thirty-two grams of oxygen gas are reacted with 10 grams of hydrogen gas to form water. If all of the oxygen is consumed, how many grams of excess hydrogen remain?",
        "Answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If 23.90 grams of water have a heat capacity of 100 joules per Kelvin, how many joules of thermal energy are required to raise the temperature of this water from 290 Kelvin to 295 Kelvin?",
        "Answer": "500"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following substances is soluble in carbon tetrachloride?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Formaldehyde [for-MAL-duh-hyd]",
            "X": "Bromine",
            "Y": "Ammonia",
            "Z": "Sodium chloride"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Cocaine has a tertiary amine group with a pKb of 5.6. What is the pKa of cocaine's conjugate acid in an aqueous solution at 25\u00b0 Celsius?",
        "Answer": "8.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the names of the following four acids: 1) H",
        "Answer": "1) HN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Uranium-235 can be used in nuclear power plants. If this isotope is at sub-critical mass and is bombarded by a neutron, which of the following is most likely to occur?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The result depends on the amount of uranium and temperature",
            "X": "An explosion",
            "Y": "A controllable source of energy will be formed",
            "Z": "No reaction"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electron configuration of an atom of gallium in the ground state?",
        "Answer": "1s2 2s2 2p6 3s2 3p6 4s2 3d10 4p1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "[pi star] orbital of ketones  and aldehydes [AL-duh-hyds]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Deprotonation at the alpha position",
            "X": "1, 2 addition",
            "Y": "1, 2 substitution",
            "Z": "Deprotonation at the beta position"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank the following four ions in order of increasing size for the dominant ionic form: 1) fluoride, 2) chloride, 3) sodium, 4) magnesium.",
        "Answer": "4, 3, 1, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calomel is an important reference electrode. In a calomel electrode, what salt solution is used to maintain constant ionic strength?",
        "Answer": "POTASSIUM CHLORIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many structural isomers are there for a compound with the formula C7H16?",
        "Answer": "9"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Dinitrogen tetroxide decomposes according to the reaction: N2O4(g)  2NO2(g). If nitrogen dioxide appears at a rate of 4 molar per second, at what rate in molar per second is the dinitrogen tetroxide disappearing?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the most sensitive type of polarography?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Normal pulse",
            "X": "Classical",
            "Y": "Differential pulse",
            "Z": "Current-sampled"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given that the half-life of uranium-235 is 700 million years, if you had 160 grams of U-235, how many grams would remain after 2.1 billion years?",
        "Answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Sodium crystallizes in the form of a body-centered cubic unit cell. If one atom of sodium has a radius of 180 picometers, what is the length, in picometers, of one side of the unit cell?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "255",
            "X": "360",
            "Y": "416",
            "Z": "509"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Kinetic-molecular theory makes several assumptions concerning ideal gases. Which of the following is NOT one of those assumptions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The average kinetic energy of the molecules is independent of temperature",
            "X": "There are no attractive or repulsive forces between molecules",
            "Y": "All collisions between molecules are elastic",
            "Z": "The volume occupied by the gas molecules is negligible compared to the volume of the container"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Water can frequently be employed in the self-assembly of nanoparticles by taking advantage of its surface properties. However, your teacher proposes that a particular self-assembly needs to take place in oil. Which of the following assembly processes would take advantage of the properties of the oil to make assembly possible?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Electrostatic",
            "X": "Magnetic",
            "Y": "Hydrophobic",
            "Z": "Capillary"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the molecular geometry of the coordination compound [Co(NH3)4Cl2]+?",
        "Answer": "OCTAHEDRAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Match the following reactions: E2, SN2, and E1 to the following three solvents in which they generally occur : 1) polar aprotic, 2) polar protic, 3) a variety of solvents.",
        "Answer": "E2 = 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In the gas phase, one mole of hydrogen gas reacts reversibly with one mole of iodine gas to form two moles of hydrogen iodide gas. If the system is at equilibrium at constant temperature, how will the equilibrium shift if the volume of the reaction vessel is doubled?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It will shift toward the reactants",
            "X": "It will shift toward the products",
            "Y": "It will not shift in either direction",
            "Z": "It is not possible to determine shift direction"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Uridine monophosphate (UMP) [YOOR-i-deen mon-uh-FOS-fayt] is essential to the synthesis of pyrimidine nucleotides [py-RIM-i-deen NOO-klee-uh-tyds]. What amino acid combines with a bicarbonate ion and two ATPs in the first step of de novo synthesis of UMP?",
        "Answer": "GLUTAMINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In general, what is the name for each individual step in a mechanism?",
        "Answer": "ELEMENTARY REACTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the common name for the amino acid having the side chain of methyl, CH3?",
        "Answer": "ALANINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In an endothermic reaction, dinitrogen tetroxide decomposes to form nitric oxide. If the two substances were in equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm] in a piston, identify all of the following three conditions that would lead to the generation of more nitric oxide: 1) pressure is removed from the system; 2) the temperature of the reaction is increased; 3) more dinitrogen tetroxide is added to the system.",
        "Answer": "ALL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Codeine is a powerful, naturally occurring opiate that is sometimes prescribed as a painkiller. If a codeine solution has a pH of 8.3, what is the solution hydroxide ion molarity to one significant figure?",
        "Answer": "2 x 10-6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Suppose that one day, Boyle's law becomes inverted but all other gas laws remain unchanged. Identify all of the following three experimental situations you would expect to observe: 1) as a balloon is put underwater, its diameter increases; 2) filling a tire causes the tire to cool; 3) as helium is let out of a tank, the temperature of the tank increases.",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assuming that all particles within a solid are equally spaced hard spheres, what two crystal structures have the least amount of empty space?",
        "Answer": "HEXAGONAL CLOSE PACKING AND CUBIC CLOSE PACKING"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The Haber process is an industrial process in which nitrogen gas and hydrogen gas are mixed at over 800 Kelvin and 150 atmospheres. The two gases react in this extreme environment to produce ammonia. Providing your answer to two significant figures, if 22.4 liters of hydrogen and 22.4 liters of nitrogen are mixed and react to completion, how many liters of ammonia will be produced?",
        "Answer": "15"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements, if doped into germanium, would produce a p-type semiconductor?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gallium",
            "X": "Silicon",
            "Y": "Arsenic",
            "Z": "Selenium"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider the following chemical reaction: NH4HS(s)  NH3 (g) + H2S(g). When 0.020 moles of NH4HS are placed in a 2.0 liter container and heated to 127o Celsius, all of the solid decomposes. Given that R = 0.0821 liter atmospheres per mole Kelvin, which of the following is the pressure in atmospheres inside the container?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.02",
            "X": "0.16",
            "Y": "0.66",
            "Z": "1.0"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Radiation enters the human body from a variety of sources. Place the following four doses of radiation in order from the largest to smallest effect: 1) chest X-ray, 2) eating 100 bananas, 3) airplane flight from New York to Los Angeles, 4) mammogram.",
        "Answer": "4, 3, 1, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following protons will have the largest coupling constant in the 1H-NMR spectrum?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Cis-alkene",
            "X": "Trans-alkene",
            "Y": "Ortho-benzene",
            "Z": "Para-benzene"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following polymers is soluble in organic solvents and rigid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Low density polyethylene [pol-ee-ETH-uh-leen]",
            "X": "Atactic polypropylene [pol-ee-PROH-puh-leen]",
            "Y": "Polystyrene [pol-ee-STY-reen]",
            "Z": "Polyvinyl chloride [pol-ee-VYNL]"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true with respect to balanced redox reactions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "All species in the balanced equation must have the same physical state",
            "X": "The oxidized atoms increase their oxidation number",
            "Y": "The reduced atoms decrease their oxidation number",
            "Z": "The total number of electrons transferred do not appear in the final, balanced reaction"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to electronic transition rules, to what sublevels can an electron move from the 3s sublevel in a single step transition?",
        "Answer": "4P, 4D, 4F, 2P"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT characteristic of amines?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A fully protonated amine is called an ammonium ion",
            "X": "Amines can function as Br\u00f8nsted bases",
            "Y": "The VSEPR geometry of the nitrogen atom is trigonal planar",
            "Z": "Amines can be a hydrogen bond acceptor"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements seemingly violates Hund\u2122s rule by shifting an electron from a full s orbital to another sublevel to give a more stable configuration?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Chromium",
            "X": "Tungsten",
            "Y": "Boron",
            "Z": "Cerium"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a first order reaction in which a graph is made showing concentration versus time, the shape of the graph is best described as which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Linear",
            "X": "Exponential",
            "Y": "Logarithmic",
            "Z": "Hyperbolic"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What Nobel Prize-winning named reaction allows for the single-step formation of cyclohexene from butadiene and ethene?",
        "Answer": "DIELS-ALDER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calculate the first order half-life in seconds to one significant figure if the rate constant is 1.7 x 10-3 inverse seconds.",
        "Answer": "400"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "While eating fish, you feel that the fish needs a little vinegar. Unfortunately, you add way too much. To lower the acidity of the fish again, you decide to add packets containing 3 moles each of sodium acetate. You estimate that you have added 1 mole of vinegar to your fish based on the fact that it has a pH around 2. Given that the pKa of acetic acid is 4.74, to the nearest whole packet, how many packets of sodium acetate must you add to the fish in order to bring the pH up to around 5.5?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "During an electrochemistry lab, you carefully construct a voltaic cell with two electrodes: a lead cathode and magnesium anode based on the standard reduction potentials. You place the two electrodes on the opposite sides of a beaker divided by a porous membrane, and then fill the beaker with a solution of potassium chloride. When you connect the two electrodes using wires and a voltmeter, you notice that no voltage flows through the voltmeter. Which of the following is the most likely cause of the lack of voltage?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "There are no anions in the solution that are able to be reduced by the cell",
            "X": "There are no cations in the solution that are able to be reduced by the cell",
            "Y": "The lead (III) cations produce a precipitate with chloride, so they do not reduce",
            "Z": "The magnesium ions produce a precipitate with chloride, so they do not reduce"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify, respectively, the types of substance generated when using the following four industrial processes: 1) Bessemer process, 2) Deville process, 3) Otswald process, 4) Mond process.",
        "Answer": "1) BE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following species cannot act as an oxidizing agent on calcium metal in aqueous conditions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Iodide",
            "X": "Permanganate",
            "Y": "Nitrate",
            "Z": "Bromine"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Molecular orbital theory predicts that the nitric oxide molecule will have 8 valence electrons in bonding orbitals and 3 electrons in antibonding orbitals. With what bond order does this correspond?",
        "Answer": "2.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many electrons in an atom of vanadium in its ground state have an angular-momentum quantum number of 2?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the IUPAC name of the organic product formed from the hydroboration-oxidation of 1-Hexyne?",
        "Answer": "HEXANAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true of the Born-Oppenheimer approximation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Molecular vibrations do not significantly contribute to the translational energy of the molecule",
            "X": "The exact position of the nucleus in a bond cannot be determined",
            "Y": "Electronic and nuclear motion can be separated since nuclear motion is significantly slower than electron motion",
            "Z": "Two nuclei that approach one another at a distance have no attractive or repulsive forces"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A current, equivalent to 0.5 faradays, is passed through a solution containing copper (II) sulfate. How much copper in grams can be plated out?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3.2",
            "X": "16",
            "Y": "32",
            "Z": "64"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements is paramagnetic?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Manganese",
            "X": "Neon",
            "Y": "Silver",
            "Z": "Zinc"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following group 6A hydrides has the highest boiling point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "H2O",
            "X": "H2S",
            "Y": "H2Se",
            "Z": "H2Te"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Blue light has a frequency of about 7.0 x 1014 hertz. Which of the following is the wavelength of this light in centimeters?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "4.3 x 10-5",
            "X": "8.4 x 10-8",
            "Y": "3.1 x 10-12",
            "Z": "2.0 x 10-24"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Your teacher wants you to use the Clausius-Clapeyron  equation to determine the vapor pressure at a particular temperature. Assuming you know the value for the gas constant, what other two values must you be given?",
        "Answer": "TEMPERATURE CHANGE AND ENTHALPY OF VAPORIZATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Liquids with weak intermolecular forces tend to have high surface tension",
            "X": "Liquids with strong intermolecular forces tend to have high surface tension",
            "Y": "Liquids with weak intermolecular forces tend to have high vapor pressures",
            "Z": "Cohesion forces refer to intermolecular attractions between like molecules"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following gases will exhibit the greatest deviation from ideal gas behavior?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbon dioxide",
            "X": "Methane",
            "Y": "Sulfur dioxide",
            "Z": "Molecular oxygen"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming each of the following is in an aqueous solution with a 1 molar concentration, which of the following solutions would have the highest conductivity at room temperature?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Potassium hydroxide",
            "X": "Aluminum nitrate",
            "Y": "Magnesium chloride",
            "Z": "Iron (II) sulfate"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The pH of aqueous hydrogen cyanide most accurately represents which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The negative base-10 logarithm of the initial molar hydronium ion concentration",
            "X": "The negative base-10 logarithm of the equilibrium molar hydronium ion concentration",
            "Y": "The negative base-10 logarithm of the initial molar hydrogen cyanide concentration",
            "Z": "The negative base-10 logarithm of the equilibrium molar hydrogen cyanide concentration"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the molar mass of chlorine is 35 grams per mole, of oxygen is 16 grams per mole, and of hydrogen is 1 gram per mole, what is the molar mass in grams per mole of hypochlorous acid?",
        "Answer": "52"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following can behave as a Lewis acid, but NOT as a Br\u00f8nsted-Lowry acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "NH3",
            "X": "H2CO3",
            "Y": "BF3",
            "Z": "HSO3-"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the molecular geometry of sulfur tetrafluoride?",
        "Answer": "SEESAW"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A total of 50.0 milliliters of 0.100 molar sulfuric acid are used to titrate 10.0 milliliters of sodium hydroxide to its endpoint. Which of the following is the molarity of the sodium hydroxide?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.025",
            "X": "0.100",
            "Y": "0.50",
            "Z": "1.00"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following solid compounds would NOT be soluble to a large extent in water, but would be soluble in hydrochloric acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ba(NO3)2",
            "X": "CuSO4",
            "Y": "MgCO3",
            "Z": "KClO4"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming complete dissociation and the absence of ion pairing, which of the following 1.00 molar aqueous solutions would have the lowest freezing point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sucrose",
            "X": "Sodium chloride",
            "Y": "Calcium hydroxide",
            "Z": "Potassium phosphate"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The specific heat of an unknown metal is  0.230 joules per gram degree Celsius. A 45.0 gram sample of the metal is heated from 25.0o Celsius to 35.0o Celsius. How much heat in joules is required to heat the metal?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "10.4",
            "X": "104",
            "Y": "342",
            "Z": "600"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answers to the nearest integer, convert the following four pressures to atmospheres: 1) 203 kilopascals, 2) 2660 Torr, 3) 2.2 bar, and 4) 3700 millimeters of mercury.",
        "Answer": "1) 2, 2) 3, 3) 2, 4) 5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the maximum number of orbitals allowed when l = 5 [L equals 5]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2",
            "X": "5",
            "Y": "11",
            "Z": "13"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank the following four substances according to increasing boiling point: 1) helium, 2) water, 3) ammonia, 4) carbon monoxide.",
        "Answer": "1, 4, 3, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the IUPAC name for the acid with the following formula: CH3CO2H?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Formic acid",
            "X": "Butyric acid [byoo-TIR-ik]",
            "Y": "Propionic acid [proh-pee-ON-ik]",
            "Z": "Ethanoic acid"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the energy in joules of a photon with a frequency of 1.00 x 106 gigahertz?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "6.63 x 10-19",
            "X": "6.63 x 10-28",
            "Y": "6.63 x 10-34",
            "Z": "6.63 x 10-49"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an example of a disaccharide [dy-SAK-uh-ryd]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Glucose",
            "X": "Sucrose",
            "Y": "Cellulose",
            "Z": "Glycogen [GLY-kuh-juhn]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many milliliters of 0.1 molar sulfuric acid must be titrated with 20 milliliters of 0.5 molar sodium hydroxide in order reach the equivalence point?",
        "Answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the characteristic feature of a metallic crystal?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The metallic bond is directional",
            "X": "The positive ion is free to move",
            "Y": "The bonding forces are weak",
            "Z": "The valence electrons are only loosely held and can move to neighboring atoms"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider the complete combustion of propane in oxygen. Providing your answer to two significant figures, if 32 grams of oxygen are consumed in the reaction, how many grams of carbon dioxide are produced?",
        "Answer": "26"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In electroplating, the object to be electroplated is placed at which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The anode",
            "X": "The cathode",
            "Y": "Either the anode or cathode",
            "Z": "The salt bridge"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds exhibits hydrogen bonding and can act as a Lewis base?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ozone",
            "X": "Ammonia",
            "Y": "Cesium fluoride",
            "Z": "Hydrogen fluoride"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "All except which of the following are true for rubidium fluoride?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It has a high boiling point",
            "X": "It dissolves in aqueous ammonia [AY-kwee-uhs]",
            "Y": "It conducts electricity in the solid state",
            "Z": "It is an electrolyte"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A sample of an ideal gas is placed in a sealed container of fixed volume. The gas is heated from 25.0o Celsius to 45.0o Celsius. Identify all of the following four factors that will increase: 1) the pressure of the gas, 2) the average kinetic energy of the gas, 3) the density of the gas, 4) the intermolecular forces.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following conjugate acid-base pairs will NOT function as a buffer?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "HNO3 and NO3-",
            "X": "NH3 and NH4+",
            "Y": "CH3COOH and CH3COO-",
            "Z": "HF and F-"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Giving your answers to the nearest integers, identify the pressure in atmospheres of a gas that starts at 1 atmosphere and 23\u00b0 Celsius at each of the following three temperatures: 1) 52o, 2) 317o, 3) 2700o.",
        "Answer": "1) 1, 2) 2, 3) 10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements is a metalloid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Copper",
            "X": "Magnesium",
            "Y": "Silicon",
            "Z": "Sulfur"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assuming that the transition of an electron in the hydrogen atom from the fourth to the second electron energy level is two electron volts, providing your answer to the nearest tenth, how many electronvolts is the transition between the first and third energy level?",
        "Answer": "9.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to the VSEPR model, what is the molecular geometry of carbon dioxide?",
        "Answer": "LINEAR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify, respectively, the VSEPR theory shapes of the following four molecules: 1) sulfur dioxide, 2) phosphorous pentachloride, 3) ammonia, and 4) boron trichloride.",
        "Answer": "1) BE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a colligative property?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Solubility",
            "X": "Freezing point depression",
            "Y": "Boiling point elevation",
            "Z": "Osmotic pressure"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the following three ions, what are the highest energy sublevels, respectively, that contain electrons: 1) Fe2+, 2) Sn4+, 3) P3-?",
        "Answer": "1) 3d, 2) 4d, 3) 3p"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The energy of a photon is directly proportional to which of the following properties?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Intensity",
            "X": "Frequency",
            "Y": "Polarity",
            "Z": "Wavelength"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "At extremely high temperatures and pressures, nitrogen gas and oxygen gas react to produce nitrogen dioxide gas. If the cylinder volume in which this reaction takes place is doubled and the temperature is held constant, which of the following effects will this have on the reaction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "No effect",
            "X": "The reaction will shift to the left",
            "Y": "The reaction will shift to the right",
            "Z": "The equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm] constant will double"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For which of the following processes is the change in entropy negative?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Water freezing",
            "X": "Dry ice sublimation",
            "Y": "Salt dissolving in water",
            "Z": "Gasoline burning"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The pressure of a mixture of three gases in a fixed volume container is 300 kilopascals. If the number of nitrogen molecules is three times the number of hydrogen molecules and the number of oxygen molecules is two times the number of hydrogen molecules, what are the partial pressures of the three gases?",
        "Answer": "N2 = 150; H2 = 50; O2 = 100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a state function?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Pressure",
            "X": "Work",
            "Y": "Temperature",
            "Z": "Internal energy"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What volume, in milliliters, of a 12.0 molar hydrochloric acid stock solution would you use to make 0.50 liters of a 6.00 molar hydrochloric acid solution?",
        "Answer": "250"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A pure enantiomeric sample that rotates plane-polarized light to the right is called which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Levorotary [lee-vuh-ROH-tawr-ee]",
            "X": "Dextrorotary [dek-stroh-ROH-tawr-ee]",
            "Y": "Meso [ME-zoh]",
            "Z": "Optically inactive"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When an aqueous solution of copper (II) bromide is electrolyzed, which of the following colors will occur at the anode?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Red brown",
            "X": "Greenish red",
            "Y": "Dark blue",
            "Z": "No color change"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A straight line is produced in the graph of the natural log of the concentration of a substance versus the time that the substance reacts. An experimenter can definitively say what about the reaction, with respect to this substance?",
        "Answer": "IT IS FIRST ORDER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "At a constant temperature, a syringe containing 20.0 milliliters of air at 1 atmosphere of pressure is pulled out so that the volume inside the syringe is increased to 40.0 milliliters. The total pressure of the gases inside the syringe decreases to approximately 0.5 atmospheres. Which of the following best explains this observation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gay-Lussac\u2122s Law",
            "X": "Charles\u2122s Law",
            "Y": "Boyle\u2122s Law",
            "Z": "Avogadro\u2122s Law"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A sample of ethyl ether has a boiling point of 35 degrees Celsius, whereas a sample of butanol has a boiling point of 120 degrees Celsius. To what intermolecular force can this discrepancy be attributed?",
        "Answer": "HYDROGEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A balloon expands isothermally from 1.0 to 10.0 liters against a constant external pressure of 7.0 atmospheres. The work in liter atmospheres performed by the system is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-63",
            "X": "+63",
            "Y": "-70",
            "Z": "+70"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements has more p electrons than s electrons?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Boron",
            "X": "Magnesium",
            "Y": "Germanium",
            "Z": "Nitrogen"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Imperfections in solids have a distinct effect on the properties of the materials. Which of the following describes 2D defects?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Pores and cracks",
            "X": "Grain boundaries and surface defects",
            "Y": "Vacancies and interstitials",
            "Z": "Edge and screw dislocations"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following four substances would have the highest melting point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C18H38",
            "X": "H2O",
            "Y": "MgCl2",
            "Z": "N2O5"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements about hydroboration-oxidation is false?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is a syn addition",
            "X": "The borane acts as the electrophile",
            "Y": "Overall, the reaction converts an alkene to an alcohol",
            "Z": "The common oxidizing agent used is sodium borohydride"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements about phase diagrams is NOT true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The point at which all three phases coexist is called the critical point",
            "X": "The line separating solid and vapor represents sublimation",
            "Y": "The line separating liquid and vapor represents boiling",
            "Z": "A negatively sloped line between the solid and liquid indicates that the solid will float in the liquid"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of an adiabatic gas expansion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Internal energy increases",
            "X": "Temperature of the working gas decreases",
            "Y": "Kinetic energy increases with average molecular speed",
            "Z": "Work done is inversely proportional to temperature difference between initial and final states"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider the following reaction:  2C2H6(g) + 7O2(g)  4CO2(g) + 6H2O(l) in which H  = - 3120 kilojoules. If 3.00 grams of ethane are burned, how many kilojoules of heat are produced?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1560",
            "X": "624",
            "Y": "312",
            "Z": "156"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An element\u2122s most stable ion forms an ionic compound with iodine having the formula, XI2. If the ion of element X has a mass of 89 amu and has 36 electrons, which of the following correctly matches the identity of the element and how many neutrons it has?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Strontium and 51",
            "X": "Krypton and 55",
            "Y": "Selenium and 55",
            "Z": "Krypton and 53"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Two reactants are mixed in a bomb calorimeter and a reaction occurs. The temperature of the calorimeter rises. Which of the following statements regarding the reaction is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The reaction is absorbing thermal energy",
            "X": "The reaction is endothermic",
            "Y": "The reaction is releasing thermal energy",
            "Z": "The reaction energy is equal to qT"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Determine the entropy change, including sign, in joules per mole Kelvin when one mole of nitrogen gas is added to hydrogen gas to form ammonia gas. Assume standard molar entropies to be 192 for dinitrogen, 131 for dihydrogen, and 193 for ammonia.",
        "Answer": "-199"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If equal quantities by mass of gases A, B, C, and D are added to a closed container of fixed volume, and the total pressure in the container is 760 torr, the partial pressure of A is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "25% of the total pressure",
            "X": "Dependent on the size of the container",
            "Y": "Directly related to its mole fraction",
            "Z": "A function of its molar mass"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "At 25\u00b0 Celsius, the standard reduction potential of Fe3+ to Fe2+ is +0.77 volts. Providing your answer to two significant figures, what is the potential, in volts, of a platinum electrode dipped in a solution of 0.0005 molar Fe3+ and 0.05 molar Fe2+?",
        "Answer": "0.89"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A nimble minded Science Bowl contestant makes a concentrated solution of sodium hydroxide which she adds to a solution of potassium permanganate. The permanganate ion reacts to form which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "MnO42-",
            "X": "MnO4-",
            "Y": "Mn2O3",
            "Z": "Mn2+"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Transition metals can have iodine atoms as ligands; however, the iodine atom is quite large in size. Based on this information, what is the point group of titanium (IV) iodide?",
        "Answer": "Td"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider the following reaction:  Cl2 (g) + 2NaOH (aq) (aq) +H2O (l) + NaCl(aq). Which of the following is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "This is a disproportionation reaction",
            "X": "The oxidation number of the oxygen changes",
            "Y": "The oxidation number of the sodium changes",
            "Z": "The oxidation number of the chlorine remains constant"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electron count for Pd(PPh3)2Br2?",
        "Answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A DoE researcher runs a redox reaction for a Daniell cell:  Cu 2+ (aq) + Zn (s) 2+ (aq) + Cu (s). Given that the equilibrium constant for this reaction is 1.65 x 1037 at 25 degrees Celsius, the E0 [ E naught] 0 [delta G zero] for this reaction are which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Both positive",
            "X": "Both negative",
            "Y": "Both zero",
            "Z": "E0 0  is negative"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In free radical polymerization [pol-lim-er-uh-ZAY-shuhn], many different substituents can be employed to stabilize the chain end radical. All except which of the following are strong stabilizers of the radical?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "CN",
            "X": "C6H5",
            "Y": "OCH3",
            "Z": "CO2CH3"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following species does NOT have at least two equally favorable resonance structures?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C6H6",
            "X": "NO2-",
            "Y": "CO2",
            "Z": "SO2"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "[delta H] is  [delta S] is negative. In which of the following temperature limits is the reaction spontaneous?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Not spontaneous at any temperature",
            "X": "Spontaneous at only high temperatures",
            "Y": "Spontaneous at only low temperatures",
            "Z": "Spontaneous at all temperatures"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following substances would you expect to have the highest molar entropy at standard conditions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Argon gas",
            "X": "Butane gas",
            "Y": "Sulfur dioxide gas",
            "Z": "Gaseous water"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to the VSEPR model, what is the molecular geometry of xenon [ZEE-non] tetrafluoride?",
        "Answer": "SQUARE PLANAR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A mass of hot copper with a heat capacity of 2.0 joules per Kelvin is dropped into the same volume of water and loses 80 joules of thermal energy. The final temperature of the copper is 295 Kelvin. What was its initial temperature in Kelvin?",
        "Answer": "335"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following tends to crystallize in a simple cubic unit cell?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Polonium",
            "X": "Copper",
            "Y": "Aluminum",
            "Z": "Iron"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Free radical polymerization can be initiated in several different ways. Peroxides and azo compounds frequently act as which of the following types of initiator?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Thermal",
            "X": "Photochemical",
            "Y": "Ionizing",
            "Z": "Redox"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A buffer solution is 0.05 molar in lactic acid and 0.5 molar in sodium lactate. If the pKa of lactic acid is 3.85, what is the pH of this solution?",
        "Answer": "4.85"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds is insoluble in water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Potassium acetate",
            "X": "Aluminum sulfide",
            "Y": "Lithium carbonate",
            "Z": "Magnesium bromide"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Place the following four molecules in order from lowest to highest entropy of vaporization: 1) hydrogen chloride, 2) ammonia, 3) water, 4) hydrogen fluoride.",
        "Answer": "4, 1, 2, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the names for positive and negative ions, respectively?",
        "Answer": "POSITIVE = CATIONS;  NEGATIVE = ANIONS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 4 substances in order of increasing pH:  orange juice;  human gastric juice;  blood;  aqueous ammonia",
        "Answer": "HUMAN GASTRIC JUICE;  ORANGE JUICE;  BLOOD;  AQUEOUS AMMONIA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the combustion of methane, if the supply of oxygen is somewhat insufficient, what colorless, odorless and poisonous gas is produced?",
        "Answer": "CARBON MONOXIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Element number 19 has an isotope named potassium-40.  How many neutrons does this isotope contain?",
        "Answer": "21"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many unpaired electrons are in a neutral bromine atom?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the term used to describe the resistance to flow of a liquid:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "viscosity",
            "X": "surface tension",
            "Y": "maleability",
            "Z": "vapor pressure"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What scientific principle BEST describes why fresh pickles soaked in brine shrivel up after a period of time?",
        "Answer": "OSMOSIS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If two solutions that are separated by a semipermeable membrane have the same osmotic pressure, they are said to be:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "isotonic",
            "X": "hypotonic",
            "Y": "hypertonic",
            "Z": "hyperosmotic"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is considered a monoprotic acid:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "sulfuric acid",
            "X": "hypochlorous acid",
            "Y": "carbonic acid",
            "Z": "sulfurous acid"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 4 cations in order of increasing ionic radii:  Mg2+;  Rb+;   Al3+;  Na+",
        "Answer": "Al3+;  Mg2+;  Na+;  Rb+"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The titration of a weak base, 0.100 molar NaCN, with a strong acid, 0.100 molar HCl, results in a solution at the equivalence point having a pH of:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "between 7 and 10",
            "X": "7",
            "Y": "between 4 and 7",
            "Z": "between 1 and 3"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In grams per liter, what is density of a gas whose molar mass is 134.4 grams per mole at standard temperature and pressure?",
        "Answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The hybridization of one \u00d4s\u00d5 (read as: one <pause> s) orbital and two \u00d4p\u00d5 (read as: two <pause> p) orbitals creates how many sp2 hybrid orbitals?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A molecule whose geometry of electron domains is tetrahedral and whose shape is bent or angular is:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "water",
            "X": "sulfur dioxide",
            "Y": "carbon dioxide",
            "Z": "ammonium"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the bond angles around each carbon in a benzene ring?",
        "Answer": "120\u00bc"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many carbons are in the following compound:  (read slowly)  4-ethyl-4-methyl octane",
        "Answer": "11"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following strong acids, all at 0.1 molar concentration, will have the LOWEST pH value:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "H2SO4",
            "X": "HNO3",
            "Y": "HCl",
            "Z": "HClO4"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Giving its proper charge, what is the oxidation number of the manganese atom in the following compound:  MnO4\u00d0  (read as: M, N, O, 4, minus)",
        "Answer": "+7"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In which positions on the benzene ring are the methyl groups found in the compound o-xylene or ortho-xylene (read as:  ORTHO-ZIE-lean):",
        "Answer": "1 AND 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a tertiary alcohol:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2-propanol",
            "X": "ethanol",
            "Y": "2-methyl-2-propanol",
            "Z": "1,2-ethanediol"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Predict the bond angle or shape for the central atom in a molecule of beryllium dichloride:",
        "Answer": "180\u00bc"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Avogadro\u00d5s gas law concerns which of the following two variables:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "temperature and pressure",
            "X": "pressure and volume",
            "Y": "temperature and volume",
            "Z": "moles and volume"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the systematic IUPAC name for the compound Fe(NO2)3?",
        "Answer": "IRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To the second decimal place, what is the concentration of nitrate ions, in moles per liter, in a 0.26 molar Al(NO3)3 solution?",
        "Answer": "0.78"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following salt solutions, all at 1.0 molar concentration, will have a pH value less than 7:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "NH4Cl",
            "X": "NaC2H3O2",
            "Y": "KCl",
            "Z": "LiBr"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 4 compounds that exhibit  hydrogen bonding:  CH4;  H2S;  NH3;  CH3OH",
        "Answer": "NH3;  CH3OH"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is typically TRUE of organic compounds:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "acetylene contains delocalized pi bonds",
            "X": "the simplest carboxylic acid is ethanoic acid",
            "Y": "ketones have no hydrogen atoms directly attached to the carbonyl group",
            "Z": "alcohols contain nonpolar hydroxyl groups"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rounded to the nearest whole number, what is the percent of magnesium in magnesium carbonate, given the atomic mass of magnesium is 24 grams per mole?",
        "Answer": "29"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements has the largest second ionization energy:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "fluorine",
            "X": "nitrogen",
            "Y": "boron",
            "Z": "lithium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following compounds in order of INCREASING ionic characteristic:  HCl;  LiBr;  CO;  KF",
        "Answer": "CO;  HCl;  LiBr;  KF"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The hybridization of one \u00d4s\u00d5 (read as: one <pause> s) orbital and 3 \u00d4p\u00d5 (read as: three <pause> p) orbitals and one \u00d4d\u00d5 (read as: one <pause> d) orbital creates how many sp3d hybrid orbitals?",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A solution contains 0.50 moles of methanol in 100 grams of water.  What is the mole fraction of methanol, to the second decimal place?",
        "Answer": "0.08"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calculate the atom percent composition, rounded to the nearest whole number, for each atom in acetic acid:",
        "Answer": "C = 25%;  H = 50%;  O = 25%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calculate the mass percent composition, rounded to the nearest whole number, for each atom in acetic acid:",
        "Answer": "C = 40%;  H = 7%;  O = 53%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of magnetism exists in substances in which electrons are unpaired and are very weakly attracted by magnetic fields?",
        "Answer": "PARAMAGNETISM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following diatomic molecules will exhibit paramagnetism:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "B2",
            "X": "N2",
            "Y": "C2",
            "Z": "F2"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a term used to describe the electronic geometry around a central atom that has 5 regions of high electron density:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "tetrahedral",
            "X": "trigonal pyramidal",
            "Y": "trigonal bipyramidal",
            "Z": "octahedral"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an aromatic amino acid:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "glutamine",
            "X": "tryptophan",
            "Y": "phenylalanine",
            "Z": "tyrosine"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules has the highest bond enthalpy, or energy it would take to break apart the bond:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "F2",
            "X": "H2",
            "Y": "HCl",
            "Z": "CO"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Silver iodide, or AgI, is LEAST soluble in which of the following aqueous solutions:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "NaOH",
            "X": "distilled water",
            "Y": "HNO3",
            "Z": "KI"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following 3 ionic solids in terms of their lattice energies or enthalpies, going from the HIGHEST to the LOWEST:  LiBr;  KBr;  NaBr",
        "Answer": "LiBr;  NaBr;  KBr"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 3 oxoacids or oxyacids in order of INCREASING acid strength:  HBrO3;  HBrO2;  HBrO",
        "Answer": "HBrO;  HBrO2;  HBrO3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules has an electron pair geometry that matches its molecular geometry:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "H2O",
            "X": "NH3",
            "Y": "SO2",
            "Z": "PCl5"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a constitutional isomer of the organic compound whose molecular formula is C4H8:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1-butene",
            "X": "2-butene",
            "Y": "2-methyl-1-butene",
            "Z": "2-methyl-1-propene"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For a given chemical reaction at constant temperature and pressure, if the value for Gibbs free-energy change is a negative, the reaction is always:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "endothermic",
            "X": "exothermic",
            "Y": "spontaneous",
            "Z": "nonspontaneous"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a phase diagram, the solid-liquid line has a negative slope for which of the following pure substances:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "carbon dioxide",
            "X": "water",
            "Y": "ammonia",
            "Z": "argon"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In order to find the heat of reaction, or delta H naught, for a reaction using standard enthalpies of formation, the working formula is:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "delta H products minus delta H reactants",
            "X": "delta H reactants minus delta H products",
            "Y": "delta H reactants plus delta H products",
            "Z": "delta H products plus delta H reactants"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short answer",
        "Question": "In crystallography, what is the coordination number, or number of nearest neighbors, of an atom in the simple cubic unit cell structure?",
        "Answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Predict the bond angles, in degrees, for atoms in a molecule of boron trichloride:",
        "Answer": "120\u00bc"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider a flexible balloon filled with 3.0 moles of helium at a temperature of 27\u00bcC and at a pressure of 101.3 kilopascals.  What is the volume in the balloon, in liters to the nearest whole number?",
        "Answer": "74"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the electronic pair geometry and the molecular geometry typical of the molecule with the general formula AB4U, where A represents the central atom, B represent the bonded atoms, and U represent the unbonded electron pair:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "tetrahedral and angular",
            "X": "trigonal bipyramidal and seesaw",
            "Y": "octahedral and square pyramidal",
            "Z": "octahedral and square planar"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the net ionic equation that occurs when aqueous solutions of ammonium sulfate and barium nitrate are mixed:",
        "Answer": "Ba2+ + SO42\u00d0 ! BaSO4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Phenylalanine (read as: FEE-nal-AL-ah-neen) is converted into which of the following amino acids by the enzyme phenylalanine hydroxylase:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "tyrosine",
            "X": "tryptophan",
            "Y": "threonine",
            "Z": "methionine"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In the equation for the Gibbs free energy change, if $H (read as: delta H) is positive and $S (read as: delta S) is positive, then the reactions are:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "product-favored only at high temperatures",
            "X": "product-favored only at low temperatures",
            "Y": "product-favored at all temperatures",
            "Z": "reactant-favored at all temperatures"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following will NOT produce a precipitate after the two aqueous solutions are mixed:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "barium chloride and sodium sulfate",
            "X": "lead nitrate and sodium chloride",
            "Y": "sodium bromide and rubidium chloride",
            "Z": "mercury one nitrate and calcium chloride"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an example of a weak base:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "NH3",
            "X": "NH4+",
            "Y": "CH3NH2",
            "Z": "C6H5NH2"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What rule states that electrons occupy all the orbitals of a given subshell singly before pairing begins and that these unpaired electrons have parallel spins?",
        "Answer": "HUND\u00d5S RULE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Knowing that gallium is in group 13 and Period 4, give the simplified ground-state electron configuration, starting with the last filled noble gas configuration of argon:",
        "Answer": "[Ar]4s23d104p1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the only amino acid that is not optically active?",
        "Answer": "GLYCINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider two tanks that are connected by a closed valve.  Tank A contains 6 liters of nitrogen gas at a pressure of 24 atmospheres and tank B contains 2 liters of oxygen gas at a pressure of 16 atmospheres.  If the temperature is constant and the valve is opened, what is the pressure, in atmospheres, of the gas mixture at equilibrium?",
        "Answer": "22"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true about amino acids:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "amino acids exist primarily as zwitterions",
            "X": "amino acid are amphoteric",
            "Y": "an amino acid becomes neutral at its isoelectric point",
            "Z": "tryptophan and cysteine contain sulfur atoms in their side chains"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 4 bonds in order of INCREASING bond lengths:  C!C (read as: C single bond C);  C=C (read as: C double bond C);  C\"C (read as: C triple bond C);  C\u00d0H (read as: C single bond H)",
        "Answer": "C\u00d0H;  C\"C;  C=C;  C!C"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following fatty acids has the HIGHEST melting point:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "an 18-carbon saturated fatty acid",
            "X": "an 18-carbon polyunsaturated fatty acid",
            "Y": "an 18-carbon monounsaturated fatty acid",
            "Z": "a 16-carbon monounsaturated fatty acid"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider an acid solution whose density is 1.5 grams per cubic centimeter and which is 30% acid by mass.  Find the volume, in milliliters, of the acid solution that is needed to contain 90 grams of acid:",
        "Answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In which of the following reversible gas reactions does the value of Kp = Kc  (read as: K sub P equal K sub C):",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A + B $ C  (read as: A plus B, double arrow, yields C)",
            "X": "2A + B $ C + D",
            "Y": "A + B $ C + D",
            "Z": "A $ B + C"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many milliliters of 0.1 molar hydrochloric acid are required to neutralize 50 milliliters of a 0.1 molar strontium hydroxide solution?",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify, by chemical formula, the oxidizing agent and the reducing agent, respectively, for the following reaction:   SiCl4  +  2Mg  !  2MgCl2  +  Si",
        "Answer": "OXIDIZING AGENT = SiCl4;  REDUCING AGENT = Mg"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the molar mass of a gas, in grams per mole to the nearest whole number, if it has a density of 0.50 grams per liter at 400K and standard pressure?",
        "Answer": "16"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which two of the following 5 amino acids are classified as basic because of the structure of their side chains:   arginine;  glycine;  glutamic acid;  phenylalanine;  lysine",
        "Answer": "ARGININE;  LYSINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "At 250K, the pressure of oxygen in a 1-liter container is 0.40 atmospheres.  If 0.10 moles of carbon dioxide are added to the container, what will be the new pressure, in atmospheres rounded to the first decimal place?",
        "Answer": "2.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following ionic compounds would have the highest melting point:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "NaF",
            "X": "NaCl",
            "Y": "CaF2",
            "Z": "MgO"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a zinc-lead voltaic cell, what is the maximum voltage, to the third decimal place, that can be obtained if the standard reduction potential for the zinc ion is  \u00d00.763 volts and for the lead ion is \u00d00.126 volts?",
        "Answer": "0.637"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider the following reaction, N2(gas) + 3H2(gas) \" 2NH3(gas), whose heat of reaction, or delta H, is \u00d091.8 kilojoules.  If the temperature for the reaction is increased, which of the following will occur:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the concentration of N2 increases",
            "X": "the concentration of H2 decreases",
            "Y": "the concentration of NH3 increases",
            "Z": "the concentration of N2 decreases"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many kilopascals of pressure are needed to compress 400 milliliters of a gas under the conditions of 150 kilopascals of pressure and 400K, to 600 milliliters at a new temperature of 200K?",
        "Answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Predict the shape of a molecule of phosphorous pentafluoride, whereby each phosphorous atom has 5 valence electrons to share with 5 fluorine atoms:",
        "Answer": "TRIGONAL BIPYRAMIDAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give all 3 angles, in degrees, that are present in phosphorous pentafluoride:",
        "Answer": "90;  120;  180"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In addition to iron, what 2 substances must be present for iron to rust?",
        "Answer": "OXYGEN;  WATER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Classify the following 3 elements as a halogen, metalloid, or transition metal, respectively:  silicon;  iron;  iodine",
        "Answer": "HALOGEN = IODINE;  METALLOID = SILICON;  TRANSITION METAL = IRON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What element is central to synthetic chemistry because of the unique ability of its atoms to bind to one another with single, double and triple bonds and form chains, branches and rings of varying sizes?",
        "Answer": "CARBON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many atoms of each element are in the following molecule:  Al2(SO4)3",
        "Answer": "Al = 2;  S = 3;  O = 12"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the MOST common method for separating a mixture of liquids based on the differences in component volatilities?",
        "Answer": "DISTILLATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of interaction occurs between molecules of H2O that causes it to have a higher boiling point than H2S?",
        "Answer": "HYDROGEN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What general term BEST describes the use of electrical current to cause a normally non-spontaneous reaction to occur?",
        "Answer": "ELECTROLYSIS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a chemical reaction, what is the term that describes the time required for a reactant to reach half its original concentration?",
        "Answer": "HALF-LIFE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an EXTENSIVE property of matter:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "temperature",
            "X": "density",
            "Y": "mass",
            "Z": "viscosity"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name for the phenomenon that occurs when a light beam becomes visible after passing through a colloid, an example of which is a beam of light passing through fog at night?",
        "Answer": "THE TYNDALL EFFECT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following techniques employs a moving phase and a stationary phase to separate components of a mixture:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "filtration",
            "X": "centrifugation",
            "Y": "distillation",
            "Z": "chromatography"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following would you expect to have an electron affinity of zero:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "chlorine",
            "X": "carbon",
            "Y": "hydrogen",
            "Z": "helium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name for the voltaic cells in which the reactants are continuously supplied to the cell and the products are continuously removed?",
        "Answer": "FUEL CELL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A Lewis base is defined as any species that does which of the following in a chemical reaction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "donates a proton",
            "X": "accepts a proton",
            "Y": "donates a pair of electrons",
            "Z": "accepts a pair of electrons"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT generally true regarding trends for the representative elements in the Periodic Table:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "nonmetals predominate the periodic table",
            "X": "metallic character increases from top to bottom",
            "Y": "nonmetallic character increases from left to right",
            "Z": "atomic radii increases from top to bottom"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which one of the following 5 atoms can violate the octet rule with more than 8 electrons:  O;  F;  Cl;  N;  C",
        "Answer": "Cl"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Boyle\u00d5s gas law concerns which of the following two variables:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "volume and pressure",
            "X": "volume and temperature",
            "Y": "pressure and temperature",
            "Z": "pressure and moles"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What mass of sodium hydroxide, in grams, would contain 40 grams of oxygen?",
        "Answer": "100"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following properties BEST explains why small liquid water droplets on a clean sheet of glass often coalesce into larger spherical water droplets:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "tensile strength",
            "X": "capillary action",
            "Y": "surface tension",
            "Z": "viscosity"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 3 liquids in order of DECREASING surface tension at 20\u00bcC:  water;  ethanol;  mercury",
        "Answer": "MERCURY;  WATER;  ETHANOL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The conversion of olein, a liquid oil, into stearin, a solid fat, by the addition of hydrogen in the presence of a catalyst and high heat is commonly known as what type of reaction?",
        "Answer": "HYDROGENATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many parts per million of arsenic are in a 2-gram water sample if it contains 8.0 micrograms of arsenic?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What simple alcohol is commercially produced by reacting carbon monoxide and hydrogen gas under pressure and heat and in the presence of a catalyst?",
        "Answer": "METHANOL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In standard chemical nomenclature, what is the ground-state electron configuration for fluorine?",
        "Answer": "1s22s22p5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following classifications of crystalline solids is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "quartz is a covalent network solid",
            "X": "calcium carbonate is an ionic solid",
            "Y": "sucrose is a molecular solid",
            "Z": "iron sulfide is a glassy solid"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the empirical formula for the following:  C18H33N6O3",
        "Answer": "C6H11N2O"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Colloids formed by the dispersal of a gas in a liquid are called:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "emulsions",
            "X": "foams",
            "Y": "aerosols",
            "Z": "solid sols"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a substance has a molecular weight of 88, which of the following will it be:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "KCl",
            "X": "C4H8O2",
            "Y": "RbF",
            "Z": "C6H14"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many nodes are in an \u00d4s\u00d5 orbital?",
        "Answer": "NONE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true of glucose:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "when glucose joins with galactose, fructose is formed",
            "X": "it is also called dextrose",
            "Y": "cellulose is a polymer of glucose molecules",
            "Z": "its formula is C6H12O6"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements regarding geometric or  cis-trans isomers is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "they have the same molecular formula",
            "X": "they have the same order of attachment of atoms",
            "Y": "they have the same orientation around a double bond",
            "Z": "they have the same functional groups"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the formal charge of nitrogen in the ammonia, or NH3, molecule?",
        "Answer": "0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "C6H6 is the molecular formula for what aromatic hydrocarbon?",
        "Answer": "BENZENE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider a mixture of nitrogen and oxygen gases that has a total pressure of 0.63 atmospheres.  If the partial pressure of nitrogen is 0.32 atmospheres, what is the partial pressure of oxygen in the mixture, in atmospheres to the second decimal place?",
        "Answer": "0.31"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a colligative property:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "vapor pressure lowering",
            "X": "osmotic pressure",
            "Y": "boiling point elevation",
            "Z": "color of solution"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a type of colloid that is classified as a sol at room temperature:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "gelatin",
            "X": "milk",
            "Y": "whipped cream",
            "Z": "marshmallow"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to the Arrhenius theory, an Arrhenius acid is any substance that does which of the following in a chemical reaction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "donates a pair of electrons",
            "X": "accepts a pair of electrons",
            "Y": "produces H+ ions in aqueous solution",
            "Z": "produces OH\u00d0 ions in aqueous solution"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If you were to evaporate 1 liter or kilogram of water, how many calories of latent heat are stored in the vapor?",
        "Answer": "540,000"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many carbon and hydrogen atoms are in a cyclopentane molecule?",
        "Answer": "CARBON = 5;  HYDROGEN = 10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the systematic IUPAC name for the following acid:  HClO",
        "Answer": "HYPOCHLOROUS ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Organic compounds that contain double bonds are said to be:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "saturated",
            "X": "unsaturated",
            "Y": "unable to undergo cis-trans isomerization",
            "Z": "unable to undergo addition reactions"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 4 elements in order of increasing atomic radii:  lithium;  oxygen;  potassium;  sodium",
        "Answer": "OXYGEN;  LITHIUM;  SODIUM;  POTASSIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "actinides are characterized by occupying the f-block of the periodic table",
            "X": "lanthanides are characterized by occupying the d-block of the periodic table",
            "Y": "alkali metals are the most reactive of all metallic elements",
            "Z": "actinides are metals"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In standard chemical nomenclature, what is the complete electron configuration for the sodium ion, Na+?",
        "Answer": "1s22s22p6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following would be the MOST soluble in water at room temperature:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Aluminum sulfate",
            "X": "Barium sulfate",
            "Y": "Lead sulfate",
            "Z": "Calcium sulfate"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the empirical formula for acetic acid?",
        "Answer": "CH2O"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true of halogens:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "iodine is the least reactive of the stable halogens",
            "X": "elemental halogens exist as diatomic molecules containing single covalent bonds",
            "Y": "their outermost electron configuration is represented by ns2np6",
            "Z": "halides of typical metals are ionic"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the total number of moles of gas in a mixture of oxygen and nitrogen gases is 12 moles, and the mole fraction of oxygen is 0.6, how many moles of oxygen gas are present, to the first decimal place?",
        "Answer": "7.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When iron becomes the ion Fe2+, it",
        "Options": {
            "W": "loses two, 3d electrons",
            "X": "loses two, 4s electrons",
            "Y": "gains two, 3d electrons",
            "Z": "gains two, 4s electrons"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements regarding the kinetic molecular theory of ideal gases is TRUE:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "the average kinetic energy of gaseous molecules is directly proportional to the absolute temperature of the sample",
            "X": "the volume occupied by the atoms and/or molecules in a gas is large",
            "Y": "collisions between gas particles are both elastic and inelastic",
            "Z": "between collisions, molecules exert both attractive and repulsive forces on each other"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The principle quantum number \u00d4n\u00d5 of an electron largely determines its:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "energy",
            "X": "spin",
            "Y": "shape",
            "Z": "orientation"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following compounds that exhibit ONLY London forces:  CH4;  N2;  BaCl2;  NH3",
        "Answer": "CH4;  N2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to the Bronsted-Lowry system, a base is defined as which of the following:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "electron pair acceptor",
            "X": "proton acceptor",
            "Y": "proton donor",
            "Z": "hydroxide donor"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the molecular formula for the conjugate base of the following Br\u00bfnsted-Lowry acid:  H2CO3",
        "Answer": "HCO3\u00d0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The reaction Ca(OH)2 + 2HCl ! 2H2O + CaCl2, is an example of what class of chemical reaction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "synthesis",
            "X": "single replacement",
            "Y": "double replacement",
            "Z": "decomposition"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A gas sample occupies a volume of 10.0 liters at a pressure of 800 torr.  If the pressure on the sample becomes 1.5 atmospheres and temperature remains constant, what volume does the gas now occupy, to the first decimal place in liters?",
        "Answer": "7.0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true regarding general trends for the representative elements in the Periodic Table:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "simple positive ions are always smaller than the neutral atoms from which they are formed",
            "X": "elements with low ionization energies lose electrons easily",
            "Y": "the size of anions increases from left to right",
            "Z": "electronegativities increase from left to right"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many carbons and hydrogens are in the following compound:  (read slowly)  2,4-dimethyl hexane",
        "Answer": "CARBON = 8;  HYDROGEN = 18"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the pH of a 1 % 10\u00d04 molar HCl solution?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Order the following 4 bonds from those with the LOWEST electronegativity difference to the GREATEST difference:  F-H;  O-H;  S-H;  Cl-H",
        "Answer": "S-H;  Cl-H;  O-H;  F-H"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Solvents, such as water, that can both donate and accept protons are typically described as:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "resonant",
            "X": "metalloid",
            "Y": "amphoteric",
            "Z": "polyprotic"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When going from left to right, elements in the same period of the Periodic Table have progressively smaller atomic radii because of:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "increased effective nuclear charge",
            "X": "decreased effective nuclear charge",
            "Y": "addition of electrons",
            "Z": "addition of neutrons"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a nonpolar molecule:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "HCN",
            "X": "HBr",
            "Y": "CHCl3",
            "Z": "CO2"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the general formula for a noncyclic alkene (read carefully as: al-KEEN) with n number of carbon atoms:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "CnH2n",
            "X": "CnH2n+2",
            "Y": "CnH2n\u00d02",
            "Z": "CnH2n+1"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Dalton\u00d5s gas law applies primarily to:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "non-ideal gases",
            "X": "gas mixtures",
            "Y": "density of gases",
            "Z": "molar mass of gas"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The oxidation number of oxygen is \u00d01 in:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "normal oxides",
            "X": "peroxides",
            "Y": "superoxides",
            "Z": "lithium oxide"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A molecule that contains 4 carbon-hydrogen single bonds and one carbon-carbon double bond contains how many sigma and pi bonds, respectively?",
        "Answer": "SIGMA = 5;  PI = 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the systematic IUPAC name for the compound RbClO4?",
        "Answer": "RUBIDIUM PERCHLORATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the pH of a solution having a hydroxide ion concentration of 1 % 10\u00d05 M?",
        "Answer": "9"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "At standard temperature and pressure, if a sample of argon has a volume of 67 liters, how many moles of argon are in the sample, to the nearest whole number?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For a series of chemical reactions, Hess's law provides a method for the summation of which property?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Heat of formation",
            "X": "Entropy",
            "Y": "Equilibrium constant",
            "Z": "Reaction rate"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the difference between heat and temperature?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Temperature is a form of heat, while heat is a measurement",
            "X": "Temperature is a measurement of molecular kinetic energy, while heat is a form of energy",
            "Y": "Heat and temperature have different wavelengths",
            "Z": "Heat and temperature have similar wavelengths but different amplitudes"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following relationships is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 food calorie is equal to 4.18 kilojoules",
            "X": "1 joule is equal to 1 food calorie",
            "Y": "1 joule is equal to 4.18 food calories",
            "Z": "1 food calorie is equal to 4.18 joules"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In order to calculate the heat of fusion for a piece of ice placed in warm water, you must know:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The energy released by the warm water and the mass of the water",
            "X": "The energy released by the warm water and the mass of the ice",
            "Y": "The energy released by the ice and the mass of the warm water",
            "Z": "The energy released by the ice and the mass of ice"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the empirical formula for C6H12O6?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C3H4O3",
            "X": "CHO",
            "Y": "CH2O",
            "Z": "C6H12O6"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the formula for iron II phosphate?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Fe3P2",
            "X": "FePO4",
            "Y": "Fe3(PO4)2",
            "Z": "Fe3(PO3)2"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Onions, shallots and leeks contain substances that cause our eyes to water. What element is common to the substances?",
        "Answer": "SULFUR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following 1.0 molar solutions will have the largest change in boiling point from that of pure water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium bromide",
            "X": "Magnesium iodide",
            "Y": "Sucrose",
            "Z": "Potassium phosphate"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the shape of the bonding structure of carbon in diamond?",
        "Answer": "TETRAHEDRAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the characteristic shape of tourmaline crystals?",
        "Answer": "HEXAGONAL  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The enthalpy in the reaction 3Q + 2R + 300 kilojoules ! (read as: yields) 6Y + Z is +150 kilojoules per mole of:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Q",
            "X": "R",
            "Y": "Y",
            "Z": "Z"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following changes will increase the reaction rate of the reaction between solid magnesium and gaseous oxygen: 2 Mg(s) + O2(g)  ! (read as: yields)  2 MgO(s) + heat?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Increasing the concentration of oxygen",
            "X": "Removing the magnesium oxide as soon as it is formed",
            "Y": "Reducing the temperature",
            "Z": "Decreasing the concentration of oxygen"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "any foreign substance added to water will cause a freezing point drop",
            "X": "a nonvolatile solute raises the boiling point of a solvent",
            "Y": "methane has a higher boiling point than ethane",
            "Z": "freezing point depression is a colligative property"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to standard chemical nomenclature, what is the formula for aluminum bicarbonate?",
        "Answer": "Al(HCO3)3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Carbon monoxide, or CO, will be adsorbed (read as: ADD-sorbed) onto the surface of which of the following metals the MOST strongly:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "iron",
            "X": "nickel",
            "Y": "cobalt",
            "Z": "gold"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 3 choices in order of increasing bond energies:  O2;  N2;  F2",
        "Answer": "F2;  O2;  N2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The molal (read as: moe-lahl) is a concentration unit that is most appropriately used in experimental designs that determine:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "freezing point depression",
            "X": "osmotic pressure",
            "Y": "density",
            "Z": "vapor pressure lowering"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electron capacity in each of the 4 sublevels s, p, d, and f, respectively?",
        "Answer": "s = 2;  p = 6;  d = 10;  f = 14"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A sample of oxygen gas is collected over water at 14\u00baC.  Knowing that the vapor pressure of water at 14\u00baC is 1.6 kilopascals, and that the pressure of the resultant mixture is 120 kilopascals, find the pressure, to the first decimal place, exerted by the dry oxygen alone:",
        "Answer": "118.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a colligative property of solutions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Vapor pressure elevation",
            "X": "Freezing point depression",
            "Y": "Boiling point elevation",
            "Z": "Osmotic pressure"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, which of the following four types of mixtures are generally considered homogeneous?  1) alloy, 2) suspension, 3) emulsion, 4) colloid",
        "Answer": "1) AL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The standard heat of formation of calcium oxide is \u00d0635.5 kilojoules per mole. What is the complete, balanced equation for the formation of calcium oxide, including the energy value?",
        "Answer": "Ca(s) + \" O2(g) ! CaO(S) + 635.5 kJ"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The following reaction between hydrogen and oxygen takes place in a closed container and at a temperature that maintains the water vapor in the gas phase: 2 H2O(g)  (read as: in equilibrium with) 2 H2(g) + O2(g). In one experiment, the equilibrium concentrations of the gases are as follows: [H2] = 2.0M, [O2] = 3.0M and [H2O] = 4.0M. Calculate the value of Keq for this reaction.",
        "Answer": "Keq = 0.75  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What do we call the ability of a single molecule to act both as a base and an acid?",
        "Answer": "AMPHOTERISM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Of which of the following acid-base titrations would the pH be less than 7 at the equivalence point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Strong base, weak acid",
            "X": "Strong base, strong acid",
            "Y": "Weak base, weak acid",
            "Z": "Strong acid, weak base"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A solution of barium hydroxide is neutralized with a phosphoric acid solution. Identify the molecular forms of the two products that are produced in this reaction.",
        "Answer": "Ba3(PO4)2 AND H2O"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The strength of the dispersion forces between two non-polar molecules increases with:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The number of hydrogen atoms in the molecule",
            "X": "The number of electrons in the molecule",
            "Y": "The magnitude of the largest electronegativity of the atoms involved",
            "Z": "The magnitude of the difference in electronegativity between the atoms"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the van 't Hoff factor for glucose?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What color of flame does lithium produce in a flame test?",
        "Answer": "RED  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following chemical bonds is not important in polymer formation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Glycosidic (read as: gly-koh-SYDIK)",
            "X": "Hydrogen",
            "Y": "Peptide",
            "Z": "Phosphodiester (read as: FOHS-foh-DY-ehs-tehr)"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What relationship exists between bond length and bond order?",
        "Answer": "INVERSE RELATIONSHIP"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following 1.0 molar solutions will have the highest pH?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrochloric acid",
            "X": "Nitrous acid",
            "Y": "Sulfuric acid",
            "Z": "Hydrobromic acid"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "10 milliliters of a 0.1 molar solution of which of the following substances added to 10 milliliters of a 0.1 molar acetic acid solution will form a buffer solution?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrochloric acid",
            "X": "Sodium chloride",
            "Y": "Sodium hydroxide",
            "Z": "Potassium acetate (read as: AH-seh-tayt)"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a polar, aprotic solvent?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Water",
            "X": "Methanol",
            "Y": "Dimethyl sulfoxide",
            "Z": "Chloroform"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What kind of isomers are mannose and glucose?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Enantiomers (read as: i-nahn-TEE-!e-mehrs)",
            "X": "Conformational isomers",
            "Y": "Mesoisomers",
            "Z": "Diastereoisomers (read as: dy-ah-STEHR-ee-\"E-mehrs)"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Transition metal elements have atoms or ions with which of the following orbitals partially filled?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "d",
            "X": "f",
            "Y": "p",
            "Z": "s"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which choice represents the electron configuration for the magnesium 2+ ion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1s2 2s2 2p6 3s2",
            "X": "1s2 2s2 2p6 3s2 3p2",
            "Y": "1s2 2s2 2p6 3s1",
            "Z": "1s2 2s2 2p6"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the pH for a solution with 0.01 mole of nitric acid in 1.0 liter of water?",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the nonsuperimposable mirror images of a chiral compound called?",
        "Answer": "ENANTIOMERS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the name of the compound HClO4?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrogen perchlorite",
            "X": "Chloric acid",
            "Y": "Perchloric acid",
            "Z": "Hypochloric acid"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a state function?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Volume",
            "X": "Energy",
            "Y": "Pressure",
            "Z": "Heat"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the pH of 1.0 mole of sodium hydroxide dissolved in 10 liters of water?",
        "Answer": "13"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two Lewis structures depict the ozone molecule equally well and there is no way to distinguish between the two structures. What is the term that describes this phenomenon?",
        "Answer": "RESONANCE  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The ability of geckos to climb smooth surfaces is due to which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrogen bonding",
            "X": "Van der Waals forces",
            "Y": "Ion-dipole forces",
            "Z": "Intramolecular forces"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Nanotechnologists are creating butterfly scale patterns on paper money to foil counterfeiters using which of the following substances?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Calcium oxide",
            "X": "Zinc oxide",
            "Y": "Magnesium oxide",
            "Z": "Aluminum oxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following bonds should have the longest length?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C-C (read as: C single bond C)",
            "X": "C=C (read as: C double bond C)",
            "Y": "C-H (read as: C single bond H)",
            "Z": "C!C (read as: C triple bond C)"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following contains polar covalent bonds?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "F2",
            "X": "HF",
            "Y": "NaH",
            "Z": "O2"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Most of the peptide chains in a myoglobin molecule adopt what secondary structure?",
        "Answer": "HELIX"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following does not describe how atoms in a CH2 group can vibrate?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Rocking",
            "X": "Symmetrical stretching",
            "Y": "See-sawing",
            "Z": "Twisting"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A chemist is trying to interpret the results of his Infra-Red Spectroscopy analysis of a compound. He sees a band of high absorbance, around 95%, at about 1775 inverse centimeters. What functional group does his compound most likely contain?",
        "Answer": "CARBONYL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "L-alanine and D-alanine are BEST classified as what type of isomers:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "cis",
            "X": "trans",
            "Y": "structural",
            "Z": "optical"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many sigma and pi bonds, respectively, are there in a  molecule with the following formula: [read slowly] CH3CHCHCH2CH3",
        "Answer": "SIGMA  14;  PI = 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following are the units of the rate constant for a  2nd order reaction given that concentration is measured in molarity and time in seconds:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "M\u01522s\u01521",
            "X": "M\u01521s\u01521",
            "Y": "Ms\u01521",
            "Z": "M\u01522minutes\u01521"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "1.0 gram of an unknown organic molecule is dissolved in 50.0 grams of benzene.   Determine the molecular mass of the unknown if this solution freezes at 4.5\u00baC.  Assume the freezing point constant of benzene is 5.0\u00baC per molal, and the freezing point of benzene is 5.5\u00baC.  Give your answer to the nearest whole number in grams per mole.",
        "Answer": "100 f = 5.5\u00ba \u0152 4.5\u00ba = 1.0\u00baC;  m f/ Kf = 1.0\u00ba/5.0\u00ba = 0.2m or 0.2mol/kg;"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider the following equilibrium reaction,  FeO(solid) + CO(gas) (solid) + CO2(gas), where \u015210 kilojoules.  Which of the following would have a similar effect on the equilibrium position as lowering the temperature:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "adding iron",
            "X": "increasing pressure",
            "Y": "removing carbon dioxide",
            "Z": "removing carbon monoxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the electrolysis of water, if a very small amount of sodium sulfate is added to the water, give the equation for the half reaction that occurs at the ANODE.  Make sure to indicate proper charges and the state of each substance, such as solid, liquid, aqueous, or gas:",
        "Answer": "2H2O(liquid)  O2(gas) + 4H+(aqueous) + 4e\u0152"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the overall reaction order for the following rate law:   rate = k[NH4+][NO2\u0152]   (read as: k times the concentration of NH4+ times the concentration of NO2\u0152)",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calculate the one-atmosphere boiling point elevation, in degrees Celsius to the 2nd decimal place, for a solution made by dissolving 1 gram of solute in 0.1 kilograms of water.  Assume the formula weight of the solute is 300 and the boiling point depression constant is 2.0\u00baC per molal..",
        "Answer": "0.07"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What letter designates the lowest energy subshell in any shell?",
        "Answer": "S"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify the scientist who proposed the existence of energy levels for the electrons in an atom.",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a common ion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Na2+",
            "X": "Al3+",
            "Y": "B2+",
            "Z": "Kr2+"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following has an electron configuration of 1s2 2s2 2p6 3s2 3p6 (read as: 1 s 2, 2 s 2, 2 p 6, 3 s 2, 3 p 6)?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium ion",
            "X": "Chlorine",
            "Y": "Neon",
            "Z": "Calcium ion"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true about the alpha particle?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is a hydrogen atom",
            "X": "It was discovered by J.J. Thomson",
            "Y": "It was used by Ernest Rutherford in experiments relating to the nucleus of the atom",
            "Z": "It is purely electromagnetic radiation"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What term best describes the type of reaction that converts uranium in the soil to radon?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Acid-base",
            "X": "Fusion",
            "Y": "Electromagnetic radiation",
            "Z": "Radioactive decay"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the process that best describes the transfer of electrons from one atom to another through electrostatic attraction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ionic bonding",
            "X": "Repulsion",
            "Y": "Nuclear force",
            "Z": "Covalent bonding"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The force between two electrically charged objects can be changed by altering what two quantities?",
        "Answer": "THE AMOUNT OF CHARGE AND THE DISTANCE BETWEEN THE OBJECTS  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is never considered evidence of a chemical change?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Phase change",
            "X": "Color change",
            "Y": "Formation of a precipitate",
            "Z": "Formation of a gas"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following represents a chemical property of sodium?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It is less dense than water",
            "X": "It has a melting point of 98.7 degrees Celsius",
            "Y": "It reacts with water to release hydrogen gas",
            "Z": "When cut with a knife, it has a shiny surface with a metallic luster"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a strong acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrochloric Acid",
            "X": "Phosphoric Acid",
            "Y": "Sulfuric Acid",
            "Z": "Perchloric Acid"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to the Br\u00bfnsted-Lowry acid-base theory, which of the following species cannot function as an acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Water",
            "X": "Hydrogen carbonate ion",
            "Y": "Phosphate",
            "Z": "Hydroxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is characteristic of a compound?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Elements must be combined in a very specific ratio",
            "X": "Properties can vary throughout the sample",
            "Y": "It can be classified as a colloid",
            "Z": "It can be classified as heterogeneous"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following results will identify an unknown substance as a mixture instead of a compound?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It cannot be separated by distillation",
            "X": "It is homogeneous",
            "Y": "It has a constant melting point",
            "Z": "Centrifuging can separate the components"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an element that is very important to human life, is contained in vitamin B-12, belongs to a group of transition metals, and has magnetic properties like iron:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "selenium",
            "X": "cobalt",
            "Y": "zinc",
            "Z": "manganese"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the pH of a 1 molar NaOH solution at 25\u00baC?",
        "Answer": "14"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a weak electrolyte:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "ammonia",
            "X": "dilute sulfuric acid",
            "Y": "1 molar sodium chloride",
            "Z": "dilute perchloric acid"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A molecular solid will most typically have which of the following melting points:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "very high",
            "X": "high to very high",
            "Y": "low",
            "Z": "variable"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the bond order between the 2 carbon atoms in acetylene?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to standard chemical nomenclature and indicating the proper charge, what is the formula for the sulfite ion?",
        "Answer": "SO32\u0152"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the atomic sublevel with the next highest energy after the 4p sublevel:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "4d",
            "X": "4f",
            "Y": "5s",
            "Z": "5p"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the  electronic configuration for sulfur, located in Period 3 and Group 16 of the Periodic Table:",
        "Answer": "1s22s22p63s23p4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name the following compound: N2O4.",
        "Answer": "DINITROGEN TETROXIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the equation for the combustion of octane?",
        "Answer": "2C8H18 + 25O2            18H2O + 16CO2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is standard temperature, in Kelvin, as defined in ideal gas equations?",
        "Answer": "273 KELVIN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "To calculate the pressure within a known volume of gas, which of the following pieces of information is NOT needed?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Temperature",
            "X": "Specific gravity",
            "Y": "Moles of gas",
            "Z": "Gas constant"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What best describes a solid whose atoms are arranged in a regular pattern?",
        "Answer": "CRYSTAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The unit cell in a crystal system may have one of several forms. Which of the following describes a cubic unit cell with one identical particle in the center of the cell?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Simple cubic",
            "X": "Orthohombic",
            "Y": "Triclinic",
            "Z": "Body-centered cubic"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A pH of of 2 has what pOH?",
        "Answer": "12"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the electromotive force of the anode in a galvanic cell is       -0.76 volts and the electromotive force of the cathode is 0.34 volts, calculate the electromotive force of the cell in volts. Provide your answer as a decimal to the nearest hundredth.",
        "Answer": "+1.10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If pure water is at its boiling point at standard pressure, how many additional calories of heat are needed to convert 1 gram of water from the liquid to the vapor state?",
        "Answer": "540"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name for the straight-chain alkane containing 5 carbons?",
        "Answer": "PENTANE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the electronegativity difference in the bonding atoms is intermediate in strength, what general type of bond is typically formed?",
        "Answer": "POLAR COVALENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a molecule having a nonpolar covalent bond:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "bromine gas",
            "X": "hydrogen fluoride",
            "Y": "water",
            "Z": "hydrogen bromide"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following are elements in the Periodic Table whose outer shell electrons are on two principal energy levels:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "alkali metals",
            "X": "noble gases",
            "Y": "alkaline Earth metals",
            "Z": "transition elements"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to standard chemical nomenclature and indicating the proper charge, what is the formula for potassium perchlorate?",
        "Answer": "KClO4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "hydrogen gas found in nature exists as a monatomic molecule",
            "X": "when 2 oxygen atoms combine to form O2, energy is released",
            "Y": "when chlorine gains 1 electron, it becomes larger",
            "Z": "noble gases tend not to bond because of their stable valence configurations"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Knowing that the chemical name for gypsum is calcium sulfate dihydrate, gypsum is what percent water by weight?  Assume the atomic masses of calcium = 40; sulfur = 32 and oxygen = 16.  A",
        "Answer": "Assume the atomic masses of calcium = 40; sulfur = 32 and oxygen = 16.  AN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the general name for a hypothetical gas that obeys Boyles\u2122s law at all temperatures and pressures?",
        "Answer": "IDEAL GAS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true of ideal gases:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2 or more gases form homogeneous mixtures in all proportions",
            "X": "collisions between gas particles are both elastic and inelastic",
            "Y": "they diffuse rapidly",
            "Z": "they assume the shapes of their containers"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What are the products for the complete combustion of methane?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbon and hydrogen",
            "X": "Carbon dioxide and hydrogen",
            "Y": "Carbon monoxide and water",
            "Z": "Carbon dioxide and water"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "For the complete combustion of butane, butane plus oxygen produces carbon dioxide and water vapor. What is the balanced equation for the combustion of butane?",
        "Answer": "2C4H10 + 13O2 !"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Determine the solubility product constant (or Ksp) of silver bromide, given that its molar solubility is 5.71  10-7 moles per liter.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "3.26  10-13",
            "X": "5.71  10-7",
            "Y": "1.14 10-6",
            "Z": "2.14  10-4"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which of the following are strong bases in aqueous solution: 1) potassium hydroxide, 2) ammonia, 3) sodium chloride, 4) calcium hydroxide, or 5) beryllium hydroxide?",
        "Answer": "POTASSIUM HYDROXIDE AND CALCIUM HYDROXIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the mass of an electron relative to a proton?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "9.1 x 10-31",
            "X": "8.2 x 10-14",
            "Y": "1/1836",
            "Z": "0.51"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Sulfuric acid is used to neutralize a solution of sodium hydroxide. Calculate the number of moles of sodium hydroxide required to completely neutralize two moles of sulfuric acid.",
        "Answer": "4  ________________________________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a strong acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrofluoric acid",
            "X": "Hydrochloric acid",
            "Y": "Hydrobromic acid",
            "Z": "Hydroiodic acid"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following would be the resulting pH from the reaction of equal amounts of a strong acid with a strong base?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Less than 7",
            "X": "Equal to 7",
            "Y": "More than 7",
            "Z": "The reaction is independent of the pH"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A molecule having a chemical formula of CH3CCCH3 would be classified by which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Alkyne",
            "X": "Alkene",
            "Y": "Alkane",
            "Z": "Aldehyde (read as: AHL-deh-hyd)"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The rare earth elements are primarily composed of elements from which groups of the periodic table?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Transition metals and main group",
            "X": "Alkali and alkaline",
            "Y": "Lanthanides (read as: LAHN-thah-nyds) and actindies",
            "Z": "Alkaline and transition metals"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How  would you classify a reaction in which solid potassium and chlorine gas react to form the ionic compound potassium chloride?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Decomposition",
            "X": "Combustion",
            "Y": "Synthesis",
            "Z": "Disproportionation"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Generally, what type of reaction is an acid base reaction?",
        "Answer": "DOUBLE DISPLACEMENT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Determine the oxidation state of each of the elements in the polyatomic ion C2O42-.",
        "Answer": "CARBON = 3+; OXYGEN = 2-"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following 1.0 molar solutions will have the largest change in boiling point from that of pure water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium bromide",
            "X": "Magnesium iodide",
            "Y": "Sucrose",
            "Z": "Potassium phosphate"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What color are the chromophores NOT absorbing in a blue shirt?",
        "Answer": "BLUE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds is insoluble in water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Barium acetate",
            "X": "Beryllium acetate",
            "Y": "Lead acetate",
            "Z": "Silver acetate"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest tenth, if you start with 3 grams of Carbon-14, how many grams of isotope will remain after 3 half lives?",
        "Answer": "0.4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true about enzymes?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They catalyze most of the chemical changes that occur in a cell",
            "X": "They are unchanged by the reaction they catalyze",
            "Y": "They do not change the normal equilibrium position of a chemical system",
            "Z": "They change the amount of product that is produced"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In what range of colors do fireflies generally emit light?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Yellow to green",
            "X": "Orange to red",
            "Y": "Red to blue",
            "Z": "Blue to violet"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What are the two conditions that distinguish bioluminescence from chemiluminescence (read as: keh-mee-luh-mi-NEH-sehns)?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Bioluminescence occurs in living organisms and has hydrogen as a common reactant",
            "X": "Bioluminescence occurs in living organisms and requires an enzyme catalyst",
            "Y": "Bioluminescence occurs in living organisms and involves the emission of light at a lower energy than chemiluminescence (read as: keh-mee-luh-mi-NEH-sehns)",
            "Z": "Bioluminescence occurs uniquely in living organisms and has oxygen as a common reactant"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When chemists do flame tests, they often view the flame through a colored transparent piece of glass to filter out any sodium contamination. What color glass do they use?",
        "Answer": "COBALT BLUE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Specifying the sign, what is the oxidation state of phosphorus in Na2P2O6?",
        "Answer": "+5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What element has the lowest boiling point?",
        "Answer": "HELIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following bonds is the MOST polar?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "B-C",
            "X": "B-N",
            "Y": "B-O",
            "Z": "B-F"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following substances has the highest boiling point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Water",
            "X": "Methanol",
            "Y": "Ethyl alcohol",
            "Z": "Diethyl ether"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The pressure of 2 moles of an ideal gas at 27\u00a1 Celsius is 1.2 atmospheres. Providing your answer to the nearest tenth, if the temperature is increased by 100\u00a1 Celsius and the volume of the gas doubles, what is the new pressure of the gas in atmospheres?",
        "Answer": "0.8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the common name given to the industrial reaction in which nitrogen and hydrogen are reacted with a catalyst, forming ammonia?",
        "Answer": "HABER PROCESS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the molecular formula for strontium nitrite?",
        "Answer": "Sr(NO2)2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In which of the following compounds does nitrogen have an unpaired electron?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ammonia",
            "X": "Nitrous oxide",
            "Y": "Sodium nitrate",
            "Z": "Nitric oxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A saturated solution of calcium hydroxide is titrated with aqueous hydrochloric acid. Using proper chemical nomenclature and indicating the state of each substance, such as solid, liquid, aqueous, or gas, what is the balanced molecular equation for this reaction?",
        "Answer": "Ca(OH)2(aq) + 2HCl(aq) ! CaCl2(aq) + 2H2O(l)  [NOTE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a colligative property of a solution?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Freezing point depression",
            "X": "Osmotic pressure",
            "Y": "Percent by mass",
            "Z": "Boiling point elevation"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many liters of 2 molar sulfuric acid are required to titrate three liters of 0.4 molar nitric acid?",
        "Answer": "0.3 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When the equation O2 + C6H14 ! (read as: yields) CO2 + H2O is balanced with the lowest whole-number coefficients, what is the coefficient of O2?",
        "Answer": "19"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given the reaction: 4PH3(aq) ! (read as: yields) P4(g) + 6H2(g), if 0.0048 moles of PH3 are consumed each second of the experiment, providing your answer to the nearest ten thousandth, what is the rate of production in moles per second of P4?",
        "Answer": "0.0012  [NOTE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following species is NOT considered an electrolyte?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium hydroxide",
            "X": "Hydrogen chloride",
            "Y": "Aluminum nitrate",
            "Z": "Diethyl ether"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify all of the following four substances that would show a positive result in a Benedict\u00d5s test: 1) simple sugars, 2) starches, 3) proteins, 4) lipids.",
        "Answer": "SIMPLE SUGARS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The following gaseous phase reaction is in equilibrium:  CO + 2H2 ! (read as: is in equilibrium with) CH3OH. If you decrease the volume of the container holding the gas, what happens to the equilibrium?",
        "Answer": "SHIFTS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify all of the following four motions that describe how atoms in a methylene group can vibrate: 1) rocking, 2) symmetrical stretching, 3) see-sawing, 4) twisting.",
        "Answer": "ROCKING, SYMMETRICAL STRETCHING, AND TWISTING"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following pairs does NOT correctly match the element and its oxidation number?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Oxygen in H2O2 and -2",
            "X": "Bromine in Br2 and 0",
            "Y": "Sodium in NaCl and +1",
            "Z": "Sulfur in SO3!2 and +4"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify by name or number all of the following five factors upon which the rate of a gaseous phase reaction substantially depends: 1) reactant concentration, 2) molecule size, 3) number of distinct products and reactants, 4) activation energy, 5) pressure.",
        "Answer": "REACTANT CONCENTRATION, ACTIVATION ENERGY, PRESSURE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds is generally considered soluble in water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium nitrate",
            "X": "Magnesium carbonate",
            "Y": "Silver chloride",
            "Z": "Barium sulfate"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Nitrous acid plus calcium hydroxide yield calcium nitrite (read as: ni-TRITE) plus water. Which of the following represents the coefficients for the compounds, in the order listed, when the reaction is correctly balanced?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1, 2, 1, 1",
            "X": "1, 1, 1, 1",
            "Y": "2, 2, 1, 2",
            "Z": "2, 1, 1, 2"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name two of the elements that are common exceptions to the octet rule, because they are frequently found in compounds in which they have only six valence electrons.",
        "Answer": ""
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Regarding butylene\u00d5s alkene isomers, which of the following statements is correct?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Some are cis-trans isomers",
            "X": "Some are chiral",
            "Y": "Some are enantiomers (read as: in-AHNT-ee-oh-mehrs)",
            "Z": "Some are atropisomers (read as: ah-troh-pee-s#e-mehrs)"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name the two spectator ions in the reaction of lead (II) nitrate and sodium sulfide.",
        "Answer": "NO3! AND Na+"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Place the following molecules or ions in order of increasing stability: He2, O2, O22!, He2+, O2!.",
        "Answer": "He2, He2+, O22!, O2!, AND O2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify which of the following three species is paramagnetic: 1) C",
        "Answer": "1) CO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, order the following four elements from least to most exothermic electron affinity: 1) fluorine, 2) chlorine, 3) bromine, 4) iodine.",
        "Answer": "IODINE, BROMINE, FLUORINE, CHLORINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements will react most vigorously with water to form hydrogen gas as a by-product?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Magnesium",
            "X": "Barium",
            "Y": "Potassium",
            "Z": "Bismuth"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If you want to separate a liquid mixture containing at least one volatile component, which of the following techniques could you use?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Scrubbing",
            "X": "Stripping",
            "Y": "Electrorefining",
            "Z": "Effusion"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds is NOT named CORRECTLY?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "SnF2: stannous fluoride",
            "X": "CuCl: cuprous chloride",
            "Y": "PbO2: plumbic oxide",
            "Z": "FeO: ferric oxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to the Big Bang theory, stable isotopes of what five elements were produced shortly after the universe was formed?",
        "Answer": "HYDROGEN, HELIUM, LITHIUM,"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following has a melting point of 185\u00baC and readily dissolves in water at room temperature, but is NOT an electrolyte:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "NaCl",
            "X": "decane",
            "Y": "methane",
            "Z": "sucrose"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the systematic chemical name for the following ionic compound:  Cr2(SeO4)3",
        "Answer": "CHROMIUM(III) SELENATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a substance whose molecular and empirical formulas are NOT the same:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "benzene",
            "X": "water",
            "Y": "ammonia",
            "Z": "sulfur dioxide"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a molecule with a square pyramidal molecular geometry around its central atom:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "PCl5",
            "X": "ClF5",
            "Y": "XeF4",
            "Z": "SF6"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "An organic compound with the formula C6H14 is an:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "alkane",
            "X": "alkene",
            "Y": "alkyne",
            "Z": "arene"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following gases has the highest effusion rate through a pinhole opening from one compartment to another and at room temperature:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "argon",
            "X": "CO2",
            "Y": "SO2",
            "Z": "helium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 3 concentration units that are temperature-dependent:  molal (read as: moe-LAHL);  molarity;  normality",
        "Answer": "MOLARITY;  NORMALITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calculate the enthalpy of vaporization, in kilojoules, of water at 25\u00baC and 1 atmosphere.  Assume the standard enthalpy of formation of liquid water is \u0152286 kilojoules and the standard enthalpy of formation of water gas is \u0152242 kilojoules:",
        "Answer": "44"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To identify the chemical compounds dissolved in a sample, a student dips a clean piece of nichrome wire into the sample and burns it in a flame. The flame burns red. What metal does the mixture probably contain?",
        "Answer": "CALCIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the decay mode and the daughter nuclide, respectively, of potassium-37?",
        "Answer": "ELECTRON CAPTURE, ARGON-37 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the specific name for the following functional group: a nitrogen atom bonded to two carbon chains and a hydrogen atom?",
        "Answer": "SECONDARY AMINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "At 25\u00a1 Celsius, the vapor pressure of water is about 3 kilopascals and the vapor pressure of methanol is about 15 kilopascals. Assuming no deviation from Raoult\u00d5s law, determine the vapor pressure, in kilopascals, of a mixture of 1 mole of methanol and 2 moles of water.",
        "Answer": "7 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify all of the following four substances that are substitutional alloys: 1) brass, 2) steel, 3) sterling silver, 4) pewter.",
        "Answer": "BRASS, STERLING SILVER, AND PEWTER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A chemist is trying to identify a chemical by determining its molar mass. A sample weighing 0.75 grams was dissolved in 0.10 kilograms of benzene and the freezing point depression was determined to be 0.50\u00a1 Celsius. Given the Kf for benzene of 5\u00a1 Celsius kilograms per mole, what is the molar mass of the chemical in grams per mole to the nearest whole number?",
        "Answer": "75"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A well near the beach is suspected to be contaminated with chloride ions from sea water. If chloride is present, which of the following will produce a cloudy suspension when mixed with the water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Silver nitrate",
            "X": "Sodium nitrate",
            "Y": "Potassium acetate",
            "Z": "Calcium bromide"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The molar mass of carbon dioxide is 44 grams. Providing your answer to the nearest integer, if 88 grams of solid carbon dioxide sublimates, how many liters of carbon dioxide gas will be formed at standard temperature and pressure?",
        "Answer": "45"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To identify the chemical compounds dissolved in a sample, a student dips a clean piece of nichrome wire into the sample and burns it in a flame. By name or number, identify all of the following five substances that might be present if the flame burns blue: 1) selenium, 2) sodium, 3) arsenic, 4) boron, 5) lead.",
        "Answer": "SELENIUM, ARSENIC, LEAD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given that the balanced chemical equation for the reaction of oxygen and ethane is: 2C2H6(g) + 7O2(g) ! 4CO2(g) + 6H2O(g), if 16 grams of O2 react with excess C2H6, to the nearest gram, how many grams of CO2 will be formed?",
        "Answer": "13"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many lone pairs of electrons are on the phosphorus atom in PF3?",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given the balanced chemical equation:  H2SO4(aq) + 2NaOH(aq)!! Na2SO4(aq) + 2H2O(l), in an acid-base titration, 25 milliliters of 0.2 molar H2SO4 were required to neutralize 100 milliliters of NaOH solution. Providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest tenth, what is the molarity of the NaOH solution?",
        "Answer": "0.1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules contains only one non-bonding pair of valence electrons?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "HCN",
            "X": "NH4+",
            "Y": "C2H4",
            "Z": "N2"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given the balanced equation: 2C4H10(g) + 13O2(g) !  8CO2(g) + 10H2O(g), what is the percent yield of water if 15 moles of water is obtained when 4 moles of butane is burned in excess oxygen?",
        "Answer": "75%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A pure element when mixed with an ionic compound is most likely to undergo which of the following kinds of reactions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Single replacement",
            "X": "Double replacement",
            "Y": "Synthesis",
            "Z": "Combustion"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an alternative name for 1,3-xylene?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ortho-xylene",
            "X": "Meta-xylene",
            "Y": "Para-xylene",
            "Z": "Cis-xylene"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Specifying the sign, what is the oxidation state of nitrogen in the neutral compound iron (II) nitrate?",
        "Answer": "+5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When calcium chloride is dissolved in water, its van\u00d5t Hoff factor would be closest to what whole number?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When the change of enthalpy of a reaction is negative and the change of entropy of the same reaction is positive, the reaction is which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Always spontaneous",
            "X": "Spontaneous only under high temperature conditions",
            "Y": "Spontaneous only under low temperature conditions",
            "Z": "Never spontaneous"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify all of the following four diatomic molecules whose bond strength would decrease after the removal of an electron to form a positively charged ion: 1) H2, 2) B2, 3) ClBr, 4) O",
        "Answer": "1) H2, 2) B2, 3) ClBr, 4) OF"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following types of decay does uranium-238 experience in order to yield thorium-234?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Alpha",
            "X": "Beta",
            "Y": "Double beta",
            "Z": "Gamma"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to the second law of thermodynamics, what effect does a spontaneous reaction have on the entropy of the universe?",
        "Answer": "INCREASES THE ENTROPY OF THE UNIVERSE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the term for the mixing of atomic orbitals to explain covalent bonds?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Transmutation",
            "X": "Ionization",
            "Y": "Hybridization",
            "Z": "Localization"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many moles of oxygen are contained in one mole of ammonium sulfate?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Denatured alcohol contains which of the following toxic substances added to ethanol?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Propanol",
            "X": "Methanol",
            "Y": "Hexanol",
            "Z": "Octanol"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Pyrex glassware contains silicon dioxide, which has acidic properties and should not be used to store which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Dihydrogen monoxide",
            "X": "Acetic acid",
            "Y": "Sodium chloride",
            "Z": "Sodium hydroxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is TRUE of ceramics?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They are homogeneous",
            "X": "They are heterogeneous (read as: heh-teh-roh-JEE-nee-is)",
            "Y": "They are chelates",
            "Z": "They are a form of glass"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements has the valence electron configuration of 3s23p3?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Phosphorus",
            "X": "Oxygen",
            "Y": "Bromine",
            "Z": "Nitrogen"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following represents the electron-pair geometry of the central oxygen atom of ozone?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Linear",
            "X": "Trigonal planar",
            "Y": "Tetrahedral",
            "Z": "Trigonal bipyramidal"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Within a single atom, what is the maximum number of electrons that can fit in an atomic shell defined by the quantum numbers n = 3 and l = 2 (read as: L equals 2)?",
        "Answer": "10 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the IUPAC name for SnCl2!! 6H2O?",
        "Answer": "TIN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, list all of the following five substances that are NOT Newtonian fluids: 1) gasoline, 2) yogurt, 3) water, 4) blood, 5) ketchup.",
        "Answer": "YOGURT, BLOOD, AND KETCHUP"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following can bond to a metal ion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ligand",
            "X": "Lewis acid",
            "Y": "Bronsted-Lowry acid",
            "Z": "Enantiomer"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many milliliters of 0.75 molar HCl are required to completely neutralize 25.0 milliliters of 0.15 molar Ba(OH)2?",
        "Answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following factors does NOT affect the solubility of a solid in a liquid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Temperature",
            "X": "Polarity of solute",
            "Y": "Polarity of solvent",
            "Z": "Pressure"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following period 3 elements has the smallest atomic radius?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium",
            "X": "Phosphorus",
            "Y": "Chlorine",
            "Z": "Aluminum"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the SI prefix that multiples a unit by a factor of 1018?",
        "Answer": "EXA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many atoms are in one molecule of butane?",
        "Answer": "14 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Nuclides that have neutron-to-proton ratios that are too high compared with stable nuclides tend to undergo what kind of decay?",
        "Answer": "BETA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following metals could NOT successfully be used to galvanize iron?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Zinc",
            "X": "Aluminum",
            "Y": "Manganese",
            "Z": "Nickel"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Isoelectronic atoms and ions are identical in which of the following ways?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Electron affinity",
            "X": "Ionization energy",
            "Y": "Electron configuration",
            "Z": "Effective nuclear charge"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many electrons with quantum number l = 1 (read as: L equals 1) are in an atom of silicon in its ground state?",
        "Answer": "8 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Recycling code 2 indicates which of the following types of plastic?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Polyvinyl chloride",
            "X": "Polystyrene (read as: pahl-i-STYR-een)",
            "Y": "High-density polyethylene",
            "Z": "Polyethylene terephthalate"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If 4.67 grams of butane reacts with 23.12 grams of molecular oxygen to produce 2.67 grams of carbon dioxide, what is the limiting reactant?",
        "Answer": "BUTANE _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Sodium azide and potassium nitrate react to inflate an airbag during a car crash primarily by producing which of the following gases?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nitrogen",
            "X": "Oxygen",
            "Y": "Potassium oxide",
            "Z": "Sodium nitrate"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By name or number, identify all of the following four characteristics that are intensive properties of a bubble of air: 1) density, 2) radius, 3) percent oxygen, 4) temperature.",
        "Answer": "DENSITY, PERCENT OXYGEN, AND TEMPERATURE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What element corresponds to the electron configuration 1s22s22p5?",
        "Answer": "FLUORINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In which of the following sets of elements would all members be expected to have very similar chemical properties?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Neon, oxygen, and fluorine",
            "X": "Argon, bromine, and krypton",
            "Y": "Magnesium, calcium, and barium",
            "Z": "Aluminum, silicon, and phosphorus"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an example of effusion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The formation of snowflakes in the upper atmosphere",
            "X": "A hot air balloon flight",
            "Y": "The evaporation of water from a lake",
            "Z": "A bike tire losing air after running over a nail"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When hydrochloric acid in an aqueous solution reacts with solid sodium bicarbonate, what are the products?",
        "Answer": "CARBON DIOXIDE, WATER, AND SODIUM CHLORIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In scientific notation, one attojoule is equal to how many joules?",
        "Answer": "1 x 10!18"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the IUPAC name of the compound PbCO3?",
        "Answer": "LEAD"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Reduction involves which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gain of electrons and increase in oxidation number",
            "X": "Loss of electrons and increase in oxidation number",
            "Y": "Gain of electrons and decrease in oxidation number",
            "Z": "Loss of electrons and decrease in oxidation number"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, identify all of the following four statements that are TRUE: 1) liquids with large intermolecular forces tend to have very low boiling points, 2) liquids with large intermolecular forces tend to have considerable surface tension, 3) ethanol has a higher boiling point than methanol, 4) the hardness of diamond is due to strong van der Waals forces.",
        "Answer": "2 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is TRUE about the solubility of a gas in water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It increases as both temperature and partial pressure of the gas rise",
            "X": "It increases as temperature rises but decreases as partial pressure of the gas rises",
            "Y": "It decreases as temperature rises but increases as partial pressure of the gas rises",
            "Z": "It decreases as both temperature and partial pressure of the gas rise"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Plastics with the recycling symbols of 2 and 4, such as those used to make plastic bags, are produced from what monomer?",
        "Answer": "ETHYLENE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A solution is prepared by mixing 1 gram of ethanol with 100 grams of water to give a final volume of 101 milliliters. Calculate to the nearest integer the mass percent of ethanol in the solution.",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the conjugate acid in the reaction of sulfuric acid and sodium hydroxide?",
        "Answer": "WATER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a covalent bond formed by orbitals overlapping end to end?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Alpha",
            "X": "Beta",
            "Y": "Sigma",
            "Z": "Pi"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 4,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The radius of a gold atom is 144 picometers and its density is 19.32 grams per cubic centimeter. What kind of crystal structure does the unit cell of elemental gold have?",
        "Answer": "FACE-CENTERED CUBIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The convex meniscus of mercury in a capillary tube indicates which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Mercury is highly attracted to glass",
            "X": "Mercury is polar",
            "Y": "Mercury\u00d5s cohesion is greater than its adhesion",
            "Z": "Mercury is soluble in water"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What compound is the reducing agent in the reaction:  CH4 + 2O2 ! (read as: yields) CO2 + 2H2O.",
        "Answer": "CH4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "About how many calories per gram will it take to sublimate water at standard pressure:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "180",
            "X": "360",
            "Y": "540",
            "Z": "720"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A Buchner (read as: BYOU-kh-ner) funnel is a piece of laboratory glassware often used in chemistry labs for which of the following procedures:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "combustion",
            "X": "filtration",
            "Y": "centrifugation",
            "Z": "distillation"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is one of the main reasons why oxygenates are used as gasoline additives:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "allow for more complete combustion",
            "X": "decrease sulfur buildup in engine pistons",
            "Y": "prevent water condensation in stored fuels",
            "Z": "corrosion inhibition"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consider the following equilibrium reaction,  PCl5(gas) 3(gas) + Cl2(gas).  If a 2 mole sample of PCl5 dissociates to give 0.2 moles of Cl2  at equilibrium, find the molar amounts, to the 1st decimal place, of PCl5 at equilibrium:",
        "Answer": "1.8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The reaction CuCl2 + Na2S  CuS + 2NaCl2, is an example of what class of chemical reaction:",
        "Options": {
            "W": "synthesis",
            "X": "single replacement",
            "Y": "double replacement",
            "Z": "decomposition"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following 4 species that contain an odd number of electrons:  O21\u0152;  O22\u0152;  SO2;  CO",
        "Answer": "O21\u0152"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the 2 alkenes (read as: al-KEENS) with the shortest carbon chains and lowest molecular weights?",
        "Answer": "ETHYLENE;  PROPYLENE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following 4 metals in order of increasing reactivity in dilute HCl:  zinc;  aluminum;  gold;  calcium",
        "Answer": "GOLD;  ZINC;  ALUMINUM;  CALCIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the general name for a substance that facilitates a chemical reaction by providing an alternative reaction pathway with a lower activation energy while remaining unaltered?",
        "Answer": "CATALYST"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "You need to prepare 500 milliliters of a 0.100 molar NaOH solution from a 0.250 molar solution.  What volume, in milliliters, of the 0.250 molar solution must be diluted to 500 milliliters?",
        "Answer": "200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following types of structures describes a beta sheet?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Primary",
            "X": "Secondary",
            "Y": "Tertiary [TER-shee-er-ee]",
            "Z": "Quaternary [KWOT-er-ner-ree]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the oxidation state of bromine in the compound bromous acid?",
        "Answer": "+3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many moles of carbon dioxide are produced from the combustion of 5 moles of hydrogen?",
        "Answer": "0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a component of a phospholipid [fos-foh-LIP-id]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Water",
            "X": "Glycerol",
            "Y": "Fatty acid",
            "Z": "Phosphate group"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following metals commonly forms cations [KAT-eye-uhns] with differing charges?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Strontium",
            "X": "Rubidium",
            "Y": "Calcium",
            "Z": "Chromium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the most common linkage between successive monomers in cellulose?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Alpha-1, 4",
            "X": "Alpha-1, 6",
            "Y": "Beta-1, 4",
            "Z": "Beta-1, 6"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term for a product generated in one step of a reaction mechanism that is consumed as a reactant in another step?",
        "Answer": "REACTION INTERMEDIATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Several years ago, scientists announced that they had succeeded in getting a nucleus of calcium-48 to fuse with a nucleus of plutonium-244. The combined nucleus is a nucleus of what element?",
        "Answer": "UNUNQUADIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "How many total atoms are contained within a body-centered orthorhombic [ohr-thuh-ROM-bik] unit cell?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2",
            "X": "3",
            "Y": "4",
            "Z": "6"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short In",
        "Question": "kilojoules per mole to the nearest whole number, what is the total bond energy for ethane, assuming that the carbon-hydrogen bond energy is 413 kilojoules per mole and the carbon-carbon bond energy is 348 kilojoules per mole?",
        "Answer": "2826"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following describes the relationship between cis-3-pentene and trans-3-pentene?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Structural isomers [EYE-suh-mers]",
            "X": "Chiral molecules",
            "Y": "Diastereomers [dy-uh-STER-ee-uh-mers]",
            "Z": "Enantiomers [ih-NAN-tee-uh-mers]"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Osmium is one of the densest elements known at 22.59 grams per milliliter. Providing your answer to three decimal places, what would be the volume in milliliters of a bar of osmium weighing 2.0 grams?",
        "Answer": "0.089"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many modes of vibration would a non-linear molecule with 9 atoms exhibit?",
        "Answer": "21"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When an acid is added to any metal carbonate, such as barium carbonate, what gas is always formed?",
        "Answer": "CARBON DIOXIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "By number, name all of the following four nonmetal oxides that have bent molecular geometries: 1) sulfur dioxide, 2) carbon dioxide, 3) nitrogen dioxide, 4) sulfur trioxide.",
        "Answer": "1, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Given that the standard enthalpy [EN-thal-pee] of formation for solid calcium carbonate is -1200 kilojoules per mole, for solid calcium oxide is -600 kilojoules per mole, and for gaseous carbon dioxide is -400 kilojoules per mole, which of the following is the standard enthalpy change in kilojoules per mole for the reaction:  CaCO3 (s)  [yields] CaO (s) + CO2 (g)?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-400",
            "X": "-200",
            "Y": "200",
            "Z": "600"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is false regarding the reaction A(g) + B(s)  C(s)?  (READ IS: A gaseous plus B solid yields C solid)",
        "Options": {
            "W": "As pressure decreases, reaction rate decreases",
            "X": "As temperature increases, reaction rate increases",
            "Y": "As surface area increases, reaction rate decreases",
            "Z": "When a catalyst is added, reaction rate increases"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Calculate the change in energy from a hydrogen atom\u2122s ground state to its first excited state in Rydbergs.",
        "Answer": "+3/4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds would be insoluble in an aqueous [AY-kwee-uhs] solution?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Calcium carbonate",
            "X": "Sodium nitrate",
            "Y": "Ammonium hydroxide",
            "Z": "Potassium perchlorate"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following accurately depicts the hybridization [HY-bri-dy-zay-shuhn] of each atom in the molecule krypton difluoride?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Krypton: sp3; each fluorine: sp3",
            "X": "Krypton: sp3d; each fluorine: sp3",
            "Y": "Krypton: sp3d2; each fluorine: sp2",
            "Z": "Krypton: sp3d; each fluorine: sp2"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the molarity of a 3.0 liter solution that contains 21 grams of methane?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0.15",
            "X": "0.32",
            "Y": "0.44",
            "Z": "0.56"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given that the Ka of benzoic acid is 6.4 x 10-5 and its pKa is 4.2, providing your answer to one decimal place, what is the pH of a solution of 0.1 molar benzoic acid and 0.10 molar sodium benzoate?",
        "Answer": "3.2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What stress applied to an equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm] causes the equilibrium to shift to the side with fewer moles of gas?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Increase in pressure",
            "X": "Increase in volume",
            "Y": "Increase in temperature",
            "Z": "Addition of a catalyst"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following would be most likely to undergo an SN1, reaction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Methyl bromide",
            "X": "2-propyl bromide",
            "Y": "Isopropyl chloride",
            "Z": "Tert-butyl chloride"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of the property that distinguishes L-alanine [AL-uh-neen] from D-alanine?",
        "Answer": "CHIRALITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following would NOT be a good method to determine the molecular weight of a protein?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Isoelectric focusing",
            "X": "Electrophoresis [i-lek-troh-fuh-REE-sis]",
            "Y": "Gel filtration",
            "Z": "Ultracentrifugation"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The molecule chlorine trifluoride has what molecular geometry?",
        "Answer": "T-SHAPED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given a box of length a and a particle of radius b, molecular weight c, and velocity d, what is the average position of the particle in the box with respect to length?",
        "Answer": "a/2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules can ionize in water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ethyl acetate",
            "X": "Diethyl ether",
            "Y": "Acetic acid",
            "Z": "Acetic anhydride"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best explains the relative acidity of carboxylic acids?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Resonance-stabilized conjugate base",
            "X": "Long O-H bond length",
            "Y": "Polar covalent O-H bond",
            "Z": "sp2-hybridized carbonyl carbon"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the term that describes the temperature at which ferromagnetic materials no longer exhibit spontaneous magnetization?",
        "Answer": "CURIE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What isotope will be formed when oxygen-19 undergoes beta minus decay?",
        "Answer": "FLUORINE-19"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following, when added to an aqueous [ay-KWEE-uhs] sample containing calcium carbonate, would be most likely to produce bubbles?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrogen chloride",
            "X": "Water",
            "Y": "Ammonia",
            "Z": "Lithium hydroxide"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following sets are all strong electrolytes?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrogen chloride, phosphoric acid, acetic acid",
            "X": "Hydrogen chloride, sodium hydroxide, phosphoric acid, potassium hydroxide",
            "Y": "Hydrogen iodide, hydrogen bromide, lithium hydroxide, nitric acid",
            "Z": "Ammonia, potassium hydroxide, sodium hydroxide, lithium hydroxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer as a decimal, what is the bond order for the oxygen-oxygen bonds in ozone?",
        "Answer": "1.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the local VSEPR geometry of a triply-bonded alkyne carbon?  W) Tetrahedral X) Trigonal planar Y) Linear Z) Bent",
        "Answer": "Y) LINEAR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT an aliphatic hydrocarbon?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Benzene",
            "X": "Propane",
            "Y": "Cyclopropane",
            "Z": "Cyclopentene"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Determine the entropy, in calories per mole Kelvin, of a system that is at 27\u00b0 Celsius and which has undergone a 1500 calorie per mole decrease in Gibbs free energy accompanied by a negligible change in enthalpy.",
        "Answer": "-5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following has the lowest freezing point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Water",
            "X": "Chloroform",
            "Y": "Acetic acid",
            "Z": "Ethanol"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given that the Kb of a particular solvent is 2.53 oC per molal and providing your answer to two decimal places, by how many degrees Celsius would the boiling point of a solution be raised if it contains 3.0 moles of a nonelectrolyte in 6.0 kilograms of solvent?",
        "Answer": "1.27"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Carbon nanotubes are potentially useful in applications such as nanotechnology, optics, and electronics. What allotrope of carbon makes up these cylinders?",
        "Answer": "FULLERENE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The wavelength of light emitted from a quantum dot generally depends on what feature of the dot?",
        "Answer": "SIZE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider the closed equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm] system of calcium carbonate, carbon dioxide, and water, which yields calcium ions and bicarbonate ions. Adding sodium bicarbonate to the solution will make which of the following true in the reaction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Q will be greater than K",
            "X": "Q will be less than K",
            "Y": "Q will be equal to K",
            "Z": "Q and K both increase"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electron configuration of bromine in noble gas notation?",
        "Answer": "[Ar] 4s2 3d10 4p5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following pairings of quantum numbers n, l, and m  CANNOT be correct?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "An electron in nickel\u2122s 3d orbital: 3, 2, 2",
            "X": "An electron in phosphorus\u2122s 2s orbital: 2, 0, 0",
            "Y": "An electron in potassium\u2122s 3p orbital: 3, 2, -1",
            "Z": "An electron in oxygen\u2122s 2p orbital: 2, 1, +1"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to valence bond theory, what is the hybridization of the central atom of xenon oxytetrafluoride?",
        "Answer": "sp3d2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Identify which of the following types of copolymer [koh-POL-uh-mer] would be represented by a molecule with the linkage pattern FGGFFFGFG?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Statistical",
            "X": "Block",
            "Y": "Graft",
            "Z": "Alternating"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true about benzene?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The carbons are alternately sp2 and sp3 hybridized",
            "X": "The carbon atoms are all sp2 hybridized with an unhybridized p orbital",
            "Y": "Some of the carbon atoms exhibit tetrahedral geometries",
            "Z": "The carbon atoms are all sp3 hybridized"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true for the isotopes of an element?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They cannot be separated at all",
            "X": "They have equal masses",
            "Y": "They have similar chemical behavior",
            "Z": "They cannot be separated by physical methods"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The equilibrium constant K for the following reaction is 6 x 10-4: (CH3)2NH + H2*(CH3)2NH2+ + OH- [CH 3 2 NH plus H 2 O yields star C H 3 2 N H 2 plus plus O H minus].   Providing your answer in scientific notation, find K for the reaction (CH3)2NH2+ 3)2NH + H+ [C H 3 2 N H 2 plus yields star C H 3 2 N H plus H plus].",
        "Answer": "1.7 x 10-11"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following bonds is the longest in length?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Fluorine-fluorine",
            "X": "Chlorine-chlorine",
            "Y": "Bromine-bromine",
            "Z": "Iodine-iodine"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Ozonolysis [oh-zuh-NOL-uh-sis] cleaves which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbon-carbon double bonds in alkenes [AL-keens]",
            "X": "Carbon-carbon bonds in alkanes",
            "Y": "Oxygen-oxygen bonds",
            "Z": "Bonds between carbon and hydrogen"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true for an adiabatic process?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Temperature remains constant",
            "X": "Pressure remains constant",
            "Y": "Net heat transfer to the surroundings is zero",
            "Z": "Work done on the surroundings is zero"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A reaction between two solutions A and B has a rate constant k of 1. If A increases from 2.0 molar to 4.0 molar and B is held constant, the reaction rate is doubled. If B goes from 2.0 molar to 4.0 molar and A is held constant, the reaction rate is quadrupled. What is the overall reaction order?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In preparing to perform a flame test on a sample, a high molar solution of which of the following chemicals would be best to use to clean your nichrome wire?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium hydroxide",
            "X": "Nitrous acid",
            "Y": "Hydrochloric acid",
            "Z": "Lithium hydroxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To heat 0.5 kilograms of water from 20 degrees Celsius to 80 degrees Celsius, providing your answer in kilojoules, how much energy is needed?",
        "Answer": "126"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For the molecular orbital diagram of H2, in which of the following locations are the electrons located?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "One electron in each hydrogen's 1s atomic orbital",
            "X": "Both electrons in the sigma 1s orbital",
            "Y": "Both electrons in the sigma* [sigma-star] 1s orbital",
            "Z": "Both electrons in the pi 1s orbital"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 25,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer to one significant figure, determine the pH of a 5.0 molar solution of acetic acid, given that acetic acid\u2122s Ka is 2 x 10-5.",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the specific chemical term for the minimum pressure required to produce liquefaction of a substance at the critical temperature?",
        "Answer": "CRITICAL PRESSURE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name the molecule with the formula CH3COOCH2CH2CH3.",
        "Answer": "PROPYL ETHANOATE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following catabolic pathways liberates carbon dioxide?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Electron transport",
            "X": "Glycolysis [gly-KOL-uh-sis]",
            "Y": "Citric acid cycle",
            "Z": "Cori cycle"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If one mole of a substance with a molar mass of 20 is burned at constant pressure and 800 kilojoules of energy is released as heat, what is the standard enthalpy change, in kilojoules, when a 5-gram sample of this substance is burned at constant pressure?",
        "Answer": "-200"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an aldehyde [AL-duh-hyd]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C11H20",
            "X": "C5H11OH",
            "Y": "C5H11CHO",
            "Z": "C5H11NH2"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which one of the following five metals would react the least with dilute hydrochloric acid: 1) lead, 2) chromium, 3) manganese, 4) nickel, 5) gold?",
        "Answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When hydrogen reacts with 2-butanone, which of the following is the primary product?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A primary aldehyde [AL-duh-hyd]",
            "X": "A secondary aldehyde",
            "Y": "A primary alcohol",
            "Z": "A secondary alcohol"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following three choices in order of increasing number of oxygen atoms: 1) one mole of carbon monoxide; 2) one mole of carbon dioxide; 3) one-half mole of calcium carbonate.",
        "Answer": "1, 3, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In which of the following ways would oxygen\u2122s electrons fill the 3 p subshells?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1 pair, 2 unpaired",
            "X": "1 pair, 1 unpaired",
            "Y": "2 pairs",
            "Z": "3 pairs"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What gaseous organic compound is made when ethanol is heated in a concentrated solution of sulfuric acid?",
        "Answer": "ETHYLENE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a flame test on an unknown compound, the flame is violet. What element is likely to be in the compound?",
        "Answer": "POTASSIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following anhydrous compounds has the lowest melting point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Aluminum chloride",
            "X": "Calcium chloride",
            "Y": "Copper (II) chloride",
            "Z": "Lead (III) chloride"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A nitrogen atom present in the backbone of a polypeptide [pol-ee-PEP-tyd] is part of which of the following functional groups?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "A primary amine",
            "X": "A secondary amine",
            "Y": "A tertiary amine [TER-shee-er-ee]",
            "Z": "An amide"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the final product of purine metabolism excreted in the urine?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Urea",
            "X": "Uric acid",
            "Y": "Ammonia",
            "Z": "Ammonium"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "At -78\u00ba Celsius, dry ice changes directly from a solid to a gas. What is this process called?",
        "Answer": "SUBLIMATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the formula for n-Octadecanoic acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C6H12O6",
            "X": "C18H36COOH",
            "Y": "C17H35COOH",
            "Z": "C16H32COOH"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following transition metals has the smallest atomic radius?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nickel",
            "X": "Iron",
            "Y": "Scandium",
            "Z": "Cadmium"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Consisting of a fatty acid chain attached through an amide linkage to sphingosine [SFING-guh-seen], what is the fundamental structural unit common to all sphingolipids?",
        "Answer": "CERAMIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In carbon dioxide, what is the formal charge on the central atom?",
        "Answer": "0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Good nucleophiles [noo-klee-uh-FYLS], which promote substitution instead of elimination reactions, tend to be which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Weak bases",
            "X": "Strong bases",
            "Y": "Weak acids",
            "Z": "Strong acids"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following carbohydrates will most easily dissolve in water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Glycogen [GLY-kuh-juhn]",
            "X": "Starch",
            "Y": "Maltose [MOHL-tohs]",
            "Z": "Cellulose"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What adjective describes a mixture that has equal amounts of left- and right-handed enantiomers [i-NAN-tee-uh-mers] of a chiral [KY-ruhl] molecule?",
        "Answer": "RACEMIC"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to valence bond theory, what is the hybridization of the central atom of methane?",
        "Answer": "sp3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A lab performs atomic spectroscopy, usually using a flame as an excitation source. However, flames only ionize a very small percentage of the atoms, so the lab wants to find a better excitation source. Name a common source that could be used to solve this problem.",
        "Answer": "PLASMA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following gases is NOT one of the major causes of the greenhouse effect?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbon dioxide",
            "X": "Nitrous oxide",
            "Y": "Methane",
            "Z": "Carbon monoxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a titration experiment, 6.0 milliliters of a 0.05 molar monoprotic weak acid are titrated with 0.10 molar sodium hydroxide. How much base in milliliters will it take to reach the half-equivalence point?",
        "Answer": "1.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following adjectives describes the reaction of a strong base with a strong acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Precipitation",
            "X": "Synthesis",
            "Y": "Redox",
            "Z": "Neutralization"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a strong acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nitric acid",
            "X": "Perchloric acid",
            "Y": "Formic acid",
            "Z": "Hydroiodic acid"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When baking cupcakes, a common ingredient used to make the batter rise is baking soda. What is the gas produced that causes the batter to rise?",
        "Answer": "CARBON DIOXIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the conjugate acid of the acetate ion?",
        "Answer": "ACETIC ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the balanced equation 2Ag+ + Cu  [yields] 2Ag + Cu2+, what is the reducing agent?",
        "Answer": "COPPER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Converting carbon dioxide to carbon monoxide through reduction would be effective method for reducing harmful levels of atmospheric carbon dioxide. However, this conversion is very difficult for which of the following reasons?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "There is a limited supply of rhenium in the world",
            "X": "Not all steps of the reduction have been completely determined",
            "Y": "The final step takes an extremely long time",
            "Z": "The carbon dioxide is too difficult to harness"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "When assigning electrons to subshells, which of the following subshells will be filled first?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "4f",
            "X": "5s",
            "Y": "5d",
            "Z": "6s"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which of the gas laws is demonstrated when an aerosol can is thrown into a fire and explodes?",
        "Answer": "AMONTON\u2122S"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of the bond linking each fatty acid to glycerol [GLIS-uh-rol] in a triglyceride?",
        "Answer": "ESTER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Several candidates have been proposed as the discoverer of oxygen. Who, however, is the scientist who most carefully documented his work and thus has been credited with its discovery?",
        "Answer": "PRIESTLY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What element has the following four characteristics: 1) it occurs naturally only in combination with other elements in minerals; 2) it is used primarily as a hardening agent in alloys; 3) its dust is highly toxic, and 4) it is an alkaline [AL-kuh-lyn] earth metal.",
        "Answer": "BERYLLIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following four compounds that are ionic: 1) sodium sulfate, 2) methane, 3) ammonium chloride, 4) beryllium iodide.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a buffering agent?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Magnesium oxide",
            "X": "Rubidium hydroxide",
            "Y": "Ammonia",
            "Z": "Monopotassium phosphate"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name of the reaction, commonly used in lecture demonstrations, in which two colorless solutions are mixed, and the liquid turns to a shade of dark blue after a short time delay?",
        "Answer": "IODINE CLOCK"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements, in its gaseous state, has the greatest electron affinity?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Fluorine",
            "X": "Bromine",
            "Y": "Sulfur",
            "Z": "Chlorine"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What disaccharide [dy-SAK-uh-ryd] is composed of beta-D-galactose [guh-LAK-tos] in a beta-1,4 linkage with alpha-D-glucose?",
        "Answer": "LACTOSE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following represents the enthalpy [EN-thal-pee] change that occurs to melt a solid at its melting point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Heat of fusion",
            "X": "Heat of hydration",
            "Y": "Heat of liquidation",
            "Z": "Heat of vaporization"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A gaseous mixture of nitrogen, oxygen, and argon have molar fractions of 0.25, 0.65, and .010, respectively. What is the pressure in atmospheres of nitrogen if the total pressure of the mixture is 4.0 atmospheres?",
        "Answer": "1.0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Ethylene [ETH-uh-leen] has which of the following?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "2 pi bonds",
            "X": "2 sigma bonds and 1 pi bond",
            "Y": "3 sigma bonds",
            "Z": "5 sigma bonds and 1 pi bond"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electron-pair geometry for ICl4- [eye C L 4 minus]?",
        "Answer": "OCTAHEDRAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the name of the periodic table group that contains elements that are silver in color, soft, and react explosively with water.",
        "Answer": "ALKALI METALS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A particle has a de Broglie [duh broh-GLEE] wavelength of 3 x 10-10 meters when it is traveling at 1.1 x 107 meters per second. Expressing your answer in kilograms and in scientific notation to one significant figure, what is its approximate mass?",
        "Answer": "2 X 10-31"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the standard molar enthalpy of formation, in kilojoules per mole, for hydrogen gas?",
        "Answer": "0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following five compounds that are soluble in water: 1) sodium sulfate, 2) lead (II) iodide, 3) barium chloride, 4) iron (II) hydroxide, 5) calcium sulfate.",
        "Answer": "1, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What subshell is defined by an electron with quantum numbers n = 3 and l = 2 [ell equals 2]?",
        "Answer": "3d"
    },
    {
        "Number": 9,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a titration experiment, how many grams of sodium hydroxide are needed to neutralize 25 milliliters of a 0.1 molar hydrogen chloride solution?",
        "Answer": "0.1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules is an alkane?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C4H8",
            "X": "C3H8",
            "Y": "C2H2",
            "Z": "C2H5OH"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Of the following five solutions, name all that are nonelectrolytic: 1) acetone; 2) glucose; 3) acetic acid; 4) nitric acid; 5) ammonia.",
        "Answer": "1, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following chemicals is least likely to hydrogen bond with water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Benzene",
            "X": "Water",
            "Y": "Ammonia",
            "Z": "Formic acid"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A sample containing sulfuric acid requires 10 milliliters of 0.6 molar sodium hydroxide to reach the equivalence point during a titration. Providing your answer as a decimal to three places, how many moles of sulfuric acid were in the sample?",
        "Answer": "0.003"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Ceramic materials have all but which of the following properties?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Low density",
            "X": "High thermal expansion",
            "Y": "High ductility",
            "Z": "High corrosion resistance"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the ground state electron configuration of iron in iron (III) sulfate?",
        "Answer": "[Ar]3d5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is true about alkenes [AL-keens] and alkynes [AL-kyns]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Both are unsaturated compounds",
            "X": "Both can undergo hydrogenation to lose hydrogens",
            "Y": "Both can undergo oxygenation to lose oxygens",
            "Z": "Both have carbon-carbon double bonds"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name all of the following five substances which are classified as strong electrolytes: 1) carbonic acid; 2) hydrogen fluoride; 3) sodium chloride; 4) acetic acid; 5) hydrochloric acid.",
        "Answer": "3, 5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements does NOT commonly form simple ions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Silicon",
            "X": "Oxygen",
            "Y": "Lead",
            "Z": "Sulfur"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many total carbons are in the organic compound  1, 1-dichloro-3-ethyl-2,4 dimethylpentane [dy-METH-uhl-PEN-tayn]?",
        "Answer": "9"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In titration, which of the following is most commonly used as an acid-base indicator in the pH 8 to pH 10 range?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Phenolphthalein [fee-knoll-THAY-lean]",
            "X": "Cresol red",
            "Y": "Bromthymol blue",
            "Z": "Methyl orange"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To what total volume in milliliters would 100 milliliters of an 80% ethanol solution by volume need to be diluted to obtain a 20% solution by volume?",
        "Answer": "400"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Your research results in a new surface temperature probe to obtain data on planet Mercury; however, the probe is highly reactive with chalcogen gases. Which of the following would best insulate the probe?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Diatomic fluorine",
            "X": "Diatomic chlorine",
            "Y": "Diatomic oxygen",
            "Z": "Helium"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If 35 liters of neon gas at 77\u00b0 Celsius is cooled, the volume drops to 10 liters. If the pressure remains constant, what is the final temperature of the gas, in degrees Celsius?",
        "Answer": "-173\u00b0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "You are asked to investigate a gaseous sample that is composed of a variety of different atmospheric gases. Which of the following gas laws could provide information about the relative composition of the gases?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Avogadro\u2122s law",
            "X": "Boyle\u2122s law",
            "Y": "Dalton\u2122s law of partial pressure",
            "Z": "Charles\u2122s law"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Put the following four compounds in order from least to most covalently bonded: 1) beryllium sulfide, 2) lithium oxide, 3) magnesium chloride, 4) calcium bromide.",
        "Answer": "2, 3, 4, 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following does NOT have an index of hydrogen deficiency of 3?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Spiropentane [spy-roh-PEN-tayn]",
            "X": "Norbornene [nohr-bohr-NEEN]",
            "Y": "1,3-cyclohexadiene [1 comma 3-sy-kloh-HEK-suh-deen]",
            "Z": "trans-1,3,5-hexatriene [trans-1-comma-3-comma-5-hek-SUH-treen]"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the oxidizing agent typically used in hydroboration-oxidation?",
        "Answer": "HYDROGEN PEROXIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the major product in the ethoxide-promoted  [beta]-elimination of 1-chloro-1-methylcyclohexane [1-chloro-1-meth-uhl-sy-kluh-HEK-sayn]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ethanol",
            "X": "1-methyl-1-cyclohexene [1- methyl-1-sy-kluh-HEK-sayn]",
            "Y": "Methylcyclohexane",
            "Z": "Methylenecyclohexane [METH-uh-leen-sy-kluh-HEK-sayn]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which halogen is the poorest SN2 leaving group?",
        "Answer": "FLUORINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the most reduced symmetry operation symbol for a molecule that has a rotation angle of 240\u00b0?",
        "Answer": "C32"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many translational, rotational, and vibrational modes, respectively, are there for the molecule beryllium fluoride?",
        "Answer": "TRANSLATIONAL = 3; ROTATIONAL = 2; VIBRATIONAL = 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements about visible energy transitions in electronic spectroscopy is NOT true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They are low energy transitions",
            "X": "They occur between d-orbitals of transition metals",
            "Y": "They occur between metal and ligand orbitals",
            "Z": "They occur between ligand orbitals"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Propranolol [proh-PRAN-uh-lol] hydrochloride is a stable solid that belongs to a class of molecules known as beta blockers, and is prescribed as a racemic [ray-SEE-mik] mixture. Which of the following is NOT true with respect to propranolol hydrochloride?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It will not rotate plane-polarized light",
            "X": "It is optically pure",
            "Y": "It is achiral [ay-KY-ruhl]",
            "Z": "It includes equal amounts of each enantiomer [i-NAN-tee-uh-mer]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer as a whole number, what is the overall order of the reaction governed by the rate law R = k[NO2]2[Br2] [R equals k times the concentration of N-O-2 squared times the concentration of bromine]?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Hydrogen and chlorine are reacted in a 500 milliliter flask to form hydrogen chloride. It takes 0.08 seconds for the amount of chlorine to change by -0.005 moles. Providing your answers as decimals, determine the rate of conversion, in moles per second, and the rate of reaction, in molarity per second.",
        "Answer": "RATE OF CONVERSION = 0.0625; RATE OF REACTION = 0.125"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following gases would deviate most from ideal gas behavior?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Helium",
            "X": "Hydrogen",
            "Y": "Oxygen",
            "Z": "Neon"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many different structural isomers are there for heptane?",
        "Answer": "NINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The following gases are all at standard temperature and pressure. Which of the following gases will have the fastest root mean square speed?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Helium",
            "X": "Molecular nitrogen",
            "Y": "Molecular oxygen",
            "Z": "Sulfur dioxide"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If the pKa of a weak acid is 4.74, what is the pKb of its conjugate base?",
        "Answer": "9.26"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a step in balancing a redox reaction in an acidic solution?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Write the unbalanced net ionic equation",
            "X": "Determine which atoms are oxidized and which atoms are reduced",
            "Y": "Balance each half-reaction for O by adding hydroxide (OH-) to the side with less oxygen",
            "Z": "Balance each half-reaction for H by adding H+ to the side with less H"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When a certain powder is mixed into a solution of silver nitrate, a white precipitate forms. When the powder is added to a solution of sodium hydroxide, bubbles form, which produce a noxious odor. These bubbles, when bubbled into a solution of nickel (II) hydroxide, produce a drastic color change from green to dark blue. What is the identity of this powder?",
        "Answer": "AMMONIUM CHLORIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a property of all amino acids?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They contain both carboxylic [kahr-bok-SIL-ik] acid and amine [uh-MEEN] functional groups",
            "X": "They are chiral [KY-ruhl]",
            "Y": "They are considered organic molecules",
            "Z": "They are generally referred to by their common name"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the pH of a 0.001 molar solution of hydrochloric acid?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best explains the difference between real gases and ideal gases?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "At low pressure, intermolecular attractions become significant",
            "X": "At high pressure, intermolecular attractions become significant",
            "Y": "As pressure decreases, the volume of the gas itself also decreases",
            "Z": "As pressure increases, the volume of the gas itself also increases"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For a d orbital, which of the following is NOT an allowed value for the magnetic quantum number ml?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-1",
            "X": "0",
            "Y": "2",
            "Z": "3"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the hybridization of the central oxygen atom in water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "sp",
            "X": "sp2",
            "Y": "sp3",
            "Z": "sp3d"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A system consists of two gases inside a piston. The two gases react to form a solid product. During the reaction, 150 joules of heat are released and the surroundings do 50 joules of work on the system. What is the change in internal energy in joules of the system?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-200",
            "X": "-100",
            "Y": "+100",
            "Z": "+200"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following properties is generally characteristic of metals?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "High heat conductivity",
            "X": "Low electrical conductivity",
            "Y": "High first ionization energies",
            "Z": "Tendency to form negative ions"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What separation technique would effectively separate a 50:50 mixture of ethanol and water?",
        "Answer": "FRACTIONAL DISTILLATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If an endothermic reaction is at equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm], how will the equilibrium shift if the temperature is raised?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Toward the reactants",
            "X": "Toward the products",
            "Y": "Toward both the reactants and the products",
            "Z": "It will not shift in either direction"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following silver salts with the given Ksp values has the greatest molar solubility?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Silver chloride, Ksp = 1.8 x 10-10",
            "X": "Silver bromide, Ksp = 5.0 x 10-13",
            "Y": "Silver iodide, Ksp = 8.3 x 10-17",
            "Z": "Silver cyanide, Ksp = 1.2 x 10-16"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Give the name of the group of elements that have high melting points, are electropositive, and are frequently used in lasers and television sets.",
        "Answer": "LANTHANIDES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given the molar mass of oxygen is 16 grams per mole and the molar mass of magnesium is 24 grams per mole, what is the empirical formula of a compound containing 48 grams of magnesium and 32 grams of oxygen?",
        "Answer": "MgO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A reaction is carried out in a constant pressure calorimeter. Appropriate measurements are taken and the energy for the change is calculated. The quantity of heat exchanged under these conditions leads to the calculation of which of the following state functions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "q [delta Q]",
            "X": "E",
            "Y": "H",
            "Z": "T"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify the number of pi bonds, respectively, in the following:  1) formaldehyde [for-MAL-duh-hyd], 2) sulfate ion, 3) acetylene [uh-SET-l-een].",
        "Answer": "1) ON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Assuming a temperature where the net magnetic moment is nonzero, which of the following types of magnetism will have the weakest external field?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Antiferromagnetism",
            "X": "Ferromagnetism",
            "Y": "Paramagnetism",
            "Z": "Diamagnetism"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given the molar mass of silver as 107.87 grams per mole, how many moles of silver are contained in 1.806 x 1024 atoms?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the local VSEPR geometry of a fully substituted carbonyl carbon?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Tetrahedral",
            "X": "Trigonal pyramidal",
            "Y": "Trigonal planar",
            "Z": "T-shaped"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following analytical tools can provide information about the crystalline structure of unknown materials?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "X-ray diffraction",
            "X": "X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy",
            "Y": "High pressure liquid chromatography",
            "Z": "Dynamic light scattering"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What are the products of the complete combustion of cyclohexane [sy-kluh-HEK-sayn]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbon monoxide, carbon trioxide and water",
            "X": "Carbon dioxide and water",
            "Y": "Carbon monoxide and water",
            "Z": "A variety of small hydrocarbons"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following ionization techniques will produce the maximum amount of fragmentation?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Chemical ionization",
            "X": "Fast atom bombardment",
            "Y": "Plasma desorption",
            "Z": "Electron impact"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is considered a diatomic element?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium",
            "X": "Sulfur",
            "Y": "Iodine",
            "Z": "Tungsten"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules does NOT have D3h symmetry?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Phosphorus pentachloride",
            "X": "Cyclopropane",
            "Y": "Boric acid",
            "Z": "Bicyclo[2.2.2]octane"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Dr. Ecniecs, the evil genius, has released multiple dangerous weather balloons into the atmosphere, filled with his new concoction - Boomgas! If the density of Boomgas drops below one third of its density at room temperature, it will explode with the force of 1/10th of an atomic bomb. Which of the following disposal methods would force the balloons to explode?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Throwing weighted balloons into the sea",
            "X": "Releasing the balloons into space",
            "Y": "Cryogenically storing the balloons in liquid nitrogen",
            "Z": "Venting Boomgas from the balloons"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider the following reaction: 5H2O(l)+ S2O32- + 4Cl2 (aq)  [yields] 8Cl-(aq) + 2SO42-(aq) + 10H+. What is the oxidizing agent in this reaction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Cl-",
            "X": "S2O32-",
            "Y": "Cl2",
            "Z": "H2O"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the oxidation number of tin in SnS2?",
        "Answer": "+4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What term describes the general process by which a racemate [ray-SEE-mayt] is separated into its component enantiomers [i-NAN-tee-uh-mers]?",
        "Answer": "RESOLUTION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What simple system is used to describe molecular vibrations in quantum mechanics?",
        "Answer": "HARMONIC OSCILLATOR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In free-radical polymerization [puh-lim-er-uh-ZAY-shuhn], there are two possible termination steps. One is combination of free radicals. What is the other?",
        "Answer": "DISPROPORTIONATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the relationship of the organic compounds diethyl ether, n-butyl alcohol, and methyl propyl ether?",
        "Answer": "STRUCTURAL ISOMERS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following types of electrodes can cause problems because it is time-sensitive and its measurements result in a cumulative response?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Enzyme",
            "X": "Gas sensing",
            "Y": "Solid state",
            "Z": "Liquid membrane"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules has a permanent dipole moment?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbon dioxide",
            "X": "Methane",
            "Y": "Hydrogen sulfide",
            "Z": "Molecular nitrogen"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "List the five halogens in order of increasing first ionization energy.",
        "Answer": "ASTATINE, IODINE, BROMINE, CHLORINE, FLUORINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is the change in the parent atom atomic number upon alpha particle emission?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It decreases by 2",
            "X": "It decreases by 1",
            "Y": "It increases by 1",
            "Z": "It increases by 2"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer in proper point group abbreviation, to what point group does the molecule 1, 2-difluoroethane [1 comma 2-di-floo-uh-roh-ETH-ayn] belong?",
        "Answer": "C2h"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Who was the inventor of the first electrochemical cell?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Michael Faraday",
            "X": "Alessandro Volta",
            "Y": "James Maxwell",
            "Z": "Benjamin Franklin"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A plastic undergoes deformation at 740\u00b0 Celsius. Given that its original cross-sectional area is 70 centimeters, its cross-sectional area after deformation is 62 centimeters, and its yield strength is 300 megapascals, determine the percent cold work to the nearest whole number.",
        "Answer": "11%"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is a proper comparison between ductile and brittle fracture?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ductile has an unstable crack and brittle has a stable crack",
            "X": "Brittle has relatively little plastic deformation, while ductile has extensive deformation",
            "Y": "Brittle doesn\u2122t occur in cold metals while ductile does",
            "Z": "Brittle fracture is preferred in most applications"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The generation of proteolytic [proh-tee-uh-LIT-ik] fragments is essential to protein purification. Chymotrypsin [ky-moh-TRIP-sin] is an endopeptidase [en-doh-PEP-ti-days] that will cleave peptide amide bonds. Name two of the four amino acids this enzyme cleaves.",
        "Answer": "(ACCEPT TWO) PHENYLALANINE, TYROSINE, TRYPTOPHAN, METHIONINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Bottom-up approaches to nanotechnology generally involve microscopy. What technique is primarily involved in the top-down approach?",
        "Answer": "LITHOGRAPHY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The molecule (2E, 4Z, 6E)-2,4,6-octatriene [2 comma 4 comma 6 -ok-tuh-TRY-een] can isomerize to cis-5,6-dimethyl-1,3-cyclohexadiene [cis-5 comma 6-dy-METH-uhl-1 comma 3-sy-kloh-HEK-suh-deen]. Identify: 1) The family of pericyclic reactions for this particular isomerization; 2) The mode of activation; and 3) The direction of stereochemical rotation.",
        "Answer": "1) EL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a method to separate two liquids?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Fractional distillation",
            "X": "Chromatography",
            "Y": "Sonication",
            "Z": "Extraction"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The intensity of absorption maxima in a visible spectrum depends upon which of the following characteristics?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ligand field splitting parameter",
            "X": "Allowedness of the transitions",
            "Y": "Electron configuration of the metal center",
            "Z": "Degree of inter-electron repulsion"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following reactions would be most expected to form a racemic [ray-SEE-mik] product mixture?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "E1",
            "X": "E2",
            "Y": "SN1",
            "Z": "SN2"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "At the beginning of an experiment measuring the phosphorescence produced by a phosphorescent substance, the brightness is measured at 12 lumens. After five minutes, the brightness is 6 lumens. After 10 minutes, it is 4 lumens. What brightness, in lumens, would you expect to find after 15 minutes?",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Organolithium [ohr-guh-noh-LITH-ee-uhm] reagents can be reacted with salts made from which element to form a Gilman reagent? Specify both the element and its oxidation state.",
        "Answer": "COPPER 1+"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Catalytic cracking is the most commonly used process in the manufacture of olefins. Different products can be produced from different reactants. If you want to produce an aromatic through cracking followed by dehydration, with what reactant should you begin?",
        "Answer": "NAPHTHENE(S)"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following spectral series has a final energy level of 4?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Paschen [PA-shen]",
            "X": "Brackett",
            "Y": "Pfund [PFOONT]",
            "Z": "Lyman"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Place the following four solvents in order of fastest to slowest reaction rate for SN2: 1) water, 2) D",
        "Answer": "1) water, 2) DM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following protein purification techniques coats proteins with a negative charge after they are denatured?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Affinity chromatography",
            "X": "Isoelectric focusing",
            "Y": "SDS-PAGE",
            "Z": "Ion exchange chromatography"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "You are studying a material that has started to undergo thermal fatigue. Which of the following would be a good action to take to reduce this fatigue?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Eliminate loading by design",
            "X": "Add protective surface coating",
            "Y": "Decrease corrosiveness of medium",
            "Z": "Add residual compressive stresses"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A variety of manufacturing processes may be employed in nanotechnology. Which of the following processes can coat almost anything by transferring material from its source to the substrate without changing chemical composition?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "E-beam",
            "X": "Nanoscale printing",
            "Y": "Vapor deposition",
            "Z": "Soft lithography"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Arrange the following three methods of solvent degassing in order from least effective to most effective: 1) atmosphere exchange under sonication, 2) purging, 3) freeze-pump-thaw.",
        "Answer": "2, 1, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which approximation is used in quantum mechanics to separate the electronic and vibrational wave functions into isolated components?",
        "Answer": "BORN-OPPENHEIMER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In which of the following scattering angles is Rayleigh [RAY-lee] scattering from unpolarized light the most intense?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "0\u00b0",
            "X": "45\u00b0",
            "Y": "90\u00b0",
            "Z": "180\u00b0"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In a recent experiment, you identified an amino acid at the active site of an enzyme. Given your knowledge that basic amino acids are generally found at enzyme active sites, which of the following is most likely to be the amino acid that you have found?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Histidine [HIS-ti-deen]",
            "X": "Aspartate",
            "Y": "Serine [SER-een]",
            "Z": "Phenylalanine [fen-l-AL-uh-neen]"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In two-photon fluorescence spectroscopy, it is common to use a molecule that has a very strong two-photon absorption cross-section. What are the names of the highly fluorescent and commonly used molecules that are generally abbreviated CV and GFP?",
        "Answer": "CRYSTAL VIOLET AND GREEN FLUORESCENT PROTEIN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Iron minerals can be subdivided into different categories based on their gangue [GANG] content. Into which of the following categories would you place a mineral that is made up primarily of aluminum oxide?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Basic gangue",
            "X": "Acid gangue",
            "Y": "Autofluxing",
            "Z": "Primary gangue"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which principle of quantum mechanics determines the transition probability for a molecule, based on the overlap of its vibrational states?",
        "Answer": "FRANK-CONDON"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "You want to process a fiber polymer whose solvent cannot be melted or evaporated. Which of the following techniques should be used?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Wet spinning",
            "X": "Dry spinning",
            "Y": "Extrusion",
            "Z": "Injection molding"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Deuterochloroform [DOO-ter-uh-KLAWR-uh-fawrm] is often used as the internal standard in carbon-13 nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy. At what chemical shift value in parts per million is the resonance centered?",
        "Answer": "77.0"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following functional group pairs corresponds to those constituting a hemiaminal?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Thiol [THY-ol] and nitrile [NY-tril]",
            "X": "Halogen and alkyl [AL-kuhl]",
            "Y": "Amine [uh-MEEN] and hydroxyl",
            "Z": "Azide and alkoxy [AL-kok-see]"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your answer as a decimal to the nearest hundredth, what is the reduced mass of an oscillator made up of a hydrogen and a fluorine atom?",
        "Answer": "0.95"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true when writing electron configurations?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Atomic orbitals can accommodate two electrons",
            "X": "Electrons pair in degenerate orbitals when possible",
            "Y": "Electrons will populate orbitals to maximize spin",
            "Z": "Noble gas cores are often used to truncate longer configurations"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Which quantum number is allowed values ranging from 0 to n -1 and is associated with atomic orbital shape?",
        "Answer": "ANGULAR MOMENTUM QUANTUM NUMBER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "When a peptide bond is formed between two amino acids, water is removed as a byproduct. Which group contributes the OH to form water, and which group contributes the hydrogen?",
        "Answer": "CONTRIBUTES OH = CARBOXYL GROUP"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the Haber reaction, where diatomic hydrogen and diatomic nitrogen react to form ammonia, how many moles of ammonia could be formed if one starts with 0.75 moles of hydrogen?",
        "Answer": "0.50"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "With regard to crystalline solids, which of the following most aptly describes a covalent network?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Low melting point, soft, excellent thermal conductor",
            "X": "Low to high melting point, hard, moderate electrical conductor",
            "Y": "High melting point, soft, poor electrical conductor",
            "Z": "High melting point, hard, poor thermal conductor"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify, respectively, the isotopes created by the emission of one beta minus particle from the following three isotopes: 1) cesium-137, 2) phosphorus-32, 3) carbon-14.",
        "Answer": "1) BA"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the electron configuration of chromium?",
        "Answer": "1s2 2s2 2p6 3s2 3p6 4s1 3d5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Baeyer-Villiger oxidation is used to transform a ketone into what functional group?",
        "Answer": "ESTER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is true of spontaneous processes at constant temperature, volume, and pressure?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Gibbs and Helmholtz free energies increase",
            "X": "Gibbs free energy increases; Helmholtz free energy decreases",
            "Y": "Gibbs and Helmholtz free energies decrease",
            "Z": "Gibbs free energy decreases; Helmholtz free energy increases"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify, respectively, the dominant intermolecular force that has the greatest effect on the following four molecules: 1) methane, 2) benzoic acid, 3) hydrogen chloride gas, and 4) ferric sulfide.",
        "Answer": "1) LO"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In lab, you have patented the creation of a metallic radioactive isotope called Sciencebowlium-23. But, after a period of time, the sample radioactively decays into oxygen-16, where it becomes a gas and dissipates into the atmosphere. You create a sample of Sciencebowlium and weigh it as 500 grams. Exactly four days later, you weigh the sample at 62.5 grams. How many hours long is the half-life of Sciencebowlium-23?",
        "Answer": "32"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the bond order of the nitrogen-oxygen bond in the nitrate anion?",
        "Answer": "1.33"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "With regard to the Rosenmund reduction, which of the following functional group pairs corresponds to the reactant and product, respectively?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ester and alcohol",
            "X": "Acyl [AS-il] chloride and aldehyde [AL-duh-hyd]",
            "Y": "Amide and amine [uh-MEEN]",
            "Z": "Ketone and alkane [AL-kayn]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In the industrially important water-gas shift reaction, carbon monoxide and water vapor react to form carbon dioxide gas and hydrogen gas as products. If the system is closed and the reaction has reached equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm], how would the equilibrium shift if the volume is decreased?",
        "Answer": "UNCHANGED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following pairs of compounds, when placed in water, would be expected to yield a precipitate?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ammonium chloride and sodium nitrate",
            "X": "Sodium acetate and lithium hydroxide",
            "Y": "Potassium sulfide and copper (II) sulfate",
            "Z": "Nitric acid and ammonia"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "There are two elements whose ground state electron configurations contain exactly two half-filled subshells. What are these two elements?",
        "Answer": "CHROMIUM AND MOLYBDENUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best describes the difference between gas diffusion and gas effusion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Diffusion occurs at constant temperature while effusion occurs at variable temperatures",
            "X": "Diffusion can occur with any gas while effusion occurs only with certain gases",
            "Y": "Diffusion involves gas molecules at the same total pressure while effusion involves gases moving from high pressure to low pressure",
            "Z": "Diffusion is mass dependent while effusion is mass independent"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to kinetic-molecular theory, what is the mathematical relationship between molar mass and average gas phase speed?",
        "Answer": "INVERSE SQUARE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "With regard to a graph illustrating the distribution of molecular speeds for a gas at different temperatures, which of the following occurs as temperature decreases?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The curve flattens",
            "X": "The average speed increases",
            "Y": "The percentage of gas at higher speeds decreases",
            "Z": "The mean free path decreases"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank the following four gases in order of increasing effusion rates: 1) Argon, 2) Helium, 3) Oxygen, 4) Chlorine.",
        "Answer": "4, 1, 3, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "You are given a particular polymer to study, and you notice that it can endure an extremely high amount of stress, but only a very small amount of strain. Which of the following types of polymer is it?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Brittle plastic",
            "X": "Tough fiber",
            "Y": "Elastomer",
            "Z": "Plastic with yield"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The measured bond angle in ammonia is 107.3\u00b0, whereas the bond angles in phosphine [FOS-feen] are 93.7\u00b0. Which of the following facts correctly identifies the atomic property that makes the two angles different?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ammonia and phosphine have different expected VSEPR geometries",
            "X": "Nitrogen is more electronegative than phosphorus",
            "Y": "The bonding orbitals of phosphine have more s and less p character than those of ammonia",
            "Z": "The phosphorus atom is much larger than the nitrogen atom"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the irreducible representation for the atomic orbital s for a molecule with C2v symmetry?",
        "Answer": "a1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "For 680 milligrams of tannic acid, which has a molar mass of 1700 grams per mole, dissolved in water, it takes 40.00 milliliters of 0.25 molar sodium hydroxide to titrate the solution to a pH of 13. Based on this data, how many acidic protons does tannic acid have?",
        "Answer": "25"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements about ferrimagnetic solids is true?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Magnetic moments are on different sublattices and are antiparallel",
            "X": "Magnetic moments are on different sublattices and are parallel",
            "Y": "Magnetic moments are on the same sublattices and are parallel",
            "Z": "Magnetic moments are on the same sublattices and are antiparallel"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the major product formed at the conclusion of the following two-step reaction sequence: Step 1) Methylmagnesium bromide, ethylene oxide, and tetrahydrofuran [te-truh-hy-druh-FYOOR-an]; Step 2) Ethyl iodide.",
        "Answer": "ETHYL N-PROPYL ETHER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Carbon dioxide has a boiling point of -57\u00b0 Celsius, whereas sulfur dioxide has a boiling point of -10\u00b0 Celsius. This difference is most likely due to the fact that sulfur dioxide exhibits which intermolecular force, while carbon dioxide does not?",
        "Answer": "DIPOLE-DIPOLE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 19,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The family of olefin metathesis catalysts developed by Grubbs employs which metallic element?",
        "Answer": "RUTHENIUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules can NOT be isolated as an optically pure sample?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Valine [VAL-een]",
            "X": "Tartaric acid",
            "Y": "Epichlorohydrin [ep-i-klawr-uh-HY-drin]",
            "Z": "Trans-4-chlorocyclohexanol [klohr-oh-SY-kloh-HEK-suh-nol]"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What two chemists, in 2001, were awarded half the Nobel Prize for their work on asymmetric hydrogenation?",
        "Answer": "KNOWLES AND NOYORI"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true of polyunsaturated fatty acids?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "They are highly concentrated in cell membranes of the nervous system",
            "X": "They are the most prevalent fatty acid found in the human body",
            "Y": "They contain two or more double bonds",
            "Z": "They play a crucial role in brain function"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true of conjugated dienes [DY-eens]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Increasing conjugation is proportional to increased UV wavelength absorption",
            "X": "Heats of formation are lower than unconjugated dienes",
            "Y": "s-trans dienes participate in Diels-Alder cyclization",
            "Z": "At lower temperatures, 1, 2-addition products predominate"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is generally NOT considered to be an appropriate SN2 electrophile?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Benzyl bromide",
            "X": "Allyl bromide",
            "Y": "Propargyl bromide",
            "Z": "Vinyl bromide"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the major organic product formed when 1-butanol is treated with the Collins reagent?",
        "Answer": "BUTANAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "According to the integrated form of the Clausius [KLOU-zee-uhs]-Clapeyron equation solved for the natural logarithm of vapor pressure, vapor pressure and absolute temperature data can be plotted to give a straight line. Which of the following corresponds to the slope?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "\u0152Hvap/R [negative delta H of vaporization over R]",
            "X": "Hvap/R [delta H of vaporization over R]",
            "Y": "\u0152R/Hvap [negative R over delta H of vaporization]",
            "Z": "R/Hvap [R over delta H of vaporization]"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Place the following four substances in order from lowest to highest boiling point: 1) carbon tetrachloride, 2) ethane, 3) propane, 4) water.",
        "Answer": "2, 3, 1, 4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Dr. Ecniecs, who loves riddles, gave the following riddle about the periodic table: Element A is left-right adjacent to element B. Element A never shares what it holds. Element B is always taking from other elements. Both elements are a clear gas. Both elements are nonmetals. Combined, they have a mass less than that of gallium. What are the identities of elements A and B?",
        "Answer": "NEON AND FLUORINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Amides are formed through a reversible reaction that causes loss of water. This reaction occurs between an amine [uh-MEEN] and what other type of molecule?",
        "Answer": "CARBOXYLIC ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT true in the titration of a weak monoprotic acid with a strong base?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The starting pH will be lower than 7",
            "X": "The final pH will be higher than 7",
            "Y": "Methyl red would be a good indicator to use",
            "Z": "Phenolphthalein [fee-knol-THAY-leen] would be a good indicator to use"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Since internal alkynes [AL-kyns] have an additional pi bond, they do not form the same products as alkenes [AL-kyns] upon cleavage by ozone or potassium permanganate [per-MANG-guh-nayt]. What functional group does this cleavage produce for internal alkynes?",
        "Answer": "CARBOXYLIC ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT a proposed step in the Suzuki reaction catalytic cycle?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Oxidative addition",
            "X": "Transmetalation",
            "Y": "Beta-hydride elimination",
            "Z": "Reductive elimination"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best describes the incident and exit beams in attenuated total reflectance spectroscopy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Incident beam is photons and exit beam is electrons",
            "X": "Incident and exit beams are ions",
            "Y": "Incident and exit beams are photons",
            "Z": "Incident and exit beams are electrons"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following pairs would most likely undergo a Heck reaction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Styrene and iodobenzene",
            "X": "Ethylbenzene and phenol [FEE-nol]",
            "Y": "Vinyl bromide and benzene",
            "Z": "Cyclohexane [sy-kluh-HEK-sayn] and allyl bromide"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 21,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In semicrystalline polymers, the ordered regions will break up and become disordered at the melting temperature. However, amorphous regions soften over a wider range. What is the name of this range?",
        "Answer": "GLASS TRANSITION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "\ufb01Synthons\ufb02 are key precursors associated with retrosynthetic analysis, a logical framework pioneered by what chemist?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Emil Fischer",
            "X": "Robert Robinson",
            "Y": "E. J. Corey",
            "Z": "Georg Wittig"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A buffer solution contains a 10 to 1 ratio of conjugate base to weak acid. The pKa of the weak acid is 5.  What is the pH of the solution?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An enzyme begins oxidation of a fourteen-carbon fatty acid. This metabolic step produces a twelve-carbon fatty acid and what other product?",
        "Answer": "ACETIC ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What ring size would be obtained at the end of the following three-step reaction sequence: 1) Diels-Alder cyclization of 1,3- cyclohexadiene [sy-kloh-HEK-suh-deen] with methyl vinyl ketone; 2) Ozone; 3) Dimethyl [dy-METH-uhl] sulfide?",
        "Answer": "SIX"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The PH3 molecule has what type of molecular geometry?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Trigonal pyramidal",
            "X": "Trigonal planar",
            "Y": "Angular",
            "Z": "Tetrahedral"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 14,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What term describes a reaction that forms two stereoisomers [ster-ee-oh-EYE-suh-mers] in unequal amounts?",
        "Answer": "STEREOSELECTIVE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In atomic orbital overlap, which of the following is true of destructive interference?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It gives a bonding orbital and no nodes",
            "X": "It gives an antibonding orbital and a node parallel to the internuclear axis",
            "Y": "It gives an antibonding orbital and a node perpendicular to the internuclear axis",
            "Z": "It gives an antibonding orbital and no nodes"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In order to enhance the activity of the catalyst, a textural or chemical promoter may be used in ammonia synthesis. Which of the following is an example of a chemical promoter?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Calcium oxide",
            "X": "Potassium oxide",
            "Y": "Aluminum oxide",
            "Z": "Silicon dioxide"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is true of the compression of a system?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Work is done on the system, and dV and dw are greater than 0",
            "X": "Work is done on the system, dV is less than 0, and dw is greater than 0",
            "Y": "Work is done by the system, dV is greater than 0, and dw is less than 0",
            "Z": "Work is done by the system, and dV and dw are less than 0"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Polycatenane [pol-ee-KAT-n-ayn] and polyrotaxane [pol-ee-ro-TUH-ksayn] are examples of what type of unconventional polymer?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Supramolecular",
            "X": "Branched",
            "Y": "Network",
            "Z": "Dendrimer [DEN-druh-mer]"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an example of an A+1 isotope?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nitrogen",
            "X": "Oxygen",
            "Y": "Sulfur",
            "Z": "Fluorine"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 17,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following techniques in the field of nanotechnology is considered to be non-destructive, non-volatile, and easy to integrate?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Molecular electronic switch",
            "X": "Room temperature single electron transistor",
            "Y": "Ovonics unified memory",
            "Z": "Spin resonance transistor"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to valence bond theory, we assume that in methane, each pair of electrons is confined to the region between the carbon and hydrogen nuclei, where the bond is strongest. What is the term used to describe this regional confinement?",
        "Answer": "LOCALIZED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 24,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Steam cracking is one process used in the manufacture of lighter olefins. Which of the following is NOT true of steam cracking?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Increasing temperature shifts cracking to the ends of molecules",
            "X": "Short residence times cause more olefin formation",
            "Y": "The reaction is favored by high pressure",
            "Z": "To minimize coke formation, steam may be added"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A molecular solid contains what type of bonding?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Metallic",
            "X": "Electrovalent",
            "Y": "Covalent",
            "Z": "Localized"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following four factors that affect the degree of crystallinity in polymers:  1) structure; 2) stereochemistry [ster-ee-oh-KEM-uh-stree]; 3) molecular weight; 4) processing conditions.",
        "Answer": "STRUCTURE, STEREOCHEMISTRY, MOLECULAR WEIGHT, AND PROCESSING CONDITIONS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Within the visible spectrum of light, photons with the longest wavelength are associated with what color?",
        "Answer": "RED"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify, by number, the following processes that would result in an increase of potential energy of a system:  1) Energy transfer as work done by a system;  2) Energy transfer as work done on a system; 3) Thermal energy transfer to a system; 4) Thermal energy transfer from a system",
        "Answer": "2, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following acids is diprotic?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Oxalic acid",
            "X": "Phosphoric acid",
            "Y": "Nitric acid",
            "Z": "Hydrochloric acid"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "To the nearest power of ten and in meters, what is the diameter of the hydrogen atom?",
        "Answer": "10-10"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Carbon dioxide, iron(III) [read as iron three] ions, and the hydrogen sulfate ion are all acids in what named theory of acids and bases, which states that bases donate electron pairs, and acids accept them?",
        "Answer": "LEWIS THEORY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following matches the molecular formula of a cyclic alkane [AL-kayn]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "C5H12 [C five H twelve]",
            "X": "C5H10 [C five H ten]",
            "Y": "C5H8 [C five H eight]",
            "Z": "C5H5 [C five H five]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the name in organic chemistry that is given to hydrocarbons with general formula CnH2n-2 [C- n -H -two -n \u0152minus- two] that possess a triple bond, the simplest of which is acetylene [uh-SET-l-een]?",
        "Answer": "ALKYNES"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following nucleotides [NOO-klee-uh-tyds] is not derived from pyrimidine [py-RIM-i-deen]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Uracil [YOOR-uh-sil]",
            "X": "Thymine [THY-meen]",
            "Y": "Guanine [GWAH-neen]",
            "Z": "Cytosine [SY-tuh-seen]"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank the following three acids from strongest to weakest: iodous [eye-OH-duhs] acid, bromic acid, bromous acid.",
        "Answer": "BROMIC ACID, BROMOUS ACID, IODOUS ACID"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Like many thermodynamic quantities, the critical temperature of a substance is strongly dependent on the intermolecular forces present.  Which of the following compounds has the highest boiling point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "N2",
            "X": "H2S",
            "Y": "CO2",
            "Z": "CH4"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following fatty acids has the highest melting point?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Capric",
            "X": "Stearic [stee-AR-ik]",
            "Y": "Palmitic",
            "Z": "Lauric"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An unknown gas effuses through a tiny hole at a rate half that of methane.  The molar mass of methane is 16 grams per mole.  What is the molar mass of the unknown gas in grams per mole to the nearest whole number?",
        "Answer": "64  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The most accurate Lewis structure of phosphoric acid had one hydrogen atom bonded directly to the central phosphorous atom and two bonded to oxygen atoms. Given this information, which of the following terms best describes how phosphoric acid actually behaves in water?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Monoprotic",
            "X": "Diprotic",
            "Y": "Triprotic",
            "Z": "Amphiprotic [am-fi-PRUH_tik]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following compounds that will dissolve in water in an endothermic fashion:  1) ammonium nitrate; 2) sodium hydroxide; 3) sulfuric acid.",
        "Answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following instruments would most likely be used in a lab to measure the concentration of a species in aqueous [AK-wee-uhs] solutions?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Infrared spectrometer",
            "X": "Mass spectrometer",
            "Y": "Spectrophotometer",
            "Z": "Buchner funnel"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a standard cell, a zinc electrode placed in a 1 molar Zn2+ solution is connected to a nickel electrode placed in a 1 molar Ni2+ solution.  The 2 solutions are connected with a salt bridge.  The standard reduction potential of Zn2+[Z-N two plus] is  -0.76 Volts.  If the standard electromotive force of this cell is +0.48 Volts, what is the standard reduction potential of Ni2+[N-i two plus] in volts?",
        "Answer": "-0.28  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following pairs does NOT correctly match the raw material and feedstock with its primary petrochemical?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Natural gas with methanol",
            "X": "Ethane with ethylene [ETH-uh-leen]",
            "Y": "Propane with cyclopropane",
            "Z": "Naphtha with benzene"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An ideal gas is confined to an airtight piston that allows the gas to expand and contract but prevents gas from entering or exiting the piston.  Initially, the temperature of the gas is 300 Kelvin, and the gas occupies a volume of 10 Liters when an external pressure of 1 atmosphere is applied.  The gas is then heated to 600 Kelvin, and the pressure is increased to 5 atmospheres.  To one significant figure, what is the new volume of the gas in liters?",
        "Answer": "4 liters"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules exhibits intermolecular attractions commonly referred to as hydrogen bonding?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "H2",
            "X": "HBr [H-B-R]",
            "Y": "HCN [H-C-N]",
            "Z": "HCOOH [H-C-O-O-H]"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle implies that it is impossible to simultaneously obtain exact measurements for what two properties of a particle?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Mass & velocity",
            "X": "Charge & spin",
            "Y": "Energy & wavelength",
            "Z": "Position & momentum"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three compounds that are capable of hydrogen bonding with themselves:  1) hydrogen bromide; 2) hydrogen cyanide; 3) butanol.",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "For a particular reaction, H = +10 [delta H equals positive ten] kilojoules per mole and S = +40 [delta S equals positive forty] joules per mole Kelvin.  At what temperature, in Kelvin, does the reaction transition from being spontaneous to nonspontaneous?",
        "Answer": "250 Kelvin"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If a molecule is known to have a trigonal bipyramidal shape such that \ufb01M\ufb02 is the central atom and \ufb01L\ufb02 is each of the five substituents, which of the following statements is NOT true about this particular molecule?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "It has a 3-fold rotation axis",
            "X": "It has at least two mirror planes",
            "Y": "It has an inversion center",
            "Z": "It has at least one improper rotation possible"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the theoretical yield, in moles, of ammonia when 4 moles of nitrogen are reacted with 9 moles of hydrogen in the Haber process?",
        "Answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "London dispersion forces increase as which of the following molecular properties also increases?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Dipole moment",
            "X": "Polarizability",
            "Y": "Bond angle",
            "Z": "Ionization energy"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Suppose the atoms of a polar diatomic molecule have partial charges of \u00b10.25 e [plus or minus zero point two five e], equivalent to \u00b14.0x10-20 [plus or minus four point zero times ten to the negative twentieth] coulombs.  If the bond length is 1.5 angstroms, to two significant figures, what is the dipole moment of the molecule in coulomb-meters?",
        "Answer": "6.0x10-30"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A particular reaction involves only one reactant, which decomposes into products. This reactant is also a strong absorber of yellow light, which allows a scientist to use a spectrometer to measure the reactant concentration as a function of time.  The scientist then plots the natural logarithm of the reactant concentration as a function of time, and notices that the plot is linear.  What is the order of the kinetics of this reaction?",
        "Answer": "FIRST"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For a hypothetical diatomic molecule, which of the following combinations of properties would result in the largest dipole moment?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Short bond length, small difference in electronegativity between atoms",
            "X": "Long bond length, large difference in electronegativity between atoms",
            "Y": "Long bond length, small difference in electronegativity between atoms",
            "Z": "Short bond length, large difference in electronegativity between atoms"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following gases has the slowest rate of effusion?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydrogen",
            "X": "Helium",
            "Y": "Oxygen",
            "Z": "Neon"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The electrolysis of water is endothermic, requiring 286 kilojoules of energy to decompose one mole of water at 25\u00b0C. Given that the enthalpy of formation of hydrogen peroxide is -136 kilojoules per mole, what is the standard enthalpy in kilojoules for the decomposition of one mole of hydrogen peroxide into water and oxygen?",
        "Answer": "-150  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What choice best describes the type of reaction that is catalyzed by lyases [ly-AYS-es]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Transfer of functional groups",
            "X": "Mediate isomerization [eye-so-muh-ri-ZAY-shuhn]",
            "Y": "Addition to double bonds",
            "Z": "Formation of bonds with ATP cleavage"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A neutral coordination compound is composed of a complex ion bound to a potassium cation [KAT-eye-uhn]. The complex ion contains a central cobalt ion bound to two ammonia ligands and four chloride ligands. What is the oxidation number of the cobalt ion?",
        "Answer": "THREE PLUS _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three techniques that could be used to determine the size of an unknown compound:  1) affinity chromatography; 2) mass spectrometry; 3) electron paramagnetic resonance.",
        "Answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following qualitative organic tests is NOT matched correctly to a functional group for which it predominantly tests?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Biuret test and amides [by-yuh-RET]",
            "X": "Lucas reagent and alcohols",
            "Y": "Tollens\u2122 reagent and carboxylic acids",
            "Z": "Benedict\u2122s test and reducing sugars"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Halogenation [hal-uh-juh-NAY-shuhn] will occur fastest between methane and the radical of which of the following elements?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Chlorine",
            "X": "Iodine",
            "Y": "Fluorine",
            "Z": "Bromine"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In terms of the ideal gas constant R, what is the constant-pressure heat capacity, per mole, of a monatomic ideal gas?",
        "Answer": "5/2 R"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the full list of products produced by the mild heating of sodium bicarbonate at temperatures of about 80 degrees Celsius?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium oxide and carbon dioxide",
            "X": "Sodium peroxide and carbon dioxide",
            "Y": "Sodium carbonate, water, and carbon dioxide",
            "Z": "Sodium carbonate and carbon dioxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What rule is used to predict the aromaticity of conjugated alkenes?",
        "Answer": "HUCKEL\u2122S RULE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The van der Waals equation is an equation of state for real gases that contains two gas-dependent parameters, a and b. What state function from the ideal gas equation does the a parameter modify in the van der Waals equation?",
        "Answer": "PRESSURE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements concerning the particle-in-a-box model is false?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The potential well is approximated to be infinitely deep",
            "X": "The ground state energy increases with the length of the box",
            "Y": "The energy levels are quantized",
            "Z": "The energy of level n is proportional to n squared"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following organic functional groups does NOT exhibit sp2 [s-p-2] hybridization?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Ketones",
            "X": "Aldehydes [AL-duh-hyds]",
            "Y": "Amides",
            "Z": "Amines"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is true regarding the chemistry of the alkaline earth elements?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Compounds of beryllium have the most covalent character",
            "X": "Melting point increases as you go down the group",
            "Y": "Atomic radius decreases as you go down the group",
            "Z": "Barium has a distinct red flame test color"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider the dissociation of weak hydrofluoric acid into fluoride and hydronium ions, and a solution in which this reaction is at equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm]. Which of the following additions would shift the equilibrium to the right?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Calcium fluoride",
            "X": "Sulfuric acid",
            "Y": "Ammonia",
            "Z": "Ammonium chloride"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Place the following four molecules in order from lowest to highest melting point: 1) NaF, 2) C",
        "Answer": "1) NaF, 2) CH"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In chemical kinetics, which of the following types of reactions has a half-life that is directly proportional to the initial reactant concentration?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Zero order",
            "X": "First order",
            "Y": "Second order",
            "Z": "Third order"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Providing your unitless answer to two significant figures,determine the bond order of N2+.",
        "Answer": "2.5"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements portrays waxes inaccurately?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Many waxes are natural products",
            "X": "Waxes help plants eliminate excess water",
            "Y": "Paraffin waxes do not contain ester functional groups",
            "Z": "Ear wax contains both phospholipids and esters of cholesterol"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Assume that 1 mole of each of the following three salts is dissolved in 1 liter of water. By name or number, give the three solutions from the one with the lowest freezing point to the one with the highest freezing point: 1) aluminum sulfate; 2) calcium nitrate; 3) sodium fluoride.",
        "Answer": "1, 2, 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of reduction reaction generally employs a metal such as ruthenium, platinum, nickel, or palladium as a catalyst, and is used to transform alkenes [AL-kayns] to alkanes in a chamber pressurized with hydrogen gas?",
        "Answer": "HYDROGENATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The approximate molar mass of copper is 63.6 grams per mole. Given that a copper electrode must be oxidized into copper (II) ions to plate one mole of       silver (I) ions onto a silver electrode, give the reduction of mass, in grams, of the copper electrode, as well as the number of moles of electrons that have flowed from the copper to the silver electrode to plate one mole of silver.",
        "Answer": "31.8 GRAMS COPPER; ONE MOLE OF ELECTRONS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following ionic salts has the LARGEST lattice dissociation energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium chloride",
            "X": "Magnesium oxide",
            "Y": "Magnesium chloride",
            "Z": "Lithium fluoride"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If 30 milliliters of 0.10 molar sulfuric acid is titrated with 0.03 molar sodium hydroxide, how many milliliters of sodium hydroxide are required to reach the equivalence point?",
        "Answer": "200  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements does NOT describe a molecule in an octahedral arrangement?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Two-fold, three-fold, and four-fold rotation axes can all be found",
            "X": "Two different types of improper rotations can be found",
            "Y": "Exactly eight different mirror planes can be found",
            "Z": "An inversion center is present"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An airtight chamber contains 4 moles of nitrogen and an unknown amount of oxygen. If the partial pressure of oxygen is 150 torr, and the total pressure is 350 torr, how many moles of oxygen are present?",
        "Answer": "3 _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many sigma and pi bonds, respectively, are in ethyne [ETH-yn], commonly known as acetylene [uh-SET-l-een]?",
        "Answer": "3 SIGMA AND 2 PI"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Consider an arbitrary acid HA [H- A], where A can be any group. Which of the following facts would allow one to directly infer that it is a stronger acid than acetic acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "H-A has the ability to protonate water in high yield",
            "X": "Acetic acid has the ability to protonate H-A in high yield",
            "Y": "H-A has the ability to protonate acetate in high yield",
            "Z": "Acetic acid has the ability to protonate A- in high yield"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Each of the following pairs of chemicals are dissolved in aqueous [AK-wee-uhs] solution at concentrations of 1 molar. Which pair would form a buffer solution?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium formate and formic acid",
            "X": "Sodium nitrate and ammonia",
            "Y": "Sodium hydroxide and nitric acid",
            "Z": "Sodium chloride and hydrochloric acid"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 15,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify the oxidation number of carbon in each of the following: dimethyl ether (CH3OCH3), methylamine (CH3NH2), and formaldehyde [fore-MAL-duh-hyd] (H2CO).",
        "Answer": "DIMETHYL ETHER"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In the Haber process, one mole of nitrogen gas reacts with three moles of hydrogen gas to produce two moles of ammonia. The process is exothermic. If a particular Haber synthesis is at equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm], which of the following changes to the reaction\u2122s conditions are predicted by Le Chatelier\u2122s principle to INCREASE the yield of ammonia?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Adding a catalyst",
            "X": "Increasing the temperature",
            "Y": "Increasing the pressure of the reaction mixture",
            "Z": "Increasing the volume of the reaction vessel"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Nitrogen monoxide reacts with hydrogen gas to form water vapor and nitrogen gas. A 1 liter vessel contains an equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm] mixture of 28 moles of N2, 10 moles of H2O, 2 moles of NO, and 1 mole of H2. Calculate Kc for this reaction.",
        "Answer": "700"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three instruments or techniques that could be used to determine the concentration of an unknown solution of acetic acid: 1) titration, 2) potentiostat, 3) ion-exchange column.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "For a second-order kinetic process where 1 molecule of A irreversibly becomes 1 molecule of B, which of the following plots would generate a line?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Plotting the concentration of A versus time",
            "X": "Plotting one over the concentration of A versus time",
            "Y": "Plotting the log of the concentration of A versus time",
            "Z": "Plotting the exponential of the concentration of A versus time"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following describes the conditions of a process that would be impossible without an energy input?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "G < 0; H < 0; S > 0",
            "X": "G > 0; H > 0; S > 0",
            "Y": "G < 0; H < 0; S < 0",
            "Z": "G > 0; H > 0; S < 0"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following statements is TRUE regarding calorimetry and heating curves?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Bomb calorimeters directly measure the change in enthalpy of a reaction",
            "X": "A heating curve plots pressure versus temperature and is divided into three regions",
            "Y": "Regions depicting a phase change are flat on a heating curve",
            "Z": "The steeper the slope of a heating curve, the higher the heat capacity of that phase"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules has T-shaped molecular geometry?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "BF3",
            "X": "NF3",
            "Y": "ClF3 [C-L-F three]",
            "Z": "SO3"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "An adsorption isotherm apparatus consists of a dosing chamber with a volume of 30 milliliters as well as a sample chamber. The two airtight chambers are initially separated by a valve and at a pressure of 0 torr. Helium gas is let into the dosing chamber until the pressure reaches 600 torr. The valve is then opened, and the helium expands into the sample chamber. Once the pressure has equilibrated between both chambers, it is measured to be 400 torr. In milliliters to two significant figures, determine the volume of the sample chamber.",
        "Answer": "15"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Drift and diffusion both describe the movement of particles. Which of the following is an example of drift?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Random thermal motion of holes",
            "X": "Atoms moving from areas of high concentration to areas of low concentration",
            "Y": "Electrons moving to the anode",
            "Z": "Dopants moving into a semiconductor"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following best explains why titanium dichloride is a solid at room temperature, but titanium tetrachloride is a liquid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The Ti-Cl bond in titanium tetrachloride has more covalent character",
            "X": "The Ti-Cl bond in titanium tetrachloride has more ionic character",
            "Y": "Titanium dichloride forms a molecular solid, whereas titanium tetrachloride does not",
            "Z": "The presence of more gaseous chlorine lowers the melting point of titanium tetrachloride"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Identify which one of the following statements about Boltzmann distribution of energy is false.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Degenerate states have the same energy and will be equally populated",
            "X": "An exponential increase in population with increasing temperature is predicted",
            "Y": "More states are significantly populated if energy level spacings are near kT",
            "Z": "At T = 0, only the lowest energy state is occupied"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Two moles of calcium nitrate are dissolved in 1 kilogram of water. Approximating the boiling-point-elevation constant of water as 0.5 \u00b0Celsius per molal, and reporting your answer to the nearest degree Celsius, what is the boiling point at standard pressure for this solution?",
        "Answer": "103\u00b0C"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In a hydrogen fuel cell, two moles of H2 are oxidized by one mole of O2 to form two moles of water. If the cell is 100% efficient, how many moles of electrons are transferred in this process?",
        "Answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The polymerization of a 1,3 diene [DY-een] will produce a material that can be used to make which of the following polymers?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nylon",
            "X": "Rubber",
            "Y": "Styrene",
            "Z": "Thermoplastic"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "\ufb01Soda-lime\ufb02 glass accounts for 90% of the glass produced and can be made by mixing a modifier, or flux, with sand. Which of the following is an example of a soda-lime glass modifier?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "SiO2",
            "X": "Ca(OH)2",
            "Y": "Na2O",
            "Z": "MgO"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Categorize each of the following four examples of isomerism as either structural isomerism or stereoisomerism [ster-ee-oh-EYE-suh-mer]: 1) geometrical; 2) ionization; 3) polymerization [puh-lim-er-uh-ZAY-shuhn]; 4) optical.",
        "Answer": "STRUCTURAL ISOMERISM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following four types of reactions that follow Zaitsev\u2122s rule: 1) S",
        "Answer": "1) SN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three statements that are true of nuclear chemistry: 1) Helium has a higher binding energy per nucleon than uranium; 2) Alpha particles have a +1 charge; 3) Beta-minus decay usually occurs in nuclei with an excess number of neutrons.",
        "Answer": "3 ONLY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "In proteins, a beta sheet is an example of what type of structure?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Primary",
            "X": "Secondary",
            "Y": "Tertiary",
            "Z": "Quaternary"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "On a phase diagram, what is the name for the one point in phase space where gas, liquid, and solid phases all coexist in equilibrium [ee-kwuh-LIB-ree-uhm]?",
        "Answer": "TRIPLE POINT _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is not one of the characteristics of indirect coulometry [koo-LOM-i-tree]?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Utilizes a constant current source and both indicating and generating electrodes",
            "X": "Can detect microgram amounts",
            "Y": "Requires the use of standards even if the current efficiency is known",
            "Z": "Can use unstable reagents"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Bronze and brass are both alloys that are made by combining copper and another substance.  What other substances are most typically used to make bronze and brass, respectively?",
        "Answer": "TIN"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following elements would be most likely to violate the octet rule?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Boron",
            "X": "Carbon",
            "Y": "Nitrogen",
            "Z": "Oxygen"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three statements that characterize pi bonds:  1) They have maximum electron density on the internuclear axis; 2) They are generally less stable than sigma bonds; 3) A triple bond consists of one pi bond and two sigma bonds.",
        "Answer": "2 ONLY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following scientists is credited with discovering electrons and calculating their mass to charge ratio?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "J.J. Thomson",
            "X": "Robert Millikan",
            "Y": "Ernest Rutherford",
            "Z": "Neils Bohr"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What gas law was used by its formulator to approximate the absolute zero temperature through extrapolation of the temperature axis until the value for gas volume equaled zero?",
        "Answer": "CHARLES\u2122S LAW _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Name the two common crystalline forms of carbon.",
        "Answer": "GRAPHITE AND DIAMOND"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following neutral ground state atoms has the lowest first ionization energy?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nitrogen",
            "X": "Oxygen",
            "Y": "Fluorine",
            "Z": "Neon"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Lipstick is known to be a suspension of high molecular weight hydrocarbons, waxes, and other ingredients. Which of the following choices does NOT describe lipstick composition?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Castor oil may be a dispersing agent",
            "X": "Beeswax is sometimes used as a stiffening agent",
            "Y": "Metal ions such as Nickel(II) [nickel two] are the basis for lipstick dyes",
            "Z": "Carbon soot is typically used as a coloring agent"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three chemical species that likely have a negative enthalpy of formation:  1) carbon monoxide; 2) nitrogen monoxide; 3) sodium bromide.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the chemical formula of the most stable ionic compound that forms between aluminum and sulfur?",
        "Answer": "Al2S3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If a random element is picked from period 5 on the periodic table, what is the probability that the element will have a high energy electron in the d orbital?",
        "Answer": "8 / 9"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "State the oxidation number for nitrogen in the molecule magnesium nitride.",
        "Answer": "3-"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What type of redox reaction involves the simultaneous oxidation and reduction of a singular species?",
        "Answer": "DISPROPORTIONATION"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What are the bond angle, in degrees, and the molecular geometry, respectively, in the sulfate ion?",
        "Answer": "109.5, TETRAHEDRAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is an insoluble base?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Lithium hydroxide",
            "X": "Potassium hydroxide",
            "Y": "Magnesium hydroxide",
            "Z": "Barium hydroxide"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Ammonia gas reacts with oxygen gas to form nitrogen dioxide and water.  If the rate of appearance of water is 36 moles per liter per minute, then to two significant figures, what is the rate of disappearance of ammonia in moles per liter per minute?",
        "Answer": "24"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following correctly identifies the effect that the presence of an uncompetitive inhibitor has on a Lineweaver - plot?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Km [K-M] and Vmax [V max] are raised, and the ratio Km/Vmax [K-M over V max] increases",
            "X": "Km and Vmax are raised, and the ratio Km/Vmax is unchanged",
            "Y": "Km and Vmax are lowered, and the ratio Km/Vmax is unchanged",
            "Z": "Km and Vmax are lowered, and the ratio Km/Vmax decreases"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the pH of a 0.001 molar solution of sodium hydroxide?",
        "Answer": "11"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What fundamental constant is obtained when a photon\u2122s wavelength is multiplied by its frequency?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "The speed of light",
            "X": "Planck\u2122s constant",
            "Y": "Avogadro\u2122s number",
            "Z": "Boltzmann\u2122s constant"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "The following three ions are all isoelectronic with neon:  O2-, F-, Na+ [O two minus, F minus, N A plus].  Rank them in terms of their ionic radii, from smallest to largest.",
        "Answer": "Na+, F-, O2-  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the major product of the Hall-Heroult Process?",
        "Answer": "ALUMINUM"
    },
    {
        "Number": 5,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is the best example of determinate error?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Random error",
            "X": "Measurement error",
            "Y": "Systematic error",
            "Z": "Sampling error"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What halogen has the greatest effect on a given molecule\u2122s lipophilicity?",
        "Answer": "FLUORINE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 11,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What general group of laboratory techniques is used to separate mixtures and has varieties such as thin-layer, affinity, and ion exchange?",
        "Answer": "CHROMATOGRAPHY  _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Identify the statement that does NOT describe a prostaglandin [pros-tuh-LAN-din] lipid function.",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Prostaglandins are involved in the inflammatory response process",
            "X": "Prostaglandins play a role in blood clot formation but not clot reduction",
            "Y": "Prostaglandins can induce labor contractions",
            "Z": "Prostaglandins can help to increase kidney blood flow"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the VSEPR [ves-per] shape of the xenon [ZEE-non] tetrafluoride molecule?",
        "Answer": "SQUARE PLANAR"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "What is the property that is generally said to be possessed by a substance if that substance has non-superimposable mirror images?",
        "Answer": "CHIRALITY"
    },
    {
        "Number": 2,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If the principal quantum number of an electron within an atom is 4, which of the following is an allowed value of the orbital angular momentum quantum number l ?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "-2",
            "X": "0",
            "Y": "\u00bd",
            "Z": "4"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three compounds that are network solids at room temperature: 1) Sodium chloride; 2) Carbon dioxide; 3) Silicon dioxide.",
        "Answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is one of the factors that determine the bonding between atoms in a solid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Atomic radius of the atoms",
            "X": "Environmental conditions",
            "Y": "Atomic mass of the atoms",
            "Z": "Magnitude of the electronegativities of the atoms"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "According to VSEPR [ves-per] theory, what is the electron-pair geometry for a compound with a molecular geometry that is square planar?",
        "Answer": "OCTAHEDRAL"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following types of photons would be absorbed by an electron transitioning from the n=2 level to the n=3 level in a hydrogen atom?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Infrared",
            "X": "Visible",
            "Y": "Ultraviolet",
            "Z": "X-ray"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "While iodine can be used to test for starch, it is not iodine that is responsible for the resultant color observed. State the ion that is responsible for the observed color.",
        "Answer": "TRIIODIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 18,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The Monsanto process is the major industrial technique used to produce what molecule?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sulfuric acid",
            "X": "Hydrochloric acid",
            "Y": "Acetic acid",
            "Z": "Nitric acid"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the central tenets of Valence Bond Theory?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Whenever possible, a bond involving p or d electrons will orient in the direction that minimizes overlap",
            "X": "The extent of the overlap depends on the shapes and directions of the orbitals",
            "Y": "The p and d orbitals have more electron density in one direction than in the other",
            "Z": "All orbitals of the same type have the same energy"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 23,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "If 35 liters of neon gas at 77 degrees Celsius are cooled at constant pressure, the volume drops to 10 liters.  What is the final temperature of the gas, in degrees Celsius?",
        "Answer": "-173 DEGREES CELSIUS"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "A sloppy chemist forgets to label two beakers.  One contains barium chloride solution, and the other contains magnesium chloride solution.  The chemist decides to add a third solution to each beaker in order to distinguish the two.  Which of the following reagents would form a precipitate in only one of the two beakers?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Sodium sulfate",
            "X": "Sodium carbonate",
            "Y": "Silver nitrate",
            "Z": "Ammonium chloride"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 1,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank, by name or number, the following three molecules or polyatomic ions from the one containing oxygen atoms in the least negative oxidation state, to the one containing oxygen atoms in the most negative oxidation state: 1) ozonide, 2) peroxide, 3) oxygen gas.",
        "Answer": "3, 1, 2"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "You take an IR [I-R] spectrum that has a long, broad peak just below 3000 inverse centimeters.  Which of the following is the likely identification of the molecule?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nonane [NO-nayn]",
            "X": "Methylcyclopentane [meth-uhl-sy-kluh-PEN-tan]",
            "Y": "Hexene",
            "Z": "Pentanol"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 7,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following compounds is most thermodynamically unstable?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Nitrogen trifluoride",
            "X": "Nitrogen trichloride",
            "Y": "Nitrogen tribromide",
            "Z": "Nitrogen triiodide"
        },
        "Answer": "Z"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following would be the most appropriate SN2   [S- N- two] leaving group?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Hydroxyl",
            "X": "O-Trifluoromethanesulfonate [try-FLOOR-oh-METH-ayn-SUHL-fuh-nayt]",
            "Y": "O-Ethyl",
            "Z": "O-Acyl"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 13,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "What is a chief difference between an electrolytic cell and a galvanic cell?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Galvanic cells convert electrical energy into chemical energy, electrolytic cells convert chemical energy into electrical energy",
            "X": "Galvanic cells spontaneously produce an electrical current; an external voltage must be applied to an electrolytic cell",
            "Y": "Oxidation occurs at the anode for a galvanic cell and at the cathode for an electrolytic cell",
            "Z": "Reduction occurs at the anode for a galvanic cell and at the cathode for an electrolytic cell"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following molecules is NOT an exception to the octet rule?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "BF3 [B-F three]",
            "X": "NH3 [N-H three]",
            "Y": "SF4 [S-F four]",
            "Z": "NO [N-O]"
        },
        "Answer": "X"
    },
    {
        "Number": 3,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In nickel-cadmium batteries, the cadmium electrode undergoes what process?",
        "Answer": "OXIDATION _______________________________________________________"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "If l = 3, what are the minimum and maximum allowed values of the magnetic quantum number (ml) [M-L], respectively?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "1, infinity",
            "X": "0, 2",
            "Y": "-3, 3",
            "Z": "-\u00bd, \u00bd"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 8,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three thermodynamic state functions that would increase as a result of water boiling at 100 degrees Celsius at atmospheric pressure:  1) Gibbs free energy; 2) enthalpy; 3) entropy.",
        "Answer": "2 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "With respect to magnesium and oxygen, respectively, how do the radii of the constituent ions compare to the corresponding neutral atoms?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Larger and larger",
            "X": "Larger and smaller",
            "Y": "Smaller and larger",
            "Z": "Smaller and smaller"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Given that the pKa [P-K-A] of acetic acid is 4.8, find the pH to one decimal place of a solution of acetic acid that contains a 10:1 [ten to one] ratio of acetic acid to acetate.",
        "Answer": "3.8"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "In sulfur dioxide, what is the VSEPR [ves-per] theory prediction for the bond angle between sulfur-oxygen bonds?",
        "Answer": "120"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "A reaction is dependent upon the concentrations of L, M, and N. You find that keeping the other reactants constant and doubling L quadruples the reaction rate; halving M has no effect on the reaction rate; halving N reduces the reaction rate to 1/8 of its original value. Provide the reaction orders for L, M, and N, as well as the overall order for the reaction.",
        "Answer": "L"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "Which of the following acts as a Lewis acid in the presence of water to form carbonic acid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Carbon dioxide",
            "X": "Methane",
            "Y": "Methanol",
            "Z": "Formic acid"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 6,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following four compounds that would function as soluble electrolytes when added to water:  1) sodium chloride; 2) decane; 3) acetic acid; 4) barium sulfate.",
        "Answer": "1 AND 3"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Rank, by name or number, the following three ionic compounds in terms of increasing lattice energy, from the lowest to the highest:  1) Magnesium oxide; 2) Sodium chloride; 3) Sodium fluoride.",
        "Answer": "2, 3, 1"
    },
    {
        "Number": 12,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Of the nonradioactive halides found in natural abundance, which is the strongest reducing agent?",
        "Answer": "IODIDE"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The solubility of a gaseous solute in a liquid solvent is typically expressed in units of concentration.  Which of the following factors does NOT affect the solubility of a gas in a liquid?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Volume of the liquid",
            "X": "Temperature of the liquid",
            "Y": "Pressure of the gas",
            "Z": "Polarity of solvent and solute molecules"
        },
        "Answer": "W"
    },
    {
        "Number": 16,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "How many moles of O2 [O two] are required to completely combust 1 mole of pentane?",
        "Answer": "EIGHT"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Multiple Choice",
        "Question": "The standard enthalpy and entropy of a hypothetical reaction are both positive.  Assuming these values are constant with temperature, which of the following statements describes the temperature dependence of the spontaneity of the reaction?",
        "Options": {
            "W": "Spontaneous at all temperatures",
            "X": "Nonspontaneous at all temperatures",
            "Y": "Spontaneous at high temperatures but nonspontaneous at low temperatures",
            "Z": "Spontaneous at low temperatures but nonspontaneous at high temperatures"
        },
        "Answer": "Y"
    },
    {
        "Number": 22,
        "Subject": "CHEMISTRY",
        "Type": "Short Answer",
        "Question": "Identify all of the following three reactions that would result in a precipitate:  1) Addition of barium nitrate and sodium sulfate; 2) Addition of aluminum nitrate and zinc sulfate; 3) Addition of sodium hydroxide and ammonium sulfate.",
        "Answer": "1"
    }
]